Chapter 84: Following the Phoenix, Pt 2

The cell was two by two meters, with a hard stone bench along one side and a bucket in the corner. The metal grate had closed behind the nice Auror man, but the Patronus remained, smiling warmly at her as it floated up and down the little cell.

She was quite sure that this was not how it was supposed to go, but she wasn't about to complain.

It was cold here, despite the Patronus. She huddled up on the bench, wishing that she had a blanket. Wishing that she was anywhere but here, that it all hadn't happened, that she could still be good, that she wasn't a crazy cold-blooded murderess who would try to kill a fellow student in a moment of anger...

Why had she done that? Harry had seemed to be convinced that she hadn't, and for an instant during the trial she had wanted desperately to believe it. But he was wrong. She remembered the act with crystal clarity, and what logical alternative explanation could there be? She had been so convinced that Draco was plotting against her, and then, somehow, she had snapped. She would never have thought she held that kind of darkness inside her, but she did know enough about Memory Charms that you couldn't just create several weeks worth of obsession out of thin air. And why had she been so convinced? It had to be insanity because he hadn't been plotting against her, she had had no reason to believe that he had been, and he had testified under Veritaserum that he had really tried to help her –

She felt horribly sick and her breath caught again, but she pushed away the tears. She had cried most of yesterday and this morning, in the detention cell looking out on the Dementor that had guarded her during her trial, and now she was simply exhausted. She couldn't bear to cry again. She had been so, so scared, and now the worst had happened, and she was still scared. She should probably sleep, but what if she woke up and the badger wasn't there anymore? The Auror couldn't leave his Patronus with her indefinitely, he would need it to guard himself, and he would need to sleep, too.

And when it was gone, she'd be left to the Dementors. She remembered, all too well, how she had felt on the day the Dementor came to Hogwarts. How it took away all the brightness, all the love, showed her her family and friends lying dead, and the terrible sadness of dying alone. Then, she had run. But now there wouldn't be anywhere to run to, nowhere to stop them from taking away all her happy memories of her parents and her friends, and instead making her relive her worst memories over and over again. And she had a pretty good idea which memory that would involve in particular. Draco Malfoy, sending curses flying through the air with violent energy, until he dealt the ending blow with a hex that sent her crashing against the wall and drew blood from her cheek. The feeling of her blood temperature dropping, getting angrier than she'd ever been in her life. And then – then she'd...

Hermione forced herself to push those thoughts aside. These might be her last hours of not having to think about it, why torture herself already? And there was one thing that she needed to do.

From a pocket of her robes, she recovered the little wax-sealed paper, marked 42. She had carried it around since Harry had given it to her. Once, it had accidentally gone into the laundry with her robes and had come out wrinkled, but otherwise apparently unharmed. The Aurors had not confiscated it, because they had only checked her for magical items.

She had remembered it, of course, when she was sitting in her detention cell, with Professor Flitwick standing guard by her side. But she had known that she should not read it yet; they had used Legilimency on her and might do so again. Harry had made it very clear that this was dangerous knowledge. But now, there would be no reason to read her mind anymore, would there? And maybe even without a wand, this would help against the Dementors, somehow.

With trembling fingers, she broke the seal, and unfolded the paper. By the silvery light of the Patronus, she read:

Since ancient times, Death has roamed the earth.
And it casts its shadows into the world.
The approach of Death drains your power.
The fear it exudes drains your happiness.
The kiss of Death destroys all that you are.
And it takes away the people we love.
But never believe that Death cannot be defeated.
Through science and magic, either or both, Homo sapiens can fight.
And we can win.
We are not there yet.
But either by our hand, or by that of our children, or our children's children.
We will end this dark stain upon the world.
Until Death is just a faded memory from dark times past.
And people won't have to say goodbye anymore.

She read the paper three times (even though she had memorized the words after the first time). Death. If Death was the answer, what was the question?

What is a Dementor?

She knew instantly that Harry was right. It fit so perfectly. The way they looked like a rotten corpse. And how the Dementor had shown her her parents dead, her friends dead –

The badger nuzzled her briefly. Animals did not understand about dying, and so they were not afraid. But she was, she was terrified – both of dying and of losing the people she cared about – and that was why the Dementor had affected her so. Most of the Ravenclaws had also not been able to cast a Patronus. Were they more afraid than others? Or were the other Houses better at persuading themselves not to think about it?

Her brain felt like it was flying, finally connecting the dots. The Patronus Charm didn't run on magic, Mr. Lupin had said. It ran on all those bright warm feelings Dementors took from you. It was like turning away from Death, focusing on all the good things of life instead, and concentrating them into one solid block of life force that Dementors could not touch. But you couldn't do that if you knew you were doing it, you couldn't focus on life while thinking of death, it would be like trying not to think of a pink elephant.

Then I will cancel the Patronus Charms, and prevent any more Patronuses from being cast. And then my Dementor is going to Kiss everyone here who voted to send a twelve-your-old girl to Azkaban. That was the other competitor for the worst memory of her life, the things Harry had almost done after she had pleaded for his help. And now she understood how he would have done it. All that would have to happen was for the Wizengamot and the Aurors to know the secret. Then Harry would have been the only one in the room able to cast a Patronus, and he could simply move it in place to only protect the faction on Dumbledore's side of the room. How could he even have contemplated it? Or had the Kiss been a bluff, and would he have protected the Lords and Ladies after all, once he gained power over them?

She turned back to the note. There was also the second part, and that was probably important. The note didn't just offer the secret of Dementors' nature, but also the clue to fighting them. Was this the happy thought he had used to cast a Patronus? It wouldn't look like people think Patronuses should look, that's what Harry had said. Anyone who saw it would know there was something strange going on. How would a Patronus come out, when it was cast not with enjoyment of life, but with defiance of death?

And would she be able to do it? Harry had read a lot of science fiction. But the keyword there was fiction. Sometimes he talked of the bright, shining future of humanity, and he really believed that, but it all just seemed like a fantastic dream to her.

But was it? Could it be done? Harry wanted to study magic experimentally, merge the wizarding and Muggle worlds, discover the secret of immortality and colonize the Solar System, that's what he had told her on the very first day they'd met. And he might even be able to pull it off, if he stopped doing stupid stuff like threatening to kill off half the political structure of Magical Britain, and focused on reading more books. His discovery of partial transfiguration proved that scientific knowledge really could improve magic. Little though she had liked to admit it before, if anyone could do the impossible, it was Harry, even if most of what he did was just tricks.

Maybe Harry's bright future was just a fantastic childhood dream. But Martin Luther King had had a dream too, and while it hadn't quite come true yet, the world was well on its way. Maybe it could be done.

It would be rather marvelous if her parents would not wither with age and die at 80, but stay by her side. It would be wonderful if wizards or Muggles or a combination could figure out how to cure Alzheimer's disease – Harry's first idea might not have worked, but there were plenty of things they hadn't yet tried, like bringing together a specialist healer and actual patients to think of one obvious example – and cancer, and aids, and all those other diseases for that matter. If they could do away with the International Statute of Secrecy, and wizards could help Muggles in underdeveloped countries, if they could stop world hunger and inequality, if discrimination for race, gender and sexual orientation in the Muggle world would disappear as it had in the wizarding world. If wizards could drop their biases against Muggleborns – like Harry had apparently already convinced Draco Malfoy to do – and even work together with Muggles and members of other magical races. If she and Harry, and Padma and Hannah and Susan and all the others, and her parents and Professor McGonagall and everyone would live for a thousand years, without wars or Dark Lords, if they could learn to go to other planets and terraform them, if she could have children and grandchildren, and even get to know her own great-great-great-great-grandchildren some day –

It would be rather marvelous indeed.

She looked around at the small cell, with a stone slab for a bed and a bucket for a toilet. It might be the right kind of thought to cast a Patronus Charm, but without a wand, it wouldn't do her much good. She was still in Azkaban, and there she would remain until she died, alone. There was only one thing left to do for her that would help the world, and that was to tear up the paper, and never give anyone cause to use Legilimency on her.

There might be a bright future in store for humanity, but it didn't seem like Hermione Granger would be a part of it.

"I had not expected to see you here, Minerva."

She turned around, feeling rather like a rabbit caught stealing carrots. The mighty old wizard stood behind her, lowering his wand. She had sneaked into his Phoenix Price room, but apparently, she had not been careful enough.

"And so I see that you have shifted your loyalties to Harry Potter," he sighed. "I cannot blame you. For what you have seen of me today, it is the right and proper thing to do."

She could not find the words to reassure him, perhaps because his conclusion was not entirely unfounded.

"Tell me, Minerva," he continued after a short pause. "You have known me long, and as well as anyone still alive. Have I lost myself to darkness today?"

"What?" she said in genuine surprise. "Albus, no!" She had resented him, had been angry at him for overriding Harry's clever and generous plan to save Hermione. Like she had resented his decisions so many times before, during the last war. But she had always understood why he acted as he did. She might not like it – and she knew he hated it – but the simple fact was that time and again, the resulting events had proved his wisdom. When Albus had finally stopped following his heart, and had started administrating the war efforts in the ruthless but sensible way advocated by Mad-Eye instead, far fewer people died.

The old wizard's lips pressed together tightly before he spoke. "For the greater good. I have sacrificed so many, for the greater good. Today I condemned Hermione Granger to Azkaban for the greater good. And what is worse, I tried to persuade the hero to do the same. A first-year child, as innocent as I once was in his love and more dangerous even than Lord Voldemort in his anger, and I tried to tell him that he must sacrifice friends or even kill innocents for the greater good."

The ancient wizard looked so pained, so broken, that she felt all her resentment trickle away. What had been going on between him and Harry?

"Albus, stop being silly," she said firmly. "You are not Grindelwald, and nor is Harry. I know you did what you had to do today." She paused for a moment, considering. "And my first loyalty remains to you. But I am also doing as I must. Hermione might not yet be lost, Albus. Harry thinks we can save her."

"Ah?" The headmaster hesitated. "And I suppose you came here for something of hers?"

She shook her head. "Just a wand for her to use." Harry had asked her whether she could arrange a wand that could not be traced back to them, and she had nodded, and come here. As many people who had died in Albus's wars, there were plenty of wands in this room, not all of them broken, and some of them from before Ollivander's time or from foreign wandmakers. It was much harder to use another wizard's wand, but Harry had said that the wand would only be needed for minor magics, and as long as she took all the wands that might work, they could give Hermione the best match and put back the rest. She had not told Harry about this room, of course. It was too sad, too powerful for a child to be confronted with. She had simply told him that she would be right back.

Albus silently looked at her for a long moment, and she felt a blush creeping up her cheeks. She was uncomfortable stealing from the good man, but it was for an honorable purpose, and she knew that he would never betray her when he discovered the theft. "I am certain that most of the people here would have been happy for their wands to be used in that way."

The old man nodded slowly. "But what good will it do her to have a wand?"

"I don't know," she confessed. Harry had fired off questions at her, making notes and crossing things out on his parchment, but hadn't really taken the time to explain himself. "Harry mentioned that she might learn to cast a Patronus Charm even there, but he did not say how. We talked about a lot of other things she might need a wand for too, but I think he rejected some of them."

"So he does not intend to free her, at least?"

"He would never risk her soul!"

The old wizard looked grave. "Did he say he wasn't planning to?"

"Yes. At least, I think he did."

Albus sighed deeply. "Wait here."

The old wizard disappeared between the pedestals. Moments later he was back, carrying a wand she did not recognize.

"Give her this one. I daresay she can use it almost as well as her own."

Minerva blinked in surprise at that. How could the old wizard possibly know that? Even Garrick Ollivander could not choose a replacement wand just by sight.

And then she blinked again, because she realized the implication.

"So you are not stopping me from doing this?"

He smiled feebly. "It might have been a long time ago, Minerva, but I was sorted into Gryffindor as well. I know that sometimes we must put aside what is wise, and do what is right."

"Albus... thank you."

The old wizard bowed his head.

"I will do more, if you will let me. I shall come with you to Azkaban, and help with whatever plan Harry has concocted. He has the intellect to match Lord Voldemort's, but he is not yet wise enough to fully understand the consequences of his actions, and I fear for him, and for you, if you should go unguarded."

"You would do that?"

"Oh yes," he sighed. "It is madness, of course. If anything goes wrong, the price will be far too high, and when next Lord Voldemort strikes, we may all be doomed. But that is not certain."

Fawkes, who sat on his shoulder, let out a triumphant battle cry. Albus smiled, and stroked the creature.

"I fear I have come too far from what I used to believe. Perhaps there is a better way. This once, I will follow the phoenix again."

Chapter 86: Following the Phoenix, Pt 4

Five to eight, in the Headmaster's office.

She was scared. Not in ten years had she done something like this. No, never had she done something like this; she had gone into dangerous situations, in the past, and even faced Lord Voldemort himself, but she had not faced Dementors, never really broken the law. In this school, she represented discipline. But then, if you could not break the rules even when they were wrong, you could not truly be a Gryffindor.

The Headmaster was feeding the chocolate bars into the newly made pouch, save for two bars which Harry had asked him to keep apart. Now, the boy with the green eyes and the scar on his forehead turned to her, holding out something made of a strange shimmering, black material.

"I want you to wear this cloak. It will keep you safe while we are in Azkaban. That way, we won't need a Patronus, so we'll have a smaller chance of being discovered."

She carefully took the cloak from his hands. "Invisibility cloaks don't do..." And then she felt the material on her skin. Her magic tingled, echoing the beauty and rightness of the feeling on her hands... "Where did you get this?"

"It's a family heirloom, but that's not the point. Please do not speak of this to others."

She nodded, even as, in her head, some cogwheels clicked and she finally understood how James Potter had done some of his stunts.

The boy turned to the old wizard, now.

"Can you withstand the Dementors' drain for as long as it will take us to find Hermione?"

"Can you?" she blurted out. "In January, you were... you got..."

"That was January," said Harry. "This is April." He smiled, then. "I have learned a lot, on that day and afterwards."

"I can, too," Albus confirmed. He took the bar of chocolate Harry offered him (even he could probably use the help while unprotected in Azkaban). Then, with a crack from Albus's wand, the boy disappeared. The old wizard turned to his phoenix.

"Are you prepared to go back into Azkaban, Fawkes?"

The phoenix let out a great, challenging cry. Dumbledore nodded, and the bird turned invisible. "And I suppose a silencing spell might be needed as well."

She pulled the cloak over her body and stepped to Albus's side. A small hand was thrust into her left hand. Her right hand grabbed Albus's. And then the old wizard, too, became invisible and they all disappeared.

Azkaban.

She felt it the moment they arrived. The Dementors... distant, but there. Hollow points of emptiness. Yet, somehow, their drain did not touch her. What was this cloak, how could it stop the most unstoppable creature on earth?

They were in a long corridor, in front of a large metal door. Albus had suggested that the Aurors would probably have put the child in their custody at a high level, rather than six levels down as was normally the suggested penalty for attempted murder. Beside her, she heard Albus quietly whispering some incantations.

She looked at the large metal door uncomfortably. Behind that door, prisoners were suffering. Her heart went out to them, and then to Harry, who was too young to have to see this kind of place. Yet for all his innocence, there had been no question of Harry staying behind. Of the three of them, she was the most dispensable one. She had come because she had been set on it, once the plans had been made – and because, if their presence should be discovered, she was the most innocent person to be found. Allowing herself to be caught might deflect attention and allow the others to remain undiscovered.

She briefly considered placing a quieting barrier to protect the boy from whatever he might hear, but there was already no sound to be heard besides the old wizard's muttering. Albus had probably set up his own silencing wards the instant they arrived.

"I found her," the old wizard's voice spoke in a whisper. "She's one level up from here. We shall have to tunnel through a floor."

None of them spoke further, as they waited. It felt like the corridor was entirely empty, save for the flickering gas lamps which only served to give this place an eerie atmosphere. And then at last, golden lines appeared on the ceiling, and a new trapdoor opened.

A small hand grabbed hers, and she felt a weightless sensation as she was lifted into the air. Fawkes, again. They arrived in the higher corridor, gently touched down on the ground, and the hole in the floor disappeared again.

"This way." A golden light very briefly lit up and moved to the right. She followed it, and saw the metal door ahead open.

She braced herself for the sight of Hermione and maybe others that would meet her there, and went through the door. It closed and locked behind her. Then she looked around, and blinked, for a silvery light illuminated the block of cells.

There, in the very last cell of this block, lay Hermione on a stone bench. She was sleeping, curled up into a tight ball. And there was a fox Patronus standing guard inside her cell.

(Earlier)

Leela peeked into the breakroom. "Mike?"

"Yes?" Auror Li put down that morning's edition of The Quibbler, whose headlines were of course filled with the case of Granger versus Malfoy (apparently Malfoy had been possessed by the spirit of Baba Yaga, and Granger's spell had cast it out into Mrs. Norris, the caretaker's cat), but which also contained some lighter material on a mixed magpie-dragon breed being spotted in France.

"Call back your Patronus. I will take care of the girl."

Li blinked. "You will?"

Leela smiled, and her fox vanished. "You're not the only one who feels that this situation is screwed up, you know. Tom is fully on our side. And I bet that from the morning crew, Godric will help too."

From the corner of the room, Bahry snorted. (He was talking to his wife by Patronus, but that wouldn't catch speech directed at others.) "I can just see Malfoy grouching when he finds out. Guess it never crossed anyone's mind that Azkaban is guarded solely by people who can cast a Patronus."

"There are no Aurors nearby," came Albus's voice. He was still invisible; there was no reason for him to show himself. "One of them is keeping her shielded from a distance. In fact, it looks like they deliberately placed her away from other prisoners, where they could do so undetected. Harry, we may not need to interfere here. If the Aurors are protecting her, she should be safe until such time as we can secure her release. There is no need for you to sacrifice your cloak."

"No." Harry's voice. "It is too great an assumption that they'll always keep her shielded. We only know that someone is doing it now. I'm not going to risk Hermione's life on that chance, you don't even need to be properly pessimistic to see that it would be stupid. Plus, if they actually do keep her protected at all times, she won't need to use the cloak, so she can keep it in the secret part of the pouch and has little chance of discovery."

Minerva blinked as she understood. Of course, that was the plan. The cloak, which somehow managed to shield her from the Dementors' fear, would do the same for Hermione. It was simple and elegant, and she wondered why Harry had been reluctant to explain this part.

But it didn't matter. There was a child, and it needed her comforting. She waved her wand and the cell door clicked open (it was only a non-magical lock, as Dementors would drain magic over time, so that was easy), stepped inside, and took off her cloak.

When Hermione Granger woke up, she instantly remembered where she was. The silvery Patronus light fell on her closed eyelids, and a knot of misery tightened in her stomach. It had not all been a nightmare. She was still in Azkaban, she was still a convicted attempted-murderess.

And then she realized what had awoken her: a soft hand on her shoulder.

Hermione's eyes flung open, and looked into the gentle face of Professor McGonagall.

"P-Professor?" She sat up, too confused to know what more to say. There was a trickling sound to the left, and she looked and saw Harry. "Harry?!"

The Boy-Who-Lived grinned cheekily, and held up two fingers. "I didn't do anything you would disapprove of. Promise."

"W-what are you doing here?" she stammered.

"We're here for you," Professor McGonagall said kindly. "I am sorry, we cannot take you away from here. But we can at least make all this less hard on you until we can prove your innocence and get you out through the legal system."

Something in her stomach unknotted, as she looked from Professor McGonagall to Harry, who nodded in agreement.

"You really think I'm innocent?"

"Of course you are, Miss Granger. I know you, you would never do such a thing. The Headmaster believes as I do, too, even if he could not say so before the Wizengamot without making your situation worse. Whether it was a Memory Charm or even darker magic, I am quite certain that your own will had no part in this."

Hermione just stared at the wall. She wanted desperately to believe it, that the darkest thing she had ever done had not really been her. It would be her greatest wish, more than being free and going back to her parents; she could even accept staying in Azkaban and being eaten by Dementors if it meant that she hadn't really done that, that she could still be good... But could it really be true?

"Surely you don't believe it?" said Professor McGonagall. "Miss Granger, surely you have never thought yourself to be capable of murder?"

"But I –" Her excellent memory helpfully replayed it for the thousandth time, no matter how little she wanted to think about it.

""But you remember doing it all the same," spoke the older witch with a note of understanding. "Miss Granger, this is one of the things I came here to do. You have gone through a terrible ordeal; you deserve reprieve and kindness and rest, and instead you were sent to this horrible place. We cannot undo those grievances, but at the very least there is no reason for you to bear such dreadful memories. I would be happy to remove them from you."

A strange feeling of hope stirred in her chest. "What?"

"Your memories of the duel might well be complete fabrications. There is no need to remember much more than simply the story of what supposedly happened." Professor McGonagall turned her head to the side, towards the grate. "Although I believe the Headmaster would like to make sure nothing important is lost first."

The Headmaster? And then there was another trickling sound, and there, behind Harry, stood Albus Percival Wulfric Brian Dumbledore, Chief Warlock of the Wizengamot and many things besides, the phoenix flaming brightly on his shoulder. The most powerful wizard in the world was standing in her cell. She felt very small all of a sudden. It was one thing for Harry and Professor McGonagall to break into Azkaban for her, but –

The great hero who had defeated Grindelwald stepped forward, in the small space of the cell.

"Miss Granger, you will not remember any of this, but most importantly you will not remember my presence. Harry and Minerva can afford to be found here, but I cannot. I most sincerely apologize."

"It's okay," she found herself stammering, even though her mind had not processed far beyond "will not remember any of this".

"You have shown extraordinary braveness today, and now I must ask you to be brave once more. Will you share your memories with me?"

"How?"

From the folds of his robes, Professor Dumbledore recovered a stone basin (which really was far too large to have fit there, but she was used to her Mokeskin Pouch by now so it didn't surprise her all that much). "I will cast the necessary spells. Your task will be to recall all your relevant memories – in as much detail as you can remember – and will them into the Pensieve. You absolutely must provide the duel, for this is where we are most likely to find clues, and everything that followed, until the moment of your arrest. In addition, there may be earlier memories which are relevant for study, such as the moment you received Draco's challenge and anything else you can think of that might be suspect. Are you prepared to share those memories with me?"

What was one more time, when she had gone through it over and over in her mind? Of course, it would mean he would have her darkest memories in his possession. Would he think badly of her, when he saw them? But Professor McGonagall had said that the Headmaster believed she was innocent...

She nodded, and the old wizard started speaking incantations.

It took a long time, and it was very painful. The spells immersed her in the memories again, playing them out visually. She had to force herself to continue several times. And then, when the last of the memories finally disappeared into the Pensieve, she looked up, at the lined face of the Headmaster, at Professor McGonagall who was close to tears, and at Harry, who had a thoughtful look on his face.

"What are you thinking, Harry?" She asked tiredly. "You don't hate me now, do you?"

He waved a hand dismissively. "Of course not, don't be stupid. But I think I can prove your innocence with this. You bled, at the end of the duel. I saw you put that memory in."

"Yes, I cut open my cheek on that final blast."

"But you can't cast Episkey, can you? I don't think uncontrolled wandless magic would let you do things you cannot do with a wand. And I didn't see you talking to anyone else. However, you had no scar or cut or anything in the morning."

That... did seem strange, now she came to think of it. A part of the miserable weight in her stomach lifted, and the cell seemed just a little bit brighter.

Professor McGonagall was practically bouncing. "But this is evidence! We can prove to the Wizengamot that she is innocent!" Professor Dumbledore, however, just shook his head.

"The trial has been and gone. We would need strong additional evidence to have the case re-examined, and as this is a blood debt, Lucius himself would have to agree to a re-trial. A single cut – it can be explained in other ways, even if those are unlikely. The memory would not persuade him, even if we could find a way to bring up the subject to him without confessing to the crime of breaking into Azkaban."

"But Draco might have the same memory," Harry piped up.

"It will not be enough for Lord Malfoy, as Draco has not seen the rest."

"It's enough for me," Hermione whispered. The realization was starting to filter through her mind now. She really was innocent... Her head swam.

The Headmaster smiled. "Did you still doubt? Well, it matters little now. I have some other questions for you still. The Pensieve captures your thoughts, but cannot show them to others... So tell me, when did you first start believing Draco Malfoy and Professor Snape were plotting against you?"

"I – I don't know, why I thought that."

"That's probably because the reason why you thought that was removed from your memory," Harry put in. "But let's pin it down. Were you thinking it the day after Snape... disbanded SPHEW, when you asked me to borrow my cloak?"

"No," she whispered. She had been planning to go into the Slytherin Dungeons, if she had been worried about Malfoy and Snape then it would have been at the forefront of her mind.

"And the day afterwards, when you sat away from me at breakfast?"

She nodded slowly. She wasn't sure anymore why she had wanted to avoid Harry... She'd been afraid to tell him... what?

"How long were you in the Slytherin Dungeons?"

"It couldn't have been more than about an hour or so... Probably much less."

"Then why did you miss the Sunshine Planning Meeting? Susan said no one understood where you'd been."

She'd been... tired, when she got back. And confused, and worried, and desperately afraid of Snape and Draco. And it was later than she had thought it would be.

"I see," Harry nodded. "Something happened either in the dungeons, or on the way back. We may have to talk to Daphne for more information."

"Could you share that memory with me, too?" Professor Dumbledore asked gently. She nodded, and he started the incantations again.

When it was all over, Professor McGonagall was looking sharp. Harry and Professor Dumbledore, too, looked like they had seen something in the memory that she had not. "What is it?"

"I can at least see how Daphne got her warnings, Miss Granger," Professor McGonagall said with a frown. "I shall be having words with Miss Margaret Bullstrode."

"What I find interesting," Harry broke in before she could ask more, "is that at least two hours must have passed between you borrowing my cloak and your arrival back in the Ravenclaw Common Room, seeing as the sun had gone down already by then. Yet the Memory itself couldn't be much more than half an hour. An hour, tops. Something happened there that you were made to forget about."

Dumbledore nodded sadly. "I agree. That much seems evident."

She slumped on the stone bench. "I don't like this. I could always rely on my memory."

Harry looked slightly guilty. "At least knowing where the holes are, and what they are caused by, should help, shouldn't it?"

Hermione nodded, and smiled weakly. "I guess it does." And it proved that someone, apparently, had manipulated her. That she was innocent. And that was worth more than anything, even more than a consistent memory.

And then her thoughts slipped in a brief moment of disorientation, like she'd just lost her track of thought. She looked back at Professor McGonagall, who had just offered to remove her memories of what she'd done (supposedly done, the Deputy Headmistress had said that she was probably innocent); that was probably why she was feeling so relieved now...

"You can remove the memory?"

The older witch shook her head, as if to clear her mind from something. But then the woman took out her wand, and pointed it at her.

"Yes, I can. I cannot offer to remove everything; your current situation would not make sense to you if I removed the trial, for instance. But at the very least you do not need to remember the duel, and this fabrication of what you supposedly did."

Hermione stared at the wand.

No more guilt.

Perhaps Professor McGonagall and Harry were right, and it all hadn't happened, maybe she really was innocent. If Professor McGonagall removed her memories of the duel, then she would have no trouble at all believing whatever they put in place instead. She would have nothing to blame herself for anymore.

But even as she started to say yes, a feeling of reluctance rose inside her.

She hadn't said anything.

She'd woken up and remembered what had happened the night before, and it had been like – like – she couldn't find words even in her own thoughts for what it had been like. But she'd known that Draco Malfoy was already dead, and she hadn't said anything, hadn't gone to Professor Flitwick and confessed. She'd just dressed herself and gone down to breakfast and tried to act normal so that nobody would ever know, and she'd known it was wrong and Wrong and horribly horribly WRONG but she'd been so, so scared –

Even if they were right, even if the duel with Draco Malfoy was a lie, she'd made that choice all by herself. She didn't deserve to forget that, or be forgiven for it. For that decision alone, she deserved everything she had got. And if she forgot the duel, she would never understand the relevance of that decision.

"I don't deserve to forget," she said in a wavering voice. "I'm a horrible person, I'm not heroic at all –"

Professor McGonagall's voice was very sharp, like Hermione had just made some dreadful mistake on her Transfiguration homework. "Stop being foolish, Miss Granger! Horrible is whoever did this to you. And as for being heroic –"

"No," Harry interrupted. "Let her explain. This may be important." He turned to her. "Why do you say that?"

"Because I... I didn't confess." She felt tears coming up behind her eyes again, and pushed them away. "I should have, maybe something could still have been saved, it was wrong to try to hide what I did, but I was just so, so scared."

"Of course you were," Professor McGonagall sighed. "Almost anyone in your place would have acted the same."

"Why?" said Hermione's voice, which seemed to be running on without her mind, now. "Why couldn't I be braver? I was going to run in front of the Dementor – for Harry – before, I mean, in January – so why – why – why couldn't I –" Why had the thought of being sent to Azkaban just completely unglued her, why had she forgotten everything about being Good –

"And then you stopped me from protecting you in the Wizengamot," Harry pointed out when she trailed off. "You might have been too scared of the Dementors at first, but in the end, you did something much greater than confessing. You averted disaster today, Hermione."

She almost smiled. Almost. "Anyone would have done that."

"No," Harry said seriously. "They really wouldn't have. Didn't you see how surprised all those purple robes were at your response? You really are a hero, Hermione."

She looked at the ground. "Being a hero is nothing like what I thought it'd be. But that's what you were all trying to tell me before, isn't it?"

Professor McGonagall just hugged her, then, and held tight for many long seconds. It was very comforting. When she let go, Hermione had made up her mind.

"Still, I... I don't think it's right to just forget."

"Then you won't have to," Harry decided. "Professor, would it be possible to simply modify the memory? In a blatant way, to make it clear that it is false? Like, we could add subtitles, saying 'don't believe this, it was implanted' or something?"

"That... would require a fair bit of skill to do well." Professor McGonagall hesitated. "But I am sure it can be arranged."

"But –" Hermione started protesting. Harry turned to her.

"This isn't just to make your life easier. I have a few plans to help you, but if they all fail, then you might end up under the Dementors' power, maybe briefly, maybe longer. The last thing you need is to dwell on an implanted memory that would give you completely the wrong idea of what kind of person you are."

He had a point. "Okay."

"So, I think we've got everything covered." Harry decided. Strange, how he was obviously in charge, and not Professor McGonagall. "And now I would like to talk to Hermione, alone. It should be safe to use your Patronus – you may see some strange things from over there, but as long as you don't hear anything it will be fine, I think."

Professor McGonagall nodded. "What do you want me to do if anyone is coming?"

"The moment an Auror even stirs out of their Headquarters, just drop your Patronus, come back here instantly and Obliviate the whole thing. If that's not an option for whatever reason, just buy me enough time to hide."

"Expecto Patronum!" A silvery cat appeared next to the fox, and preceded Professor McGonagall out of the cell. Hermione blinked, confused, but Harry did not seem about to explain. He just took out his wand, and cast some silencing barriers. "I think it's time I told you about Dementors."

"I read your note," she volunteered. "I think I understand."

"Oh, you did?" He looked relieved. "That's great, that'll make the Memory Charms a lot easier."

"Memory Charms?" she repeated, as he grabbed around his neck, and suddenly held a cord that hadn't seemed to be there a moment before.

Harry had the decency to look guilty. "Yes. I don't like messing with your memory, but it would be too dangerous if you remembered me being here, they might give you Veritaserum again. But let's not talk about that for the moment, we can discuss it later." He pulled a thin pouch from his neck, and then summoned a wand out of it. "The spell is called the True Patronus Charm. Cast it. I want to know whether it works for you."

She took the unfamiliar wand with a trembling hand. A slight, warm tingle surged through her fingers when she touched it, as had happened when she had first touched her own wand. Then she closed her eyes, cleared her mind, and tried to call back all those emotions she'd felt before. She thought of the future Harry had painted, and the vision she had imagined before. Finding a way around aging and disease. Curing all the world's problems. And here was Harry, doing the impossible by breaking into Azkaban for her. Maybe she could be part of this bright future. Maybe she could help to make it happen.

"Expecto Patronum!"

And out of her wand burst an enormous silvery humanoid, its light like a sun, far outshining the fox's brightness. She almost dropped her wand in shock, and the figure dimmed a little.

"Steady!" Harry warned. "Hold on to that thought."

She held onto it then. It was easier to imagine the world turning out okay, as she looked into the sun-like brightness of the figure. It was neither a man nor a woman, but it looked human, and it seemed to smile at her.

"I did it." She looked up into Harry's eyes, which were twinkling with delight, too.

"I always knew you had it in you to destroy Dementors, Hermione. But now cancel it. We have a few more things to do."

He started taking out book after book from the pouch, and putting them on the stone bench.

"I still don't understand," Hermione started to protest.

"I don't know how long it'll take me to legally get you out of there. If it takes too long I could break you out illegally and we can hide you in America or something, but then you would be a fugitive for the rest of your life, so I'd rather not do that. So for now, you'll have to stay put. With the wand, you can shield yourself from the Dementors. The books will give you something to do."

That sounded reasonable. "What if the Aurors stop sending their Patronuses here? This is the second, the first Auror left his badger with me, but I don't know whether they're going to do that tomorrow, or next week. How will I sleep?"

Harry grinned cheekily. "You know the three Deathly Hallows, and you have guessed that I have one. Tell me, what is it rumored to do?"

"It hides the wearer, even from Death's ga– oh."

"Exactly. You'll understand the full plan later. Now, take this, and feed the chocolate into it." He handed the pouch to her, and pointed to the large pile of chocolate, which was the last thing he'd taken out. "And then the books and the wand, but say 'Rowena' before each of them. Oh, and don't forget the cloak." As he bent down and picked up the shimmering black cloak from the ground, she realized it must have been there all along, even though she hadn't seen it.

"Why? And why aren't you telling me the full plan now?" But she obeyed anyway, and started feeding the chocolate and the books into the pouch.

"Because it'll take time, and the longer we linger, the larger the chance we are discovered. And honestly, I'd rather not have to explain your having a wand." He canceled the silencing barrier and said, in a raised voice, "you may come back now."

Professor McGonagall returned, with a worried frown. "It is almost midnight. We should go soon, because the next change of the guard starts in a bit over an hour, complete with a feeding round."

"Yes," Harry agreed. "Hermione, I'm really sorry, but you'll have to forget all this."

Forget all of it? Forget that Harry and Professor McGonagall had come for her, that they believed that she was innocent; forget that there was still hope? It was like a slap to her face.

"I don't want to," she whispered.

"If they catch you with the cloak, they will give you Veritaserum again, or they'll use Legilimency on you. It would be too dangerous if you knew for sure that I was involved. I'm sorry, I hate doing this to you. But instead, you will remember dreaming of some trustworthy figure telling you everything important. That's why we had to talk to you first, to know what we needed to tell you in the Memory Charm. Is that okay with you?"

It wasn't okay, not at all, but it did make sense, and she couldn't ask Harry to risk himself just so that she would remember. She nodded silently.

Professor McGonagall gave her a long, warm hug. Harry did the same. And then Professor McGonagall took her wand out.

"Please lie down on the bench." She did so, looking at her two kind helpers while she still could. The last thing she heard was "Somnium".

When Hermione Granger woke up, she instantly remembered where she was. The silvery Patronus light fell on her closed eyelids, and a knot of misery tightened in her stomach. It had not all been a nightmare. She was still in Azkaban, she was still a convicted attempted-murderess.

But she also remembered the dream.

"Hello Hermione," the shining silver otter had said. It was clearly a Patronus, and it spoke in her mother's voice, but how could that be? Her mother was not a witch...

"I am not really here," the otter had continued. "You might think of me as a dream, or rather, a fake Memory Charm. I am not the first false memory you have been given, although I am rather more benevolent than the last one."

"The duel," she had volunteered.

"Yes," the otter had agreed. "As your friend said during your trial, your memory has been altered. It is obvious to everyone who knows you that you could not, would not, have done such a thing. It would be obvious to you, if it had been someone else. And if you examine your memories, you will agree that they have been tampered with. You received a cut during the duel, and the next morning it wasn't there. That does not fit. And the day you went into the Slytherin Dungeons, it was still light when you left the dungeons, but full dark when you returned to Ravenclaw. That, too, does not fit. You are innocent."

Her heart had leaped at that.

(And, thinking back, Hermione had to agree that the memory of the duel didn't feel very real. All the memories were there, but it was somehow overlain with a feeling of distance, that it wasn't really true. She hadn't had that idea when she remembered it before, but she probably felt differently because of what the otter had told her...)

"You still have friends, Hermione, who believe in your innocence. We will do everything in our power to prove it to the Wizengamot, and get you free. But for now, while you must remain here, I can offer you two independent forms of protection. To start, you might want to cast a Patronus whenever it is safe to do so."

"A Patronus?" She had repeatedly incredulously.

"Yes," the otter had stated. "I know that you have learned in school how the spell works, and that you have since figured out why you failed, and how to do better. The light in you is strong, and I am certain that your Patronus will shine brighter than even the brightest Patronus you have seen."

(Brighter than Dumbledore's? But then, knowing the powerful dream Harry had hinted at in the little note, she could almost imagine it might be.)

"If it is so bright, will it not be dangerous to me?"

(She could not remember why she had thought it might be. Although, come to think of it, a different kind of thought for this spell might turn it into a fundamentally different spell. And that is what Professor Quirrell had warned about, ardently, in his special safety lecture for Muggle-borns. Never, ever, cast potentially powerful spells without knowing exactly what they will do.)

"Yes, it might be. This Patronus is different from the ones you have seen; it cannot be sensed by Dementors, and it can even destroy them if you allow it to become bright enough. You will be tempted to do so, but you must never make it go that bright. The Patronus is not fueled by your magic, but by your life force. If you pour too much into it, you will die. If ever you feel your emotions going out of control while you have a Patronus active, drop your wand instantly."

"But I have no wand."

The otter had swirled around, and a thin pouch had fallen on the floor below it.

"Take it, and take the wand inside it. Wear it around your neck. You will also find some other things in there to pass the time, – as it may take a while before we can prove your innocence – and a scroll of parchment with useful spells should your circumstances change. Anything that the Aurors should not find on you, should be added back with a password 'Rowena'. But do not attempt to use it to escape. The penalty for that is the Dementors' Kiss, a fate generally considered to be worse than death."

"I will not." Inside the pouch, she had seen, were a lot of books. And –

"This, Hermione Granger, is Ignotus Peverell's Cloak of Invisibility, rumored to shield the wearer even from Death's gaze. It will hide you from humans, although it does not stop you from being solid, and it does not block spells. However, when worn, it cannot be directly targeted. Most importantly, wearing the cloak will make you invulnerable to Dementors. This is the second protection I offer you. Do not let anyone see it, or fail to see you in your cell when they look. In fact, use it as little as possible. But if the Aurors' Patronus from your cell disappears, you can sleep under this cloak, and protect yourself with your wand while you're awake."

"How will I avoid discovery if I sleep under the cloak?" she had asked.

(An interesting question, as this wasn't the first thought on her mind when re-examining the memory. Shouldn't she have asked first whether this was Harry's cloak? It certainly looked like it.

But of course, the otter had said: it wasn't really there; this wasn't a real memory, it was planted. If she said things she wouldn't expect herself to say, and couldn't remember why, then that was probably because she hadn't.

Just like she might not really have attacked Draco Malfoy...)

"Wear the bracelet that you will find in the pouch. It is imbued with a spell to warn you whenever someone approaches. If you are asleep at the time, it will also wake you. Since the Aurors patrol every six to eight hours, you may have to get used to a segmented sleeping pattern."

(That wasn't so bad, she knew. According to the historian A. Roger Ekirch, this had been the standard way of sleeping in humans for centuries; experiments by the psychiatrist Thomas Wehr had confirmed that humans naturally took to this habit, given enough darkness. She wasn't too sure of the details, since Harry's books had only mentioned this as a brief paragraph, but it was certainly worth trying.)

"Thank you," she had said, while hanging the pouch over her neck. She had really meant that.

"You are welcome. And now, I must depart. Farewell, Hermione Granger."

And the otter had gently swirled around her, and then disappeared.

Had it been a dream? No... it felt more real than that, somehow, even if it clearly wasn't. She touched her neck, and yes, there was the thin cord of the pouch.

With a trembling hand, she held her hand over it. "Invisibility cloak."

She felt it before she properly saw it. A jolt of magic surged through her body. Her fingers tingled, and somehow, even though she couldn't make out the words, it felt like the cloak was whispering to her, or maybe singing a strange kind of song in the back of her head. She threw it around herself, and it warned her entire body.

This was not like Harry's cloak. There had been a bit of a tingle when taking his, and it had felt warm on her hand and delightfully soft on her skin, but she didn't remember the whispering or the music. And yet she had thought it was special at the time. Did Harry posses a fake, an invisibility cloak made in deliberate imitation of this one? Did he know?

But she shouldn't be wearing the cloak when she didn't need to. If an Auror came in, and saw the cell empty... She quickly removed the cloak, although she felt a bit sad as the fabric left her skin and the soft song in the back of her mind faded away. But she would wear it again, she knew, and that was a comfort. For now, she put it back into the pouch (remembering to say "Rowena" before doing so) and took out the bracelet, and the wand.

They watched, behind the wall separating Hermione's cell block from the corridor they were standing in, as Hermione sat still and sorted through her "dreams". Professor Dumbledore had cast a spell to make the wall transparent, but only in one direction, so they could see how Hermione responded to the fake Memory Charm, but she could not see the large glowing cat Patronus that accompanied the invisible spectators: Harry, the two Professors, and the Phoenix.

The four of them watched, as Hermione wore the cloak and put it back, and then retrieved the bracelet and the wand. They watched as she wore the bracelet, and screwed up her eyes in deep concentration.

It took many long seconds. But then she made the movements of the spell, her mouth moved, and a great humanoid sprang from her wand. And they watched as Hermione carefully lowered her wand, and smiled.

"Come. We have lingered long enough here." It was Dumbledore's voice. "Now let us move a few levels further from the guards, and depart."

Down the stairs, through a corridor, past a metal door. Another stairs, another corridor, another metal door. It was taking all of Harry's self-control to keep walking, to not ask to stay just a little bit longer, give the poor prisoners in there some Patronus-time, but he knew it would be foolish, the guards would come soon enough. And if they paused, would he ever be able to persuade himself to leave?

Another stairs. Ahead of them, the metal door clicked open. The Patronus led them past empty cells, to the leftmost one. Now, Dumbledore started his enchantments to break out the wall and trick the wards into not noticing this. "Take your broomsticks," he warned the two of them, and Harry did. He guessed that, somewhere near him, the invisible Professor McGonagall was doing the same.

"Hey," he whispered. "Where are you?"

A soft hand touched his head. He gently grabbed the arm, then pushed the bar of chocolate into it. He and the Headmaster had both taken one bar for themselves, for they had had to walk through Azkaban unprotected and didn't know for how long, but Harry had hardly nibbled his. He could easily stand the Dementors' proximity; he wasn't afraid anymore, he was ready to fight Death in all its forms. But Professor McGonagall would probably have a harder time. As they didn't want to be seen, they couldn't exactly keep the Patronus up while flying through the hole in the wall and away from Azkaban. It was only a brief exposure, and she should be able to handle it – it was very unlikely that she was as vulnerable as Professor Quirrell had been, especially since she could cast a Patronus in the first place – but it would still be unpleasant for her.

"It is done." The Headmaster's whisper. "Cancel your Patronus, and both of you mount your broomsticks." He spoke another enchantment, then, to control both brooms. As neither Harry nor McGonagall could see each other or the Headmaster (and only the occasional flash of fire from a corner of their eyes), but he could see them (since he apparently could see through Disillusioning), the old wizard would steer them. There was a lot of trust implied in giving over full control, but considering the old man's power and position, not to mention his knowledge of and involvement in the plan so far, he already got to decide whether Harry lived or died. Harry obeyed without argument.

The wall opened like a door, and Harry was lifted into the air and carried outside. Down below, he saw the pit full of Dementors, squirming, and he felt their fear swirling around him, trying to engulf him, but he pushed those feelings away. Instead, he let himself be filled by a rush of hatred at the vile creatures.

And then the door had closed behind them and become part of the wall again. Harry was lifted up into the air, an invisible point of consciousness, until the building was far below them. Suddenly he rushed forward, over the sea, away from the fortress. Looking behind, there were no pursuers. Nobody had noticed their presence, or their departure.

After a long time, the broom slowed down, and then stopped in mid-air. A hand grabbed Harry's left shoulder. "Minerva, take a hold of Harry, he is to your left." Another hand grabbed his right arm. And then he burned up, and suddenly he found himself in Professor McGonagall's office.

With four trickling sounds, the four of them were visible again. Dumbledore plunged a hand into his robes, and took out a Time-Turner. He threw the chain over Professor McGonagall's head, and pointed his wand at Harry. There was a click.

"I opened your shell. Five turns should do it." Then the old wizard turned his Time-Turner around, and both he and Professor McGonagall disappeared.

You can do that?! Harry was briefly baffled. But he wasn't allowed to tell anyone about the Time-Turner anyway, and the chain on his wasn't as long. He took it out and spun the hourglass five times. And there he was with the two Professors and the phoenix again, in the same office.

"It is now about fifteen minutes after we left," the old wizard said. "Be seen, Minerva. Then go to bed. It has been an exhausting day." The witch nodded, and walked towards the door. Then the old wizard took Harry by the arm, and they burned out and reappeared in the Headmaster's office. The Headmaster sank down in his chair.

"Congratulations, Harry. Your plan worked perfectly. I had not expected that."

"Nor I," Harry confessed. "I usually try to be properly pessimistic when planning, but somehow nothing went wrong this time. It's almost scary how everything went according to plan. We didn't even need any of the fallbacks! Although –" he added as an afterthought, "it might still go wrong. Or might already have gone wrong. It all depends on Hermione not getting caught now."

"But even if so, none of us are obviously involved. You might be implicated, but you are still the scion of a Noble House, and you will not be convicted without more solid proof. I will arrange the alternative cloak and perform the enchantments to make it feel the way I memory-charmed Miss Granger to remember." He sighed, then. "I am not pleased with the price of sacrificing your cloak if she is caught, Harry. It is a priceless artifact. And even though its magic might lightly compel those around it to return it to its owner, whether that is feasible when it's in the clutches of the Ministry is a rather different matter. But then, she might not be caught; that is the idea after all."

Harry nodded. Besides, if she was caught, Hermione would most likely be lost unless there was already a plan in motion to get her out really soon thereafter, as they probably couldn't get away with doing this a second time. "This is the price of not having her escape."

"True," the old wizard nodded, "I am impressed, to be honest. You could have simply walked her out of there. I would not have believed it possible."

"Azkaban's protections really aren't that great," Harry shrugged. "It's just the Dementors, and I'm not afraid of them. I could have destroyed them all from where we left through the wall."

"Caw!"

The cry pierced his heart. Dumbledore, too, flinched. Apparently, he had removed the spell of silence from his companion, who had a very obvious, blatant question, that somehow had not occurred to Harry.

Why didn't you?

Tears fell on Harry's cheeks as the satisfaction at a successful mission was instantly replaced by the crystal-clear knowledge of what he had left behind. How could he have forgotten? Hermione might be relatively safe, but all the other prisoners were still there, were still suffering, and he had been to Azkaban, had hovered right over the pit, he could have ended the place right there and then, and he hadn't, he hadn't even considered doing it...

"Harry..." the old wizard's voice was gentle, understanding.

"I'm sorry," Harry told Fawkes desperately. "I'm sorry, I should have thought of it, should have done something, should have saved them, and I didn't, and I'm so, so, sorry."

"You have saved one person tonight, Harry. That is more than we could have hoped for."

"It's not enough," Harry sniffled.

Dumbledore sighed sadly.

"I understand all too well how you feel... It is the burden of the phoenix. Fawkes, there will always be more people to save. But regardless of what could have been, we have saved one person tonight. One innocent child who will not have her soul marred by Dementors, or be subject to the whims of the Aurors. One more life, Fawkes. Will you not be content?"

"Caw."

It sounded better, there was a note of approval. But it wasn't enough. Harry had taken up the task, had sworn to himself that he would destroy Azkaban, and when faced once more with his ancient enemy, he had closed his eyes, passed all those doors without it even occurring to him that he could do something right there and then...

In a blur of tears, he walked to the door.

"Harry..."

"If you don't mind, I would like to be alone now, Headmaster."

The old wizard bowed his head, and the spiraling stairs started turning as Harry stepped onto them.

Chapter 88: Perspective, Pt 2 - Planning

It was all over the paper, of course. "MAD MUGGLEBORN SENT TO AZKABAN" and "WIZENGAMOT MAKES AGE EXCEPTION FOR HEINOUS CRIME". The breakfast table was abuzz with talk. Many people were saying how they had never expected it. Others were dragging up anecdotes explaining how they could totally have seen it coming, that Harry Potter had been turning her dark all along. Many of the vicious things which were now repeated everywhere were those which Padma herself had made up earlier that year, before the ghost of Salazar Slytherin had set her straight and Hermione had become a friend. But no one believed her now when she said they had just been lies.

The papers didn't say anything about Harry Potter's threat, or Hermione's response to it. The papers never wrote anything about Harry Potter anymore, not since the Ginny Weasley article, because including him in any article was sure to make nobody believe in it. But this, too, was repeated in whispers on all the House tables, as enough of the students had family in the Wizengamot for the tale to spread. At the Ravenclaw table, it was seen as a sign of redemption; the hero's love interest, having fallen into darkness, going to her death to stop the hero from following her on this path. At the Slytherin table, the more typical response was sneering at Potter's crazy threats. Only some of the Gryffindors seemed to think that declaring enmity to House Malfoy and to Malfoy's political section, was a good idea.

Harry Potter himself was sitting at a side of the Ravenclaw table, looking so utterly broken and destitute that nobody dared to go anywhere near him. He was just staring ahead with empty eyes, and occasionally lifting a spoonful of porridge to his mouth. Some of the times he missed.

Harry Potter had failed. He had tried to save Hermione, for whom he would do anything, for whom he would defy the Headmaster and Professor Snape, make pools of blood seep out from under the doors, or glue forty-four bullies to the ceiling. And he had failed. It was an incredibly sad sight to see, like something in the world was fundamentally broken.

Most parts of her wanted to leave the Boy-Who-Lived alone with his grief, like everyone else was doing. But surely he had heard the rumors, surely he had seen the papers, and he was probably thinking that he was the only person in the world who believed Hermione was innocent...

She took a deep breath and stepped up towards him.

Harry was staring into space, not really seeing anything, not tasting whatever food was in front of him.

It had been a terrible night. In his dreams he had seen, over and over, the phoenix burning up and disappearing. Or sometimes, the phoenix turning away from him in disgust, as he'd taken the selfish choice, postponed doing the right thing yet again, thrown away this one chance of making a difference here and now.

And those had been the good dreams. For he had also revisited Azkaban in his sleep, walked those corridors, heard the screaming and sobbing.

No, I didn't mean it, please don't die.

But this time, it had been Hermione's voice begging, and he'd wanted to release her, to free everyone, but his hands were tied, he couldn't believe that he could do it anymore, he'd failed. He would never take the fortress down as he had once promised himself, for he would always find excuses to postpone. And he felt in his dreams the despair brought by the Dementors, but he couldn't cast the True Patronus Charm anymore, as his guilt crushed in on him because he had given up the conviction that every life was worth fighting for –

It was hard to shake the feeling that he had failed, that he would never amount to anything, that this was the point in life where it was too late to turn back. And maybe he could still go to Azkaban, even without a phoenix to help him (for Fawkes was no longer interested in him in that way, Dumbledore had said), and open the floodgates and tear the place down, but it was almost certain that he couldn't that and survive, not without a phoenix to sustain him. And all his reasons for not killing himself still applied, but wasn't that still selfishness and fear talking?

A figure appeared beside him.

"I believe," Padma Patil said. "That Hermione is innocent. We all do, in S.P.H.E.W."

She didn't know about the phoenix. How could she? But she must think he was grieving for Hermione, and that was probably for the best. How would an innocent Harry respond? A Harry who hadn't helped Hermione, who hadn't seen the phoenix?

"Good," he just croaked.

Padma stood awkwardly beside him for a few moments more, and then turned to leave.

"Wait."

Come back in six months. That's what he had told the phoenix. When he had had the chance to raise an army of True Patronus casters, when he could expect to take on Azkaban and live. He might have been able to do that last night, if he'd only realized, but that chance was gone. Was he going to wallow in self-pity now? Or could he at least be the person he'd promised the phoenix he would be?

"Can you meet me this evening, after dinner?" Padma had not been able to cast the normal Patronus Charm, even though her wandwork had been declared perfect. And she had been borrowing his books. Maybe, she could learn what Hermione had also learned.

"Okay."

She left then, looking slightly confused, and Harry felt a bit better. It wasn't the best kind of answer, it wasn't like going back in time and taking a different choice before it was too late to turn back. He would still never have a phoenix by his side to help him turn on the evil in the world and bring it down. But maybe he could still be a good person. Maybe the sensible choice could still be the right one. Or a right one, at least.

Hermione huddled under her blanket.

She had spent a bit of time last night trying out her new wand, until the bracelet had heated up to warn her that someone was approaching. She'd quickly canceled her Patronus and put the wand away. A man in the bright red Auror robes had come in, followed by a Lioness Patronus, waved his wand, and a plate of food had appeared (bread with ham and cheese and some carrots, with a jug of water of the side). Then he'd left again without saying a word. Not a minute later, the bracelet had cooled down. He'd gone down the stairs the other way, she had guessed, to feed the other prisoners.

Hermione had carefully finished the food (she was hungry, she'd hardly been able to eat the mashed potatoes with sausage and lettuce they'd given her shortly after she arrived, and it tasted pretty terrible cold), but she hadn't dared to take her wand or any of the books out again. Not while the Auror was still below her, and would have to come back past her cell. So, she had lain down again, and fallen asleep quickly.

She had still been asleep when Auror Li had come in to bring the food this morning (a bowl of porridge with berries, with another jug of water), but woken up when he draped a blanket over her. He had just smiled at her, tucked her in, and gone on his way. Some time later, after the bracelet had told her the Auror had come back from the depths of the prison, passed her cell, and gone on towards the headquarters, the lioness Patronus that had been in her cell when she woke up had disappeared, and was instantly replaced by the badger.

Now, she sat under the blanket, which was warm and comfortable even if it looked rather old. She could just cast Thermos, but she might have to answer whether it was warm enough like this, and for that, she'd need to know. One by one, she took out the books in the pouch, scanned them, and put them back. It was hard, for a Ravenclaw, because they all looked intriguing, but she had to know which one to read first.

Ah. That was sure to be a winner.

She carefully laid aside the Timeless Physics booklet, checked the rest, and then took it up again. It was time to learn the science behind partial transfiguration.

Someone tapped Harry on the shoulder at lunch, and a boy in green-trimmed robes handed him a sealed parchment envelope.

The note inside said:

Classroom to the left of Transfiguration, 1 in the afternoon.

- LL.

This time he did figure out the initials, and he had a pretty good idea what the boy would say, too. He sighed, pocketed the note, and went back to finish his lunch before 1pm.

It was interesting to notice the subtle differences between just having a normal Patronus in her cell, and the great bright humanoid. It didn't feel cold anymore, and she was happier, somehow, more optimistic that everything would turn out alright. Although that might have been because she was holding on to the bright thought that fueled the Patronus Charm, the shining future where the world would be wonderful. But even so... Somehow, it seemed, the Dementors could still reach you through a normal Patronus. She had felt that, before, but she'd thought that was just nerves caused by seeing them, and being afraid of what would happen when there wouldn't be a Patronus anymore.

She turned another page in the little book. It was a very interesting read. Written for a complete novice, and just right to get the intuition. Plus, it wasn't very long; she'd probably have learned it by heart before the day was over.

It was definitely a sign of Harry, though. He had tried to explain her about this before, but in between the hand-waving and the exclamations about the universe standing still for a million years and it not mattering at all, she had given up. It was just too much of a coincidence for her anonymous benefactor to just happen to include this book with the other physics textbooks. And it made sense.

Harry would always come to save her.

She sighed. The hard thing was, she was grateful. Really really grateful. She probably wouldn't get exposed to Dementors even without the help – the Aurors certainly seemed to be planning on keeping her protected – but all the same, having her own Patronus was reassuring. And the Cloak – woah. And most of all, the books, and the wand... Take away the Dementors from Azkaban and you'd still have something as bad as the worst kind of Muggle jail: a dimly lit, smelly cell without any natural light, with little space to move around and absolutely nothing to do other than being grateful that she was spared the worse fate. If it wasn't for the pouch, she might just go mad with boredom, instead of Dementation.

It was just that... well...

Would she always just be someone for Harry to save?

She had tried so hard to be her own person. She'd worked like mad to stay ahead in all her classes. She had become an army General, and won many victories. She had named herself a heroine, banded together with her friends, and fought bullies.

But when the people gossiped about her, Harry had set ghosts on them. When the bullies she fought had tried to get revenge, Harry glued them to the ceiling. When some unknown entity had framed her for murder (she was starting to believe that it hadn't really been her, now), he'd declared enmity on an ancient House and threatened to kill off half the Wizengamot for her. And now that she had been sent to Azkaban, Harry had broken in to make sure she was fine and given her some tools to pass the time while he went about gathering evidence to prove her innocence.

Harry was the hero, Dumbledore had said, and the story revolved around him. And whoever she might have been otherwise, she had been swallowed up, and now she was just the girl he had to save, over and over.

It had been important to her before. It still was. But somehow, the idea seemed more childish to her now; it all paled in comparison to being eaten by Dementors. How many people were in this fortress, suffering day and night, like she had thought she would, too? She had heard that man sob, yesterday, and just because she couldn't hear him from here didn't mean he wasn't there. The suffering was still happening. So nearby. Wouldn't those people give anything to have a friend like Harry, who would come save them no matter what?

Her Patronus wavered and brightened, wavered and brightened again, and she quickly dropped her wand, as the otter had told her to do. There was a soft touch of emptiness at her mind, almost imperceptible but still there, but she knew where it was coming from and disregarded it. She picked up her wand, but didn't recast the Patronus Charm. Not now.

She carefully reread the last paragraph in the book, and turned the page.

Maybe history would just remember her as the Mad Muggleborn who had attacked Draco Malfoy for no good reason. Maybe Harry would pull a marvelous stunt and she'd be the innocent girl he saved from Azkaban. Maybe she would never have her own story. But maybe that was alright. The best thing she could do was to just to be herself, and accept wherever that led. And right now, that meant to study hard, and apply herself to learning anything she could from the books she had.

People grow up by being put into grown-up situations, Professor Dumbledore had said. And that was true, she knew now.

She had a lot of growing up to do.

Hermione turned another page.

It might not have been Harry, she considered. Or not just Harry. The cloak he had lent her before wasn't The Cloak of Invisibility, and he could hardly have two, could he? It had just seemed like it was made in imitation of this one, or maybe that was just how all invisibility cloaks felt.

Or maybe that memory was altered too, a little voice in the back of her mind said.

That was the terrible thing about the wizarding world. Not even your thoughts were safe. You couldn't trust your emotions when Dementors might be nearby; you couldn't trust your memories when someone might have changed them. Only cool logic remained, at least as long no one confunded you. And whatever you thought, felt or remembered, someone might pluck from your mind with Legilimency. Maybe going with Professor McGonagall, that first day, had been a mistake, and she should have just said no, stuck to the powerless, safe Muggle world. Like her mother had obviously wanted her to do.

She sighed and turned another page.

When Harry walked into the classroom, the older boy was already there. As he closed the door, Lesath started casting various incantations of privacy. Then he dropped onto one knee.

"My Lord." His voice was shaky, but he pressed on. "I am sorry... about what happened."

"Were you involved?" Harry asked quietly.

"No, my Lord, I would never hurt your friends. Unless you asked me to."

"Then you have no need to be sorry," answered Harry, choosing to ignore the addition for the time being. "And I continue to insist that I not your Lord."

"Yes, my Lord. But what I wanted to say... If you need my help to break her out... Just say the word, and I will do anything you ask of me. Even if it means getting her before father... I will do what you ask." His voice broke, and Harry felt a twinge of guilt for not taking any steps to help Lesath's father yet. Like I could have done yesterday.

It was touching, how loyal the boy was. Just like his mother. Although for very different reasons. Had Lord Voldemort seen this in her, when he decided to subvert Bellatrix for his own purposes?

He opened his mouth to gently turn the boy's help down, but then his mind caught up with what he was doing and he closed it again, reconsidering.

Of course the boy wasn't just offering to help Hermione, he was still hoping that Harry would get his father out of Azkaban as he had done for his mother. Maybe he even hoped to help with that. Lesath probably didn't know that he was the product of rape, that his mother had been given as a "reward" to the Lestranges, and Harry certainly wasn't going to tell him.

And while there was little the boy could do to help Hermione, he might perhaps be able to help his own father, and the other prisoners of Azkaban. It wouldn't even be using him, for if there was anyone who was motivated to do something about Dementors, it would be the boy who'd been agonizing over them for all his life. But would he be able to cast the True Patronus Charm?

"Get up, and take a chair." Harry gave the example himself by sitting down on a chair the wrong way, folding his arms across the back. Lesath slowly, respectfully, followed suit. "Tell me, Lesath, if you want to share... How did you grow up?"

The boy swallowed.

"After they took away my parents, they sent me to a Muggle orphanage. It was okay, I guess. I stopped slipping up and saying things about magic quickly enough, as the others just made fun of me when I did."

"What do you think happens when we die?"

Lesath blinked at the non-sequitur, but didn't question it. "Nothing, my Lord. We just cease to be." He shrugged. "No pain or misery, at least."

Well, at least half of that was promising. "Have you learned the Patronus Charm?"

Another confused blink. "No, my Lord."

"Why not? For someone like you I would imagine opposing Dementors would be at the forefront of your mind."

"It's – I couldn't really show up to the lesson. The Gryffindors would never me accept there, and it's not really a thing you're supposed to try when you're in Slytherin anyway."

Harry nodded. Of course, someone like Lesath could not be seen doing anything out of the ordinary, or he'd be beaten up again.

"Would you like to learn?"

Lesath looked surprised. "Anything you ask of me."

"No... I'm not asking it of you. I just want to know whether you, personally, would like to be able to cast a Patronus Charm."

Lesath seemed to consider the question for a moment.

"Yes, I think I would like that."

Harry smiled. Even if it wouldn't work, if his mindset of accepting death as a release would make him unsuitable to perform the True Patronus Charm, just knowing the normal version of the spell would be a good thing for the boy. And if it did work...

"Meet me here tomorrow, at 8pm."

Draco was lying on the luxurious bed in a private room in St. Mungo's Hospital for Magical Maladies and Injuries. He was staring at the ceiling, a sick ball of guilt churning in his stomach.

His father had not been pleased, when Draco told him everything that happened this year.

It had taken Lucius Malfoy almost no time to point out where Draco had been tricked. A prediction of "about seven" magical children, which turned out to be close to the real number, wasn't actually proof of anything. Even if the whole genetics thing was accurate about things like eye color (and it probably wasl Harry couldn't just have faked all those books), there was no reason to believe that magic followed the same rules. Most magic didn't seem to obey the rules of physics from Harry's books. But Harry had gotten him to accept the "evidence" while he was distracted by the much worse possibility, and then he hadn't realized he should reconsider afterwards. And Harry had told him he couldn't make himself believe something else, and so he hadn't tried. But that had been a lie too. You could make yourself believe that blue was green if you tried hard enough.

But the thing was... even if the first step to losing his belief in blood purism had been a lie, there was still all the rest. Once you knew what you were looking for, you couldn't stop seeing it.

It wasn't just that Hermione Granger was the most powerful student of their year, except for himself. As his father had pointed out, you got exceptions in every group; Hermione Granger might be an exceedingly rare case, and highly awkward for Malfoy's politics, but a Mudblood like that would pop up every century or so, and Draco just had the bad luck of having one in his year.

But if you looked at the other Mudbloods in his year, they didn't seem any worse on average than the purebloods or halfbloods. Justin Finch-Fletchley was normal, for a Hufflepuff, and Dean Thomas was also around average. Anthony Goldstein, the son of two Muggle-borns, was near the top of their year. Gregory Goyle, pureblood though he was, was magically quite weak, and the purebloods in the first year were overall not doing any better than the halfbloods. It really, really, looked exactly like the way you would expect the world to look if there was no difference between Muggleborns and purebloods whatsoever.

He'd explained all these things, as his father listened patiently, with a sad look on his face. He'd had to, because of the Veritaserum. And his father did listen, and pointed out that these observations could just have been coincidences, and came up with half a dozen anecdotes of Muggleborns getting Squib children, or being so weak that they'd had to leave Hogwarts after their fifth year because they'd earned no O.W.L.s. But those were just anecdotes, and Draco couldn't stop himself from thinking that there were probably equally many such stories about purebloods, if his father only looked... Draco couldn't be convinced just by stories anymore, he needed proof. And that, his father could not give.

Lucius Malfoy had considered Obliviating his son. Harry's dangerous game, it seemed, had worked. Draco's style of thinking was permanently altered. But if he could just forget about science, forget about questioning your beliefs and all that Harry told him, he could be the boy again who he had been last year. He could grow up to be like his father, become a Death Eater, and lead House Malfoy's political battles for blood purism, like he'd always wanted.

It would just mean forgetting everything that happened this year.

Harry's teachings hadn't just affected how he looked at blood purism. They'd been in everything. The way he led his army, talked to his friends, the way he had acted towards Hermione Granger and Millicent Bulstrode. The way he thought. And if his father removed the very beginning, none of that would make any sense to himself anymore. You could permanently damage someone, by removing the most crucial memories that everything else built on. So the only way for Lucius Malfoy to get rid of the mad ideas Harry had planted in his son's mind, was to remove the entire year, except maybe for the classes.

And he would have done that. It would have meant taking Draco out of Hogwarts, teaching him at home, relinquishing the political advantage of being at Hogwarts together with the other heirs of pureblood families, and the chance of his son growing into the leadership. But Lucius Malfoy would have done that, if Draco hadn't begged him not to.

On seeing the possibility to just forget everything, Draco had felt hopeful for a moment. But then he realized what it would mean.

The person he was now, that's what it would destroy. He would not remember having been an army General, or how to think creatively. He would no longer know that he had it in him to inspire and lead the best people of all houses. If he eventually did return to school with a plausible excuse for his absence, he would take leadership of Slytherin, the House of bullies and losers, and never question it or even consider it a bad thing.

He would not have guessed this even a day earlier, but when given the choice, he realized that being the person he now was meant more to him than being the next Lord Malfoy. And that's why he had begged his father not to Obliviate him. And his father loved him, so he hadn't. There was just one thing he had removed, because, apparently, Draco had been an idiot and done something that would have given Harry Potter and Dumbledore power over him, but Draco had agreed to that.

And he was still the next Lord Malfoy. Despite everything, his father didn't disown him. Lucius Malfoy hoped that his son would grow wiser in time, and use his new-found desire for proving everything to see the obvious proofs that blood purism was true. But if not... Lord Malfoy was willing to gamble everything he believed in on his son turning out well regardless.

It had brought tears to Draco's eyes, and he'd told his father about the Patronus, and showed him that he could cast it. If Lucius Malfoy was dismayed by this new skill, he didn't show it. He also accepted Draco's word that Salazar Slytherin could cast this spell without an argument.

Draco had been in a magical sleep for most of the rest of the day and the following morning, as his body restored from the effects of the Blood-Cooling Charm. He was still feeling weak, but the Healer had said he'd be able to go back home by the end of the week.

The door opened, and Lucius Malfoy came in.

"What happened?" Draco croaked. He hadn't seen any newspapers, and the Healers hadn't given him any news. His father sat by his bed, a gentle smile on his face, and stroked his son's hairs.

"Don't worry, Draco. You have been avenged." A look of grim satisfaction briefly drew over his father's face, before softening again. "She is in Azkaban."

What?

"But I thought you were just going to have her sent to Nurmengard?" In a small part of his mind he had already worried that that might be excessive; he would have been content with having her permanently exiled from the wizarding world. But she had done something totally, absolutely, horrendously bad to him, and he'd been burning with that feeling of betrayal, so he had agreed that it was only right. But this –

"The Wizengamot was more open to justice than I expected them to be."

"How did Potter respond?"

Lucius Malfoy shrugged. "Badly. I do believe I was mistaken about him. He is not who I thought he was."

"Who did you think he was?"

Draco's father just shook his head. "It doesn't matter. He has declared enmity on our House, and I am all too willing to grant it. You are not to talk to him again, son."

Draco nodded. That was to be expected anyway. After what Harry had done to him... There was no way they could still be friends.

"He also," Lucius added with an amused smirk, "threatened to take control of the Dementor in the room and have everyone who voted in favor of imprisonment Kissed. I did think he was better than making ridiculous bluffs like that."

Draco's eyes had widened, his throat was suddenly very dry. "Father, I don't think that was a bluff."

"You jest."

"No. Harry never makes empty threats. I've tried calling his bluff seven times on extremely ridiculous occasions, and he was serious every single time."

"The power of a single Dementor almost killed him in January, as I understood it. How would he control one, when he cannot even cast a Patronus? Like you can?" There was even some pride in that smile, but Draco wasn't in the mood to appreciate it. He was terrified by what might have almost happened to his father.

"He can. He didn't want to show me at first, said it was some big secret, but I wouldn't help him fix Slytherin House unless he did. So he had me look away while he cast, and I saw the light. It was... there aren't really words for it." And he told his father about the scene on that balcony, with Harry's insane speech and the Patronus light that felt like a sun shining brightly right next to him.

In the end, Lucius looked thoughtful.

"Was this also on the occasion when you got him to swear the vow to take Dumbledore as his enemy?"

"Yes. My vow in exchange for his."

His father nodded. "That seems to have worked out. Potter certainly did not seem very friendly towards Dumbledore yesterday. You did well there, son."

Draco suddenly had a lump in his throat.

"And you truly think that he was serious in his threat."

"Yes! Why... why didn't he?"

"The Granger girl refused his help." Lucius stood up. "I suppose this confirms that Potter is not who I thought he was, although I have no idea who he is, then. Thank you, son. But now I must leave you. I will return tonight."

He gently laid a hand against his son's forehead once more, and then departed the room.

Draco stared at the ceiling.

Hermione Granger in Azkaban.

He could still see her, in his mind's eye, clinging desperately to his hand as he stopped her falling from the roof. When they'd trained their armies together, they had worked like a fluent team. When he'd helped her against Flint, the main point had been Slytherin's reputation, but there had still been that sort of connection between them... not quite like friends, but... people who didn't mind each other, at least. Allies.

It actually hurt, to think of her in Azkaban, having the life and magic drained out of her. Despite what she had done to him, he didn't wish that on her.

Why had she done that? She had somehow been convinced that he was plotting against her. Why, all of a sudden? They'd been fine just two weeks before. And no matter how angry and frustrated she had seemed in their duel in the forest, how had she come to the point of cold-bloodedly trying to murder him? How could Hermione Granger have figured out a way around the wards, and not told a teacher about it before? Or had she made this extremely cunning method that had evaded headmasters for over 500 years up on the spot?

It didn't make sense, it didn't make sense. She didn't have the tiniest bit of Slytherin in her! Hell, she'd been too much of a Hufflepuff to fire a simple strike hex. She shouldn't even have been able to come up with such a plan, let alone execute it!

Draco noticed that he was confused.

But that was Harry thinking, and Harry was his enemy now, so he pushed the thought away.

Harry, who would have sent a Dementor to take his father's soul. He felt tears of anger burn in his eyes now. He had thought Harry was his friend, in that strange way Harry had of being friends with anyone. But Harry never lied. He actually would have done that, if Granger hadn't stopped him.

He thought of Granger screaming in Azkaban again. No, she didn't deserve that. At that moment, he would have gladly let her go, murder attempt or not.

As long as Harry Potter would take her place.

"Why did you want to go here? It seems a bit... random?"

Harry smiled, and continued casting his privacy spells. "Because it's private, and we'll notice people coming from quite a distance. Besides... this place means something to me."

The two of them were standing on top of the Ravenclaw tower. Padma didn't say anything through the whole sequence of privacy charms. They weren't as many as Mr. Bester or Professor Quirrel could make, but they would have to do. If someone was spying on them here, well, they might already know about Harry's "special ability" anyway, and Harry wasn't planning on speaking any secrets out loud tonight.

"Tell me, Padma," he said, when he was finally done. "How do you feel about Azkaban?"

She shivered. "It must be hell there. Poor Hermione."

"Leaving out Hermione, though... How do you feel about Azkaban being used as a place to punish magical criminals?"

"I... never really thought about it."

"Could you? Consider it for a few minutes. I would like to hear your opinion."

She was silent for a while, with a frown deepening on her face. Eventually, she took a deep breath.

"I think it's a pretty bad place at all. I mean, if you steal or make a "mud pie" or something or you just have a terrible temper, you're not automatically an evil person. You're just an idiot. And even if you actually try to murder someone, if, if someone like Pansy Parkinson had done what Hermione was accused of, then you're a pretty bad person who deserves a lot of punishment, but getting your life sucked out of you for ten years might be... too much?"

Harry nodded. "I agree. How about the really evil people? The Death Eaters, who were sent there for life? Do they deserve their fate?"

"I don't know!" Padma exclaimed frustratedly. "Why are you asking me this?"

Harry wasn't going to let her get away with not deciding. "Suppose you were Minister of Magic or something, and you had the power to disband Azkaban, and set up a more merciful prison. I want to know whether you would do it."

"I – I –" Padma stammered for a bit, but then closed her eyes and thought about it again.

"No," she said eventually. "Without Azkaban, what will you do with Dementors? It's horrible, and even the really evil people probably don't deserve it – you could just execute them like the courts do in India – but it's better that they get eaten by Dementors than a village full of innocent Muggles. I think that's why Azkaban was made in the first place."

"Ah." Harry nodded. "And if Dementors could be banished so they would never feast on humans again?"

She gave him a very weird look. "Well, obviously you'd do that. I bet even the Minister for Magic would prefer them gone."

"You'd be surprised." Harry said dryly. "Okay, change of subject... You couldn't cast the Patronus Charm in January. Do you have any idea why not?"

"I... what? I don't know, it just doesn't work for everyone. Maybe I'm just not a good enough person."

Harry shook his head. "It has nothing to do with goodness. It might not even be happiness. Could you try casting it, and tell me what you feel? Does it feel like your happy thought isn't enough? Or do you feel afraid?"

She frowned, probably considering whether this wasn't too private to tell him. But then she shrugged and made the motions.

"Expecto Patronum!"

A Patronus completely failed to appear.

"It feels wrong," she decided. "The spell doesn't connect, but it seems like – like I'm trying to do something not-me somehow."

Harry smiled brightly. Gotcha.

"I felt the same way. There's a certain kind of person who can't cast the Patronus Charm, and can probably never learn. It has nothing to do with how good or happy you are... it's more about the way you think."

"How do you know?"

"Do I have your word not to speak of this to anyone, unless there is a really good reason, like someone's life being at stake?"

She considered for a moment. "Okay."

"Expecto Patronum!"

The enormous humanoid sprung from his wand, and lit up the entire balcony. Padma jumped back in shock, shielding her eyes.

"What is that?" she gasped, when she could find her voice again.

"The True Patronus Charm," Harry said, and willing her to have the spell, like he had done with Hermione. He could feel it, the little spark of magic as she gained the spell, even if she might not be able to cast it yet. "This form of the spell allows you to put as much strength into the Patronus as you want, without any blocks from within yourself. In fact, you have to be careful, for if you put too much into, it can drain all your life force, and kill you. But given just the right amount of strength, it can destroy Dementors."

Padma looked awed as she stared at the Patronus. There were tears in her eyes, Harry noticed.

"Can I learn that?"

"I believe so. That is why I'm telling you this."

"And you want me to help you destroy the Dementors of Azkaban, so the prison can be reformed. That's why you were asking me."

"Yes. I'm willing to teach you anyway. But I hope you will help me."

"So Hermione won't be exposed to Dementors anymore."

Could he tell her? She was not an Occlumens, but he was already gambling a lot on nobody being interested enough to use Legilimency on her. There were not many Legilimenses at Hogwarts, and once he told her the secret of Dementors there'd be a world of trouble anyway if any of them should read her mind. But if she knew about Hermione being okay, could Padma really act like she would if she didn't know? And if she didn't know, could she act like she wasn't aware that a solution to Azkaban might exist?

"So nobody will be exposed to Dementors anymore." He stared into the night, to the spot where the Phoenix had disappeared. "You shouldn't do this for Hermione. It will take a while to learn this spell, and even then I don't know how we are going to deal with Azkaban. I hope to get Hermione out long before that, anyway, and she knows a secret that should make it easier to deal with Dementors." Technically, that was true, even if it wasn't the whole truth. "Don't tell anyone I said that, not even Susan or Daphne or any of the others."

"What? How?"

"I can't say. Just don't talk about it, okay? It's Hermione's life that's on the line if you even think about it too loudly."

She opened and shut her mouth a few times, but then seemed to make up her mind. "Okay. Will you teach me your spell now?"

"It'll take a while." Harry had decided, when he thought this session over during History of Magic, that it would be too dangerous to tell her immediately. She'd first need to appreciate that death could really be defeated. He'd selected a variety of science fiction books working with this premise that she could read to prime her mind. That would be the very minimum preparation that he ought to do to make sure that he wouldn't harm her by telling her the secret. "And if I tell you the instructions, you might not be able to cast this true form of the Patronus Charm, and yet you will never be able to cast the normal form again, no matter how much you change. Are you willing to take that risk?"

She was silent for a while, looking at the spectacular sight of the humanoid Patronus still patrolling the balcony.

"I am," she said eventually.

"Then, I have a few books I will want you to read."

Wednesday evening.

They had been at it for over an hour. The older boy was picking up the gestures of the spell with the speed you might expect from a fifth-year, and his wandwork had been perfect for the last ten minutes, but the spell required something more, and Harry could see that Lesath didn't have it.

Lesath paused, wiping the sweat from his brow. "I don't think it is working, my Lord."

Harry nodded. "What was your happy thought?"

"The moment I heard of mothers escape."

It might be a powerful thought, but was it the right kind to cast the normal Patronus Charm? To fuel the Patronus, you needed to take all the brightness of life, and put that into the spell as you turned aside your fear of death –

But Lesath had never had much brightness in his life, had he? He hardly remembered his parents, he'd never had friends. He'd never even triumphed in gobstones tournaments or quidditch, because if he drew too much attention to himself he'd get beaten up more than he already was.

Was it possible to cast the Patronus Charm just from hope?

Maybe it was, maybe it wasn't. In the end, it wasn't the normal Patronus Charm that he most wanted Lesath to learn. If the boy had to be pushed in a direction, it would be better for both of them if he could just learn the true form.

"Lesath... I have made a vow." He stood up and walked to the window, where the stars were just visible. It was frightening, saying it out loud, but if anyone would ever ask him his opinion about Azkaban, he wasn't going to make a secret of it. "I will tear down Azkaban. I will destroy Every. Last. Dementor. And if you are willing, you can help me do it." He turned around, and saw Lesath staring at him open-mouthedly.

"I'm not trying to give you false hope. I fully believe that we can do this, that the darkness can be broken. And I need you to believe the same." He tried to radiate as much confidence as possible.

"I believe, my Lord." The boy's voice ended in a sob.

"Hold on to that thought, and cast your Patronus Charm."

...

"Expecto Patronum!"

Nothing happened.

"It felt wrong, my Lord. Like... like the thought doesn't fit the spell."

Harry nodded. "That's because it is more a thought for the True Patronus Charm."

"What is that?"

"If I explain, you will never be able to cast a normal Patronus. No matter how much happiness you find, you won't be able to do it. But there is a small chance that you will be able to destroy Dementors. I don't know how small." Lesath wasn't like Padma, he didn't have the same preparation. But if he might never be able to cast the normal Patronus Charm anyway, if nobody would ever expect him to, because he was a Slytherin...

"I would give anything for a chance to destroy Dementors." There was a light in Lesath's eyes. Yes, Harry thought. He would.

Harry checked. All the spells of silence were still active.

"The Dementors are a representation of Death, cast into the physical world. That's why everyone feels they are so undefeatable. Because everyone has always believed that you cannot escape death."

"But... Death can't be defeated, can it?"

"People – Muggles – used to think that Smallpox or the Measles couldn't be defeated, but because of scientific research, they were." He saw Lesath nodding understandingly. The boy had grown up in the Muggle world, he probably knew about vaccines. "What's the chance, really, that we cannot get over something like old age?"

It was hard for the boy, Harry could see it. So he took out his wand.

"Expecto Patronum!"

The bright humanoid leaped into existence. Lesath gasped.

"This form of the Patronus Charm can destroy Dementors. Never believe something is impossible just because everyone says it cannot be done."

"I – I believe, my Lord."

Harry smiled. "Cast your spell."

"Ex... expecto Patronum!"

Nothing. Harry hid his disappointment. "It's okay. This was only your first try."

"I... I don't believe I have it in me, My lord. I'm sorry, that I am such a bad servant."

"No." Lesath shouldn't believe that he couldn't do it. Confidence was essential for the spell. "You can. I am certain that you have it in you. Just keep practicing, and don't lose faith. Before the year is over, I predict that you and I will be able to go to Azkaban, together, and destroy every last Dementor. Hold on to that thought, Lesath."

"Yes my Lord."

Harry stood up and grabbed two science fiction books from his bag. "It's time to go back to our respective common rooms. I know it's O.W.L. year for you, and you shouldn't neglect your exams, but if you have some spare time remaining, perhaps you can try reading through these books."

"Whatever you wish, my Lord."

"I continue to insist that I am not your Lord."

"Of course, my Lord."

Harry wearily trudged back to the Ravenclaw common room, feeling guilty. He was using Lesath. He'd taken an enormous risk on an assumption that the boy probably wouldn't manage the normal Patronus Charm, but a lot could change over the course of a lifetime. Harry also had very little doubt as to how much effort Lesath would pour into reading those books – Harry could tell him not to neglect his O.W.L.s, but the boy would always prioritize what he saw as his Lord's interests.

And if it worked, he didn't even have a plan. He knew vaguely that he wanted to attack Azkaban, but could he risk Padma and Lesath's lives on that? There might be an age limit on Azkaban, but he doubted that the same would apply to the death sentence. For that matter, could he risk them getting exposed to Veritaserum? The damage would probably be limited to just a few Aurors, but that was already a heavy cost to be imposing on others.

There were, undeniably, many risks in the course he was taking, not just to himself but to others as well. However, it was either this, or continuing to do nothing forever. He didn't know yet how to finish it, but there were definitely more possibilities if Padma, Lesath or both of them were able to cast the Patronus Charm than if it was just Harry and an imprisoned Hermione. It might end badly, but taking the risk was still better than not doing so.

At the very least now, if he died, there would be others to carry on the work.

Hermione woke up with a scream. She didn't remember the dream, but it had been vivid and painful. And she was still sweating. The sick, worried feeling from her nightmare didn't abate, she was so afraid, but she didn't know what of –

It was very dark, she noticed. There was only the distant flickering glow of the oil lamp on the door. No Patronus.

Panic rose up in her. She'd been abandoned. The Dementors would take her. Death would take her, because that's what they were, she remembered all too well. But that knowledge could not protect her, could it?

She shivered. The blanket suddenly didn't seem warm enough. Her sleepy mind was reeling and she could hardly think, it was like when she'd been sick last year, and she'd been alternating between being really hot and extremely cold, and she'd been unable to concentrate on anything, and her memory had been slipping –

But then, her mother had sat by her bed, and comforted her.

She held on to the thought of her mother like a lifeline. It took a tremendous effort. She felt it, the drain from the Dementors, trying to pull the warm thought out of her, but they were far enough away, and with all her concentration, she could hold it. My mother is called Roberta Granger, she repeated to herself, as she shook her head, stumbled towards the jug of water and splashed some over her face. It tingled, but at least it made her more awake.

She probably doesn't even know you are here, a treasonous voice inside her whispered. The panic was abating, now, and it was replaced by a deep feeling of sadness. But she could deal with that.

Is there anything I can do?

There had been solutions, she knew. But it was hard to remember, which frightened her, until she remembered that the Dementors were interfering. So she just pushed her memory to bring up the right recollections.

What do I have?

She had the pouch. She looked inside it. There was the wand, but would she be able to cast the Patronus Charm in this state? No. She was almost crying from the miserable sadness inside here, there was no way she could envision and believe in that bright future that she couldn't even properly remember now. There were books too, mathematics and physics and spells and Occlumency... she couldn't think of a way to use them. And then there was –

"Cloak," she croaked as she held her hand over the pouch. A pleasantly tingling feeling ran through her body as her fingers touched the cloak that was rumored to hide the wearer from Death's gaze. She threw the cloak over herself, begging whichever higher creature might be listening that this would work.

And she was safe.

She spent a few more minutes crying, not from misery but from relief. The Dementors' drain was all gone; she sensed them, in the distance, but they had no effect on her anymore. Still, she had to eat two whole bars of chocolate from her pouch before she was feeling more like herself.

That had not been a pleasant experience. It had taken her far too long to think of the cloak. Of all times the Aurors could stop protecting her, did it have to be while she was asleep?

Her heart skipped a beat. The bracelet was heating up. An Auror was coming.

She would have to remove the cloak.

The Dementors are a representation of Death, she told herself. Death is nothing to be afraid of. Because Harry, and I, and our friends and family will stand up and fight it! She held on to that thought, as she pulled the cloak off herself and pushed it into the pouch. The Dementors' drain would harm it and the bracelet over time, but it would take days of exposure before they'd stop working, and she wasn't going to keep them unprotected for that long.

She sat down on the bench, and held on to the thought, projecting enmity and an absolute plan to destroy Death and all it meant to the Dementors down below. It took nearly all of her concentration, but there was enough left to notice that the bracelet got warmer, but not hot; the Auror was not passing her cell. And then, finally, it cooled down again.

She got her wand out. With her thoughts so concentrated, she thought she could do it.

"Expecto Patronum!"

And there it was, the bright silver humanoid. She took a deep breath, and relaxed. A few minutes later, the fox returned to her cell.

What had happened? The Aurors obviously hadn't stopped protecting her completely. The fox had been in her cell when she went to sleep; the same Auror was still sending it to her. So something must have caused the female Auror to call it back.

A new prisoner? That would explain why an Auror had entered the corridor, but not passed her cell. The new person would be in the other cell block in this corridor. And if other Aurors from the DMLE had come to deliver the prisoner, the Aurors on duty couldn't be seen to be missing a Patronus...

Was she going to have to repeat this experience every time someone visited the prison? No. It only got so bad because she was asleep when the Patronus left. She'd gone to sleep shortly after the evening meal (with no natural light, day and night seemed to sort of blur together), so around 7... Maybe if she stuck to sleeping during the night the chance of new arrivals showing up was smaller?

Or should she sleep under the cloak? It would be comforting, certainly. But it would be risky, and the bracelet would have her wake up in terror of discovery every time an Auror came by. No, she'd rather keep that option for emergencies.

She got the wand from her pouch and checked her watch. It was 10pm, and she was still tired, but she didn't think she'd be able to sleep right now.

Time to practice some more transfiguration.

"You request... an audience... with Professor Dumbledore." She stared at the young boy who was visiting her office.

"Yes. Is that strange?"

"Well," Minerva McGonagall said, adjusting her glasses. "It's just that it's rather unusual for you to ask first."

Harry shrugged. "I figured I might as well warn him beforehand this time. I want information, Professor McGonagall. If You-know-who is still alive and attacking my friends, I need to know everything. I need to know the prophecy, how we know he's still alive, and everything else that might possibly be relevant. Tell the Headmaster that I'm done humoring him and his crazy wish to keep me in the dark."

Chapter 90: Updating Beliefs, Pt 2

There was one flaw with the plan to wait until the Easter Holidays before trying to expose Quirrell. One glaringly obvious flaw that Harry really should have thought about last night.

There was no getting around facing Quirrell today.

It was Friday, April 10th, of 1992, and Harry was sitting in the last session of the day. Defense Against the Dark Arts.

He had considered contriving a sickness. McGonagall would probably even help him, if he pointed out the likelihood of the Defense Professor taking one look at him and deriving everything Harry was thinking of without even using Legilimency. Or Professor Snape could have arranged a Potions accident that would require him to be sent off to St Mungo's. However, none of those things were very likely for a student who'd been in apparently perfect health yesterday and brewing nothing more exciting than a potion of cold resistance, so if he did get incapacitated, Quirrell might derive what it meant anyway. Besides, it would take some fairly serious harm to stop Quirrell from visiting him.

So, instead, he had spent most of Potions class thinking about other plausible excuses why he would not want to talk to Quirrell about what had happened to Hermione. There were some surprisingly good reasons, he had realized, which he really ought to have figured out even without a motive to hide his real thoughts from the Defense Professor.

At the end of class, just as Harry had expected, Quirrell held him back, and told him to follow him to his office. As he trailed after the Defense Professor, Harry cleared his mind and, like an Occlumency barrier, turned into a version of Harry who hadn't had yesterday's disturbing conversation.

The door closed behind them with a soft click.

"I was rather put out when I heard about Monday's trial, Mr. Potter," the Defense Professor spoke in an icy voice, once he had cast all the usual privacy charms. "It appears that you have still not learned how to lose."

"I am well aware that what I did was stupid," Harry said coldly. "But losing is for points, not people."

Quirrell slammed his hand down hard on his desk. "Pretending to lose is for everything! You should have gritted your teeth and acted upset, while outwardly resigning yourself to the situation. Then you could have made arrangements to retrieve Granger afterwards, perhaps even before she was brought to Azkaban! Instead, you drew attention to yourself in the worst possible way. You threw away all semblance of maturity by positing your ridiculous threat against House Malfoy, casually destroying your reputation by showing yourself as a deluded child with an over-inflated ego. And besides that, you did immeasurable harm to yourself by causing Lord Malfoy to lose his fear of you."

Harry nodded silent agreement. Not being a complete idiot, he'd eventually worked out who Lucius Malfoy had thought he was talking to in front of the Wizengamot. And the Dark Lord Voldemort would certainly never promise his enmity in a deadly voice, he'd just say something that would actually feel like a threat to Lucius – without even being understandable to other people in the room, as Voldemort presumably knew some things about Lucius most people didn't.

"And then," Quirrell bitterly continued. "When your halfway decent plan failed, did you attempt to negotiate, or execute a maneuver that could win the respect of Britain's powerful? No, you made an insane threat. What would you have done if you had actually been required to execute it? Murder the majority of the largest political body of Britain? Do you honestly expect that you would have been allowed to live, following such an act? Any in that room, save perhaps for Miss Granger herself, would have killed you afterwards. You are but a mere child, and for all your machinations you do not have the power to defend yourself from those who wish you ill, once your allies have cause to abandon you."

"I know," Harry murmured. Mostly, he remembered those dark moments in the ancient halls of the Wizengamot in terms of shame, but he hadn't been able to stop himself from considering what would have happened if Hermione hadn't spoken up. None of the likely outcomes were good. There were some very good reasons why his dark side had moved on to alternative ideas.

The Defense Professor sat down, still glaring angrily at Harry. "And now, here we are. Unless you play your hand remarkably well, it is likely going to follow you for the rest of your life. If Granger escapes from Azkaban, they will suspect you because you drew attention to yourself, so that line is closed to you. If your... ah... proclivity with Dementors ever becomes public knowledge, they will understand that you were serious, and those who believe themselves to be pure of heart will never willingly follow you anymore. How will you lead Magical Britain then? Or would you prefer never to show that particular prowess, and allow the world to continue believing that you are a fool? Your youth might give you some excuse, but once you establish yourself in power even your earliest endeavors will be subject to public scrutiny. All for your lack of sense and unwillingness to think beyond the moment!" His eyes flashed, as he gestured for Harry to sit down as well. "Have you at least given some thought on how you will deal with the consequences of your stupidity?"

No. He'd been thinking of other things, such as phoenixes, taking down Azkaban, Who-Framed-Hermione-Granger and How-To-Free-Hermione-Granger. Even if he had thought about it (which he probably should have), Harry wasn't quite sure that he wanted to lead Magical Britain. But Quirrell obviously didn't want to hear about that. "I could make it seem like I was trying to get everyone to write me off as a stupid kid, so they won't see it coming when I strike?"

Quirrell waved a hand irritably. "That won't work. It might be effective for those who are playing the game on level three and model you as a level two player, but to most people it will sound like little more than an excuse. Besides, the claim will be unmasked for its dishonesty the instant your variation of the Patronus Charm is discovered."

"Point taken. So what would you suggest I do, then?"

The Defense Professor fixed him with a glare. "I am not sure you deserve my advice, Mr. Potter."

Harry shrugged. He honestly didn't care much at this point. The Defense Professor raised his eyebrows.

"You will care, Mr. Potter, when these events come back to hurt you." He poured two cups of tea, and pushed one towards Harry, giving him a long, hard look.

"You will say that your bluff was for the Headmaster," he said quietly. "He was aware of your abilities and might have been sufficiently alarmed at you considering such a step that he would allow you to spend your money as you desired. It will be your responsibility to procure the Headmaster's cooperation with such an explanation, but since he defended your actions before the Wizengamot, I suspect it will not be hard." He took a sip. "Naturally, there are some who will wonder what you would have done if he had called your bluff. The answer is that you would indeed have canceled the Patronuses to prove your point, conjured your own in protection of the Lords and Ladies, and then used that position to bargain with Dumbledore – or indeed, with Lord Malfoy, as he might have been more willing to see your point of view when it was only your Patronus standing between him and a Dementor. You will be expected to demonstrate your Patronus-destroying ability, of course."

That might be a little troublesome, Harry thought. But perhaps if he gave the idea some further thought it could be made to work. Maybe once he and his army of True Patronus Casters had eliminated all Dementors in the world, it would be safe to give this explanation.

"Of course," the Defense Professor continued, "anyone with a modicum of intelligence will see all the glaring flaws in such a plan. However, taking into account that you are a first-year child, it may be perceived as an acceptable error of judgment, and fall into obscurity amidst your more successful accomplishments, once you achieve greatness."

The words felt oddly foreboding, and yet the voice was nothing but resigned. Perhaps it was no more than Harry's private worries about the man's motives, but still...

"Thank you," Harry said quietly. "I'll think about it."

Quirrell nodded shortly.

"That being settled –" the voice turned into ice again "– I must say I am surprised at you. I would have expected you to come to me for advice the instant I was released. Can I conclude that you suspect me?"

Well yes. That was the only reasonable conclusion for that particular observation. Harry had, in fact, been waiting to pounce on his mentor the moment he returned. Would have done so instantly on seeing him at dinner yesterday, to hell with his meeting with Dumbledore, if he hadn't known about Hermione's relative safety. He could afford a little more delay than he had initially planned because the Aurors seemed to be protecting her – not that he wanted the Defense Professor to know about that quite yet – but even taking this into account, there was no conceivable reason why he wouldn't have begged Quirrell's help the first available instant, unless he strongly suspected the man's involvement. Since he hadn't done that yesterday evening, the only safe answer Harry had was to adequately justify his suspicion in a way that wouldn't interfere with whatever Moody and Dumbledore were planning, or give anything away about Hermione. And that, preferably, without alienating his mentor, because he would still really like his advice on the situation.

"Ah, so you do believe she is innocent, then?" bit a version of Harry who had agonized for four days over Hermione's fate, and come to some rather disturbing conclusions.

"Do not hold me for an idiot, Mr Potter," Quirrell said sharply. "This murder was well-planned to evade detection both by the wards of Hogwarts and the Headmaster's timely eye – or indeed, by any Defense that could reasonably be expected from the Headmaster, a rather convenient situation. Naturally, in such a thoughtful murder, some innocent would be placed to take the blame." A brief, wry smile crossed the Defense Professor's lips. "Besides, I consider myself a talented teacher, but even I could not teach such murderous intent to a student as obstinate and untalented as Hermione Granger."

"You suspect the Headmaster?"

"He is the obvious suspect, more so even than you might realize. There is an important gathering of the International Confederation of Wizards, next week. The representatives of the magical governments around Europe will come together to pass treaties and international laws for the next ten years. It would be the perfect time for Lucius to be torn by grief, and certainly a good time to throw away his game against Dumbledore for the sake of revenge. Besides, if Draco had not survived to testify, the investigation would surely have taken significantly longer."

"But eventually, it would still have led to Hermione taking the blame," Harry said. "I admit I also came to the conclusion that Dumbledore had a strong motive. But for all that I have seen of him, I find it difficult to believe that he would plot to send any Hogwarts student to Azkaban. Ever."

"Ah," the Defense Professor said softly. "But the only way Dumbledore could escape unscathed from a student dying during his reign as Headmaster, is if the death was truly unexpected and unpreventable by reasonable means. Murder by another student is one of the very few ways that would accomplish this. And if he must, in a sufficiently noble cause, sacrifice a student – why, who would he choose, but she who declared herself a heroine?"

That gave Harry some pause. It might just be hindsight bias, but that did seem to concentrate some of that hypothesis's probability mass onto framing Hermione in particular. Similarly, Professor Quirrell had predicted in advance that Dumbledore might target Draco...

But if it's you behind all of this, Professor, you might have shaped your plans to frame the Headmaster, and taken care to cast suspicion on him in advance.

The concept of 'evidence' had something of a different meaning, when you were dealing with someone who had declared themselves to play the game at 'one level higher than you'.

"You are an obvious suspect too," Harry replied. "As Professor Snape pointed out yesterday, the Defense Professor always is. The wards did not give alarm, which points to staff involvement, and the method by which Draco was attacked suggests a substantial amount of cunning, especially since the perpetrator would have needed to select a method that could conceivably have been transparent to a child reading Hogwarts: a History. You are powerful enough to have pulled off those Memory Charms, and skilled enough to cover up potential incriminating evidence. I do not know what exact motives you might have had, but you play the game on a sufficiently high level that this is only to be expected."

"I suppose I cannot be offended, as your reasons are sound," the Defense Professor said with a sip of his tea. "But you normally would not let vague suspicions stop you, and I am hardly the only one with the skills and opportunity to accomplish this."

"Well," Harry started. "I figured that it was obvious that you didn't want to save Hermione. If you did, you would have."

"That is an intriguing idea. How do you imagine I would have achieved that?"

"You didn't go to the trial, for a start. I know you were being detained, but you were a witness, having put extra protection on Draco beforehand. You could have persuaded Bones to let you go. If you had gone there and told them what you obviously knew, that Hermione was innocent –"

"Then it would not have made the slightest difference," Quirrell said dryly. "You have seen the idiocy of people, Potter, do you truly believe they will listen to sense? In truth, I considered it probable that she would not lightly be sent to Azkaban, because she is so young. Drawing attention away from her youth and on to a tale of innocence they would not believe would hardly be helpful. Even Headmaster Dumbledore understood that."

"But you could have gone there, and reacted on what actually was happening, rather than on what you expected beforehand. I went there without a plan, and if not for Dumbledore's interference, I could have saved her using Lucius's life debt."

"A plan you could have come up with beforehand, without first making an embarrassment of yourself." He smiled dryly. "I do not think the DMLE would have let me go for the pure sake of witnessing the trial. If I went there, I would be expected to speak. Which, as I said, would not have been helpful. Even with the advantage of hindsight, I doubt that I could have done much good, other than perhaps clout you over the head before you could go on to make the idiotic threats you did."

"You could have asked to speak to Malfoy beforehand. He hates Dumbledore more than Hermione, if you explained your theory about Dumbledore's motives to him, he might have agreed."

"That would involve telling him about your slipping up and mentioning his promise to Dumbledore. A mistake, I daresay, you would hardly want him to know about. Nor would it have changed much. Lord Malfoy has no advantage to gain in going after Dumbledore, who could just deny his involvement. He would not cancel the trial. Even if he truly did not believe that Miss Granger was guilty, he would seek her destruction regardless, for the humiliation she brought to his House on Saturday. Besides, he is hardly beyond suspicion himself."

"You think Lucius Malfoy would have tried to kill his own son?"

"Why not? From Mr. Malfoy's recorded testimony, I gather that you enjoyed some success in changing young Mr. Malfoy's political views. If Lucius Malfoy learned of that earlier... he might have decided that his former heir had become a liability."

"Padma came up with a similar theory," Harry said. "But I don't buy it. Draco is entirely convinced that his father loves him, and there is plenty of evidence pointing in that direction too. Besides, if Lucius set up the whole thing himself, then why did he decline Dumbledore's offer of coming to an agreement about Hermione? Why did he ask an insanely high price to dispense with the blood debt, when he could have known Dumbledore would not let me pay it? He wouldn't actually care that much about throwing Hermione into Azkaban, and he could have gained a large political advantage and got rid of the debt he holds to House Potter, by bargaining to have her wand snapped instead. And that would be sufficient revenge for a mere humiliation, especially with Draco's testimony under Veritaserum that he only lost because he was tired."

"Perhaps," Quirrell said ponderously.

"Getting back to the point," Harry went on. "There's also the matter of you saving Draco. That was a life debt, right there. And Malfoy couldn't have said that you created the circumstances deliberately, not without casting doubt on Hermione's testimony. If we'd both claimed a life debt together and asked for Hermione's life..."

"Life debts are not personal, Potter. You can have a life debt to a Noble House, but not to a commoner."

"But you are noble, aren't you?" He might as well use the conversation as a good excuse for polling the man about Monroe.

Quirrell carefully put down his tea. "Amelia mentioned those suspicions to me. I see that she has also spoken to others. Who else is aware of this?"

Harry didn't respond.

The Defense Professor stood up to face the fireplace, turning his eyes away from Harry. When he spoke again, his voice was less sharp, and more bitter.

"I know the one she was speaking of, of course. David Monroe. The kind of hero anyone would recognize from fairy tales, wielding justice and vengeance like twin wands against his personal nemesis, a Dark Lord who was a threat to far more than just himself." Professor Quirrell gave a soft, bitter laugh. "Do you know, at that time I thought myself already cynical, and yet... well."

The silence stretched, as Harry listened intently.

"In all honesty," said Professor Quirrell, continuing to stare at the fire, "I still don't understand it. They should have known that their lives depended on Monroe's success. And yet it was as if they tried to do everything they could to make his life unpleasant. To throw every possible obstacle in his way. I was not naive, Mr. Potter, I wouldn't have expected the power-holders to align themselves with him so quickly – not without something in it for themselves. But their power, too, was threatened; and so I was shocked how they seemed content to step back, and leave all burdens of responsibility to him. They sneered at their benefactor's performance, remarking among themselves how they would do better in his place, though they did not condescend to step forward." Professor Quirrell shook his head as though in bemusement. "And it was the strangest thing – those who served the Dark Lord leaped eagerly to their tasks, and as he grew crueler toward his followers, they followed him all the more. Men fought for the chance to serve him, even as those whose lives depended on Monroe made free to render his life difficult... I could not understand it, Mr. Potter." Professor Quirrell's face was lit up by the flickering of the flames, giving an eerie impression. "Perhaps, by taking on himself the curse of action, he removed it from all others? Was that why they felt free to hinder his battle against the Dark Wizard who would have enslaved them all? Believing men would act in their own interest was not cynicism, it turned out, but sheerest optimism; in reality men do not meet so high a standard. Monroe, I daresay, would have been better off fighting his enemy alone, than with such followers at his back. And perhaps, in time, that is exactly what he did."

"I see," Harry said, his mouth dry. It was taking a lot of effort to keep pretending to be a Harry who didn't suspect anything. If the Defense Professor had indeed been both at the same time... he'd just explained why he would have retired Monroe, and continued with Lord Voldemort.

But alternatively, the voice of Ravenclaw said in his head, it might also explain why an intelligent Voldemort did not succeed, with an even more intelligent Monroe working against him behind the scenes.

"I cannot say what happened to that man," Quirrell said, turning around, and stepping back to his chair. His hand was quivering slightly, as it often did. "But I daresay that if, hypothetically, he and I were the same person, I would have some very good reasons for not wanting this identity to be discovered."

"Good enough to let Hermione Granger be eaten by Dementors."

"If you want to put it like that, Mr. Potter, yes. She honestly doesn't mean that much to me." The Defense Professor sat down again. "I do regret the girl's situation. She was a good student in my Defense class, and could have been a valuable ally to you later. But in truth, even if I had claimed to be this noble scion, it would not have helped her much. We cannot both claim the same price for our debt, that is now how the law works."

"Be that as it may..." Harry whispered. "But all this sounds more like excuses, not reasons, for not making any sort of actual effort to save her."

The Defense Professor smiled. "Why yes, you are quite correct. I chose not to act on half-hearted plans that might have backfired and would have definitely drawn attention to myself, when there was an obvious way to help the girl without any downsides."

"There was?"

"There is. Surely you realize that Miss Granger is not dead yet. If we act quickly, there will still be something left to save. Even supposing she has already stopped eating and drinking, it would take at least two weeks to die in Azkaban."

Harry swallowed at the mental image. He didn't want to tell Quirrell that Hermione was already mostly safe, because that safety was precarious, and if it was Quirrell behind the attack, it would be trivial to send a note to the DMLE or to Lucius Malfoy. "What did you have in mind?"

With a blur, the form of the Professor turned into the blue-and-white banded snake.

"Musst create debt," the snake hissed. "Real debt. Ssave lord'ss life deliberately. Ssay it iss for sson's ssake. Then assk for girl'ss freedom in exchange."

"Ssave life from what?" Harry hissed back.

"Hiss old masster," the snake suggested. "Meeting next week. Sset up imposstor ass hiss masster. Bringss woman. Claimss power over World. Cassts no-apparation sspell. Ssayss your enemy is bad sservant. Torturess him. Then casstss Killing Cursse. You interfere."

"Don't like torture! And lotss of other flawss..."

"Torture iss only brief, and he desservess it. Bessidess, needed to keep ambiguouss whether he sserved Dark Wizard willingly, and you don't want him ssent to prisson, no? No real flawss. Have thought thiss through."

"What if ssomeone cassts Killing Cursse on Dark Wizard? And how do I get there? What if ssaving goes wrong? What if not?"

"I am no fool, boy! Choosse time when sschoolmasster absent. Imposstor hass device to move around quickly. Cannot be targeted eassily. Woman too. I will bring you there. Will ssay I wass alerted. Took you back in time. You walk in, with guardian Charm. Protect lord, for hiss sson. I will be there, pussh lord away if it failss. But unlikely."

"Time device iss ssecret," Harry hissed.

"Not your problem! Ssituation iss important enough to warrant exception. They will think of ssome excusse."

"And then what?" Despite himself, Harry was intrigued by the plan.

"You quickly recasst guardian Charm. Dark wizard targetss random bysstander. You ssend guardian to them, sso are unprotected. Dark wizard no fool. He ussess deadly area charm on you. Too sstrong for your sshields, too broad to dodge. You resspond with sstunning charm."

"Sstunning? Would not even get passt his sshields!"

"Dark Wizard never had sshields. Too powerful to need them. But not the point. You musst catch hiss sspell. I have dark wizard'ss wand, woman ssaid where sshe hid it. You ssaid before that your wand sshares coress with dark wizard'ss. I sstudied this... If sspellss meet – sspectacular effect. You sstop him from cassting or moving. You usse Muggle explossive device. Large blasst. He diess. Of coursse, he really ssurvives. Can dissapear in blasst."

It was a lot to take in. Hell, it would be a huge operation.

"Would ssurely take too long to sset up?"

"Preparationss already in place." There was a content sort of feeling in that hiss. "I told you sso before. I expected you to losse patience with imprissonment ssoon enough. Plan will give you freedom. And power. You will be ssavior." The snaked hissed a strange sort of snake-chuckle. "Sso only needed a few adaptationss. Can execute in three dayss if needed. Sspend time practissing sspell capture and blocking Killing Cursse."

"Musst think..."

Creating a real debt from Lucius to him would be a good solution, at least if there was no way he could be suspected of having engineered the whole thing. It would be better than giving money to a man who was guaranteed to use at least part of it in ways Harry did not approve of, certainly better than negotiating a lower punishment for Hermione, and probably more feasible than proving her innocence. It was just that it would be really bloody dangerous, ethically questionable, and would have some side effects regarding the public's expectations with respect to Voldemort. It was almost certain that Quirrell had his own ulterior motives with this plan, too.

"Why usse masster, not ssome other threat? Sseemss far-fetched. Ssurely other planss would be eassier?"

The snake made a strange movement, that might perhaps be interpreted as the serpentine version of a shrug. "Ass ssaid, preparationss already in place. Therefore quicker than other planss. But ssmall adaptationss posssible. Maybe just have woman and other sservant attack? Less threatening, and will raisse different expectationss, but could work, if you prefer. Could leave ambiguouss whether their masster iss involved, although they musst have hiss wand. Less perfect, but perhapss... Explanationss can be changed, if necesssary, just not overall plan. We have little time, before girl goess inssane. And meeting iss perfect moment."

Some part of Harry admired the way the Defense Professor pushed him into a corner. The Professor probably didn't know that there was a way Harry could have helped Hermione without breaking her out, something McGonagall or Dumbledore would never have agreed to – he might have derived that the cloak had shielded Bellatrix from the Dementors while he was unconscious, but he wouldn't know why, and it was a further leap to assume that it would work even without Harry's presence. And if Hermione was actually in real trouble in Azkaban, suffering constantly, getting closer to death each passing day... then he would have done it. Even taking into account the torturing and the risks inherent in the plan, even if he suspected that the Defense Professor might have set up this scenario just to persuade him to go along with the plan...

But if he has, then what is his motive? asked Slytherin. He seems to be willing to write Voldemort out of the plot, so it cannot be to persuade Dumbledore that Voldemort is gone or returned. So what would be achieved by following this plan besides creating a debt to Lucius Malfoy?

It would allow us to make up with the Malfoy family, Ravenclaw promptly volunteered. At least Draco would appreciate his father being saved. Also, it would put us in the spotlight as a miracle worker who can defeat dark wizards with vastly more power.

But how is that helping him? Slytherin shot back.

He seems to want to make us powerful... Ravenclaw supplied thoughtfully. To what purpose, I don't know. But that fits the explanation that he broke out Bellatrix Black to get us access to Slytherin's lost magic.

Of which he would profit, too, Slytherin pointed out. But I agree that his overall actions and statements seem consistent with his wanting to make us more powerful. Should we do it?

What? Gryffindor and Hufflepuff yelled.

Hear me out. Increasing our popularity and political sway is highly desirable, and might help to set plans in motion to clear up the messes in government, like Azkaban. Lucius was a Death Eater, and has certainly contributed to torture and murder, not to mention sending a child to Azkaban just this week – a short round of torture is arguably a fair punishment, or rather, far less than he deserves, since it is unlikely that he will ever be sentenced for his crimes. And it will help Hermione.

The plan is risky, though, Ravenclaw pointed out.

More risky than leaving Hermione in Azkaban, where any number of circumstances could cause a thorough search of her cell, and the discovery that she has a wand and invisibility cloak? Slytherin asked. Once that happens, we might not get into too much trouble, but at the very minimum Hermione will no longer be protected. So right now, not acting is also dangerous.

There have to be other ways of getting her out, Gryffindor protested. Ways that do not require deceit.

Like what? Slytherin asked simply.

Harry swallowed. Even if the Defense Professor had set the entire thing up to push him into a corner, could he afford to refuse it?

What if this is the only way to save Hermione?

He didn't know. The idea was starting to seem a lot more appealing, if he could tweak it here and there. But he also had a nagging feeling that – despite the plan's lack of murder – Hermione would probably have told him not to go to such lengths to save her.

"You hessitate," the snake concluded as the silence stretched. "Why? Plan ssolid. Can explain in more detail if wissh. Had four dayss in cusstody to think about ssmallesst detailss."

"Need more time," Harry stalled. "Many thingss to conssider! Can I ssleep on thiss?"

The snake shook. "Musst know tonight, to sset everything in motion. If we wait a day, we cannot do the plan for another day. Iss that worth it?"

Harry frowned. "Tonight after dinner?" Dinner would start in less than an hour, but he would still have six Time-Turned hours to think.

"That sshould be acceptable," the snake hissed, and turned back into Professor Quirrell.

In hindsight, Harry would remember that he should have just left. Think over the plan, like he said he would do, and return after dinner. He certainly should not have decided that he needed more information about two of yesterday's open questions to make an informed decision.

"Dumbledore and the others think You-Know-Who did this," Harry volunteered. "I am not so convinced, but it seems... relevant." He didn't say more, of course. If anyone was managing to listen in, they didn't need to know what had passed between him and the snake.

"The Dark Lord?" Quirrell raised an eyebrow. "What motive would he have?"

"The Headmaster thinks that he sees me as his enemy, and is striking at my allies before they grow strong."

"Does he? And did it occur to him to wonder why an enemy of yours would use the Granger girl to kill Malfoy, and not just you?"

"No, I don't think it did," Harry shrugged. "But even if it is unlikely that he was involved in any way, I figure it's worth knowing a bit more about him. I know Dumbledore's take on him, and I roughly know Malfoy's, or at least Draco's position... but I would like to know your opinion about him."

"What is there to say?" Quirrell shrugged. "He was extremely powerful, wielding magics most people had never even heard of. He had only a handful of followers, but he used them to perfection to strike fear in everyone's hearts."

"Was he intelligent? They seemed very convinced he was, and suggested him carrying out highly intelligent plots."

"Such as they would not see the difference between someone who receives high grades in school, or someone who is actually intelligent. I daresay Dumbledore believes that Lucius Malfoy is intelligent, and Lucius thinks the same about Dumbledore."

"That's not an answer," Harry observed.

The Defense Professor smiled. "I would say he is no fool, and his plots are certainly worthy of a Slytherin. I would estimate his intelligence over that of those who fought or served him, although in all fairness that is not saying much. However, there is little evidence that he was more than that, and plenty of evidence that he was not. Remember how he not only destroyed the dojo where he would have learned martial arts, but then also left someone alive to tell the tale of this weakness to the world."

But if it was you, Quirrell, then you did come away with those martial arts lessons. It suddenly hit Harry that Quirrell had learned to pretend to lose in a humiliating and painful fashion, about a year before everyone involved in this lesson had been tortured into insanity and killed. And that Quirrell's list of mistakes he would never make as a dark lord contained an item to never leave the source of your power behind where others can find it.

"It also occurred to me," Harry said (for he could not be seen to take too much from an idle anecdote), "that if You-Know-Who had actually been smart, he would have won instantly. He wouldn't have pottered around for ten years with standard terrorist tactics, he would cast Imperius on a House Elf to sneak transfigured toxin into the cups of his enemies or something like that."

"I daresay he wasn't inclined to use any Muggle knowledge, but otherwise, I concede your point." A grim smile crossed his face. "If I were bored, I could probably take over the Ministry in a few weeks at most."

"So if he was actually intelligent," Harry pushed. He was a bit nervous, but he didn't let it show, as it was a perfectly reasonable question. "Then he wasn't really trying. So what would his ulterior motive have been?"

The Defense Professor sighed, and stood up.

"I will leave you to figure that out for yourself, Mr. Potter."

"But..."

"Let us dispense with games. We both know what you are really trying to ask. I must confess I had expected you to figure it out earlier, although I certainly did not mind. But very well. I shall update my plans accordingly."

He grabbed some powder from a little box on his desk, and strode towards the fireplace, where green flames erupted as Harry sat stock-still in confusion.

What.

Quirrell looked around, and nodded formally to Harry.

"Goodbye, Mr. Potter. I daresay we shall meet again." And then he stepped into the fire and disappeared.

The penny dropped.

Aw crap.

Chapter 91: Updating Beliefs, Pt 3 – Aftermath

"And so you are telling me that I actually employed Lord Voldemort to teach Defense Against the Dark Arts."

Dumbledore had his head buried in his hands, and was looking very old. Harry thought he had never seen the man look so broken.

"Well... yes," he said. There was no milder way of putting it.

"And I suppose it would be too much to ask that this broke the curse he put on the Defense position in the first place." Dumbledore sighed deeply, pushed himself out behind his desk, and stepped over to a faded shield on the wall. After several incantations, he returned.

"I have fired him," he answered Harry's unasked question. "The wards will no longer permit him access without giving alarm. Hogwarts will be safe once more. Safer, at least, than anywhere else in the country."

"Can you bring my parents here?" There hadn't been much time for thinking during his mad run towards the Headmaster's office, just for a few wordless concepts to pop into his head, but that had been enough.

"I do not believe that is necessary, although they are of course invited to visit you for the Easter holidays. As I have told you before, Voldemort and his allies have learned, during the last war, not to attack the Order's families."

"Yes, you taught them by burning Narcissa Malfoy to death, right?" Dumbledore didn't respond.

Harry continued, not quite managing to keep the edge from his voice: "I am not in the Order of the Phoenix, nor do I think that Quirrell is using his old Death Eaters at the moment – certainly not Malfoy, at any rate. Besides... I think I might have undone some of that work when I was prepared to pay a hundred thousand Galleons for Hermione Granger's life. He won't be fighting you, he will be fighting me, and he knows perfectly well that it would affect me a lot if he took my parents. So can we please not go from guesses, and just keep them safe?"

Dumbledore sighed. "Very well. I shall send Minerva, Alastor and some others to guard them invisibly, and then bring them here tomorrow to visit you. That, we can do without even giving them any alarm. And while they are here, I can strengthen the protections on them."

"That just seems nowhere near enough, Professor!

"How much do you think Voldemort expects to gain from attacking your parents? If he has to fight his way through several members of the Order, it doesn't seem like the effort would be worth it. If I put my strongest protections on them, which it would take a full day of work to tear through, it also doesn't seem worth it. You can uproot their lives and ask them to stay here while your father loses his job and your mother is terrified – I know she fears magic and would not appreciate being trapped here – but you must ask yourself whether it would be in their best interest to do so."

Harry almost roared in frustration. "Inconveniences don't compare to dying! Quirrell is insanely powerful. I... I saw him fight an Auror who looked pretty old and very tough, and it was just no match. He could take down several of your precious Order members at once while standing on his head with one hand tied behind his back! Bring my parents here now, and then we can talk about what else to do with them later."

"If that is the way it must be." The Phoenix Patronus blazed into existence. "Tell Minerva to take what help she can from the Order, and bring Mr. Potter's parents to Hogwarts immediately. Be quick, but do not give them undue alarm." The Patronus disappeared, and he turned his eyes back to Harry, looking severe. "And now, Mr. Potter, tell me." The usual warmth had gone from his voice. "When did you see the Defense Professor fight an Auror?"

Harry sighed. "I guess at this point it would be completely stupid if I didn't tell you about the Azkaban breakout."

"So basically," Harry summarized. "Quirrell planned the whole thing, and I screwed it up. But I ended up getting out anyway, learning a lot about myself in the process. And I do think Quirrell probably told the truth, that she was originally innocent, because everything she said matched with what he had told me – at least she did love him, and did not expect to be loved in return. Even if she was never innocent, I'm still glad that she's no longer suffering there, because no one deserves that." He paused for a moment. "On the other hand, this whole thing was a huge mess-up with terrible consequences, and now she will end up serving You-Know-Who again and doing horrible things for him... I'm not so happy about that."

"I see." Dumbledore was frowning, although he no longer looked threatening like he had at the beginning of this talk. "You have made an enormous mistake, Harry, and I wish you had decided to trust me, then. Death would have been the merciful way out for Bellatrix, and that much, I could have offered."

"I don't think I would have been happy with that," Harry said, looking at the floor. It would have been the sensible thing to do, but that was just hindsight. And if Bellatrix could have lived, not as a slave to some Dark Lord but actually get therapy and be free... That would have been worth the other costs.

"At least my understanding of that day is now improved," the Headmaster sighed. "Thank you for that, Mr. Potter."

"Are you going to turn me in?" He didn't think the Headmaster would, but it wouldn't hurt to check.

"No. This crime was Voldemort's, even if he misled you into participating. Besides, we shall need you, now more than ever. I will speak to Amelia and inform her of matters regarding our Defense Professor, and I shall say that other magic than the Animagus transformation was used to break out of Azkaban, but leave it at that."

"Professor... I think I should warn you. You think you and the Order have held off You-Know-Who for years. But that's just... he wasn't fighting you, he was playing with you. If he had fought all-out, he would have won, if not instantly then at least within the first year. I've known him since September, and I've known you, and I am... absolutely convinced of that, Professor."

Dumbledore's brow creased into a deep frown, but he didn't outright reject the statement. "If that is the case, then what do you propose he was doing?"

"I don't know." Certainly Voldemort's lack of effort made sense in the first two years, when Monroe was gaining prestige and followers from fighting him, but what about the eight years of terror afterwards?

"He's smarter than I am. I don't know what he was doing, he never dropped a hint, or if he did, I didn't understand it. I could make up many random guesses, but it would be like... like the old Greek philosophers saying stuff like 'all is fire'. I'd have no way of knowing that the hypothesis was actually true."

"I am glad that you at least acknowledge Lord Voldemort as a threat now. So let me ask you another question. What was he doing this year? The thing that was hidden in this school is still hidden; if he made an attempt on it, I would have known."

"Are you sure of that?"

"Absolutely. Merlin himself might have broken through the defenses, but even he would not have been able to do so without alarm."

"All right." Harry decided to accept that as plausible for now. So what else could Voldemort, coming to teach at Hogwarts disguised as Professor Quirrell, achieve?

He said he always wanted to teach Defense Against the Dark Arts, Hufflepuff pointed out. And that might be true. Voldemort applied to the position years ago, which is how it got cursed in the first place.

It seems unlikely to the extreme, his Slytherin side said, that he would go to the effort of possessing a victim's body and hiding right under Albus Dumbledore's nose just for the pleasure of teaching. There has to have been an ulterior motive.

So what has happened this year? Ravenclaw asked. Did anything out of the ordinary happen that could be best explained by an evil genius executing some kind of plot?

And that was the baffling thing. As far as Harry could see, nothing dark had happened this year, except for the Azkaban breakout, which Quirrell could not have been planning from the beginning (as Harry only discovered the required power in February) and the attack on Draco and Hermione. That had almost certainly been Quirrell, trying to push Harry into following his plan to "defeat Voldemort", and conveniently taking away the two people who caused Harry to think before doing stupid things. He might also have been involved in protecting Hermione and the other heroines, and sending her those messages, but to what purpose? And other than that, what had Quirrell done, or potentially done, other than just teaching? What had he even shown an interest in?

Me.

"He's been mentoring me," Harry said, his mouth dry, his voice sounding hollow even to himself. "He... had plans for me. He said he wanted me to rule, and every thing he did when interacting with me, publicly and privately, seemed to be pointing in that direction."

"I may have been around Alastor for too long," the old wizard responded, "but the obvious rebuttal that comes to mind is that he might just want you to think that."

"But what would the point of that be? To stop me from seeking power, because it might be playing into his hands?"

"Perhaps."

Harry shook his head. "There are some things I need to do whether or not there is a Dark Lord I need to fight. And he knows that. He knows perfectly well that I will want to take down Azkaban no matter what – in fact, he made sure of that, by taking me there. He knows me through and through, Professor. It's pointless to conjecture him planning things which involve me acting unlike I normally would."

"But you think he wanted to make his prophesied enemy stronger? To get you to rule, so you will have followers at your back and call to destroy him?"

"Yeah, about that prophecy... Can you please make preparations to take me to the Department of Mysteries? I need to hear it for myself. It couldn't possibly be a false memory planted by You-Know-Who so everyone would think I was his destined enemy, while really I was just some random kid?"

"There is a prophecy, for I saw the orb float to your parents' hand. And if it said something different, I expect they would have told me. But very well. I shall make plans to let you visit that place."

Would it take eight years to break into the Department of Mysteries, and insert a fake prophecy?

"I think I also want to know... what happened the night my parents died? How do we know that he tried to cast the Killing Curse on me?"

The old wizard shrugged helplessly. "It was the one spell he used above all. Why should he use something else?"

"That's all? I'm known as the only person ever to survive the Killing Curse, and we don't even know for sure whether he in fact cast the Killing Curse on me?"

"No, there's another piece of evidence. There is a spell, priori incantatem, which forces a wand to reveal the last magic performed with it. I cast it on Voldemort's wand, just in case, and can confirm that his final spell was the Killing Curse."

"Wait." Harry's head was buzzing. "You found You-Know-Who's wand?"

"Of course. It was left by his corpse. When Hagrid alerted me that the house was in ruins, I came instantly, and took all three wands. I have destroyed Voldemort's wand afterwards, of course." He didn't mention what had happened to Lily and James's wands, but Harry had a distinct feeling that he already knew.

"The thing is... Bellatrix told me where to find my wand, when she believed I was her master. I thought she had visited the house and taken it from his body."

"If she had, she would hardly have left you alive. But no, no Death Eater has been in your house. Even after their deaths, the Fidelius Charm on the Potters' house was still active. It seems unlikely that Sirius Black also passed the secret to her. Why would he, unless the Dark Lord was planning to take her with him? I have no guess of what she could have meant." [In case of confusion, see Footnote]

"He left his real wand with her." Harry was staring into space. "And he took a spare wand himself. He was planning to die, or to leave his wand behind, or for something unusual to happen."

The Headmaster gave him a piercing stare. "What on earth could be his motive for dying? It doesn't seem like the kind of thing he would be overly fond of."

"You are convinced he was already immortal, aren't you? So leaving the burnt husk of his body behind wouldn't hurt him as much as it would most other people. I don't know why he would do that, but that might just mean I'm not creative enough. And in fact, what if he never did cast the Killing Curse on me, but cast it on himself? It doesn't make sense that a small baby would be the first to survive the Killing Curse."

"That would require a rather extraordinary amount of self-loathing." There was no twinkle in Dumbledore's eyes, only sadness and exhaustion. "And I can think of several reasons why the Killing Curse might have bounced."

Harry quirked his eyebrows. "Like what? The harmonizing of our magics?"

"That could certainly have caused unexpected problems," the old wizard nodded, "although I have never heard of such an effect and cannot imagine why you would have been born with it. I suspect the reason is rather the other way around."

"Would you care to elaborate?"

"I would have preferred to wait longer, but... I know there is little point in treating you as a child." He stood up, and took an ancient-looking book from a shelf. The pages were grayed and brittle, and it shed paperdust as Dumblefore carefully opened it.

"I found this old grimoire in the ruins of an ancient structure of what was once the capital city of magical Italy. I have made copies, of course, but with magical books, the original often has a kind of integrity that copying cannot preserve. So too with this one. There is a lot of knowledge contained in its pages, even if most of it is half-faded, but what is most relevant to you is found in chapter nine." The pages rustled, and turned themselves towards somewhere around the middle of the book.

"Here," he pointed to the left page, which featured a faded picture of a girl, somewhere between six and fifteen years old, but it was hard to tell, "the author, a werewolf who lived some nine hundred years ago, describes a child, who seemed to be possessed by a dark wizard that was terrorizing the country at the time. She did his bidding, remembered things that only the dark wizard would know, and even had the same kind of walk and peculiar facial expressions. Sometimes, very rarely, the child acted differently, more child-like, and did not remember what it had been doing. The author says he believes that there were two spirits in the child, one the original, and one the possessor.

"The interesting thing, the extremely interesting thing, was that the dark wizard in question was alive, and functioning, at the same time. This is the only tale I have ever found of a possession which did not require the possessor to be dead or unconscious. I do not know how he managed the feat, but I have not read all the ancient works that still exist, and Lord Voldemort might well have found different stories. Since learning of your dark side I have come back to this tale, and while the explanation I have pieced together is far from complete, it seems likely that there is some kind of connection. I suspect that, unlike what we might normally expect, he did not try to kill you immediately. If he knew the dark magic to take over another's body, he might have used that on you. Your dark side is really the remainder of his spirit."

Harry frowned. "That doesn't make sense. One, why would he do that, rather than killing me? Two, we know that his last spell was the Killing Curse, why would he go to that effort and then try to kill me afterwards? Three, my dark side is not a separate entity, it is a way I sometimes am. I asked the sorting hat, and it did say that there was only one person under its brim. So it seems that this has little to do with me."

"Do not forget the words of the prophecy, Harry. Either must destroy all but a remnant of the other. That, I think, might have been what motivated him. Should one seek to prevent a prophecy in the obvious way, the invariable outcome is that they end up fulfilling it regardless. Voldemort might have realized that the prophecy would not have been fulfilled if he killed you, and fate would intercede to have something go wrong. Something that would mark you as his equal, which might refer to a transfer of power. When I learned of your dark side, I realized that it was obvious that Voldemort would not have made that mistake. Preventing a prophecy is hard; fulfilling it is easier. If he used this dark ritual on you, it would mark you as his equal, as you would essentially share a part of his magic. And he might then be able to use the Killing Curse, which strikes directly at the soul, but is known to leave the body intact... That would leave only a remnant of you behind, your body, preserved by the possession."

"That seems... extremely convoluted. And rather far-fetched."

"If it were only intended to leave a remnant of you behind, the process would certainly be unnecessarily complicated. However, there are other advantages to this course of action. He would have a child in his power – a child believed by others to be harmless, and moreover a herald of the light – and could use the body to come close enough to his enemies to strike. He might have been contemplating such a possession before, and simply taken an opportunity to win two battles in a single move. It seems unwise to use the body of such a young child, but perhaps the method only works on children? I do not know, but I must beg you not to disregard the possibility merely for my lack of knowledge – I cannot provide details, but what I do know is that your dark side seems like a reflection of Voldemort's personality, and this is the best hint I could find to a process which might have caused such an effect. Undoubtedly there is far more to this tale that I simply do not yet comprehend."

"Right. But that still doesn't address the problem that my dark side simply does not behave like that. Nor does it explain why You-Know-Who died."

"It might. The Killing Curse is not an easy spell, and I am not certain how it behaves in situations outside the obvious. If he was possessing your body at the time, it is conceivable that he accidentally hit that part of himself. Even the most powerful wizards can make mistakes, especially when they attempt magic that has never been done before. An accident like this could well make the spell backfire. And while we have exceedingly little data as to what a botched Killing Curse might do, it does not seem inconceivable that it caused a part of his personality to be blown into you – his personality only, not his consciousness, so the sorting hat would not see it. Perhaps, when his spirit was flung from his and your body, it passed through your soul, leaving part of itself behind? Or the possession itself warped what had already developed of your own personality? You were very young at the time, your mind and soul still growing, so that might be why you subsumed this part of him inside yourself. However it may be, it is still obviously a somewhat separate part of you."

"Hold on."

Was there any chance that this insane story was really true? Leaving aside all the guesswork and unstated assumptions about souls in the explanation, could Voldemort have caused some kind of spell effect that blasted his own personality in a part of Harry's brain?

Dumbledore is generally hailed as wise, his Gryffindor side pointed out. He is also probably insane, but he has read many ancient texts, knows of many dark rituals. In matters of myth and legend he is certainly schooled. I would not disregard his theory just because it seems somewhat wild – if he takes the possibility seriously, things like this might have happened before. Even disregarding the rest, his words suggest that there are multiple sources referring to possession – what would something like that do to the developing brain of a baby?

But if it is true, how could we know that? Ravenclaw asked. It does fit the data somewhat, but Dumbledore had most of this data when he constructed the hypothesis, so we cannot really use the fact that it seems to fit as proof. Is there an additional experiment that could confirm some of these ideas?

We do not need to believe it to acknowledge the possibility that our dark side was originally a part of Voldemort, Slytherin pointed out. And act accordingly.

Act how? Ravenclaw rebutted. If we do not know the extent or the method of the possession, the possibilities to account for are endless. If even half of this story is true, it could mean that something more than his personality is still there – what if he is still possessing us? What if he can take us over any time he likes, read our mind, or perhaps even have us drop dead on command?

I don't think he read our thoughts... Hufflepuff pointed out timidly. He didn't really seem to know about Draco's Patronus, or about the fake spell we gave Tracey.

Or that's just what he wants you to think, said the voice of Moody.

There was a brief pause as the other imaginary personalities stared at the newcomer, but then Ravenclaw gave a mental shrug, and added: This is Quirrell we're talking about. There's really no telling with him. But it would explain why he so often seems to know exactly what we aren't telling him, and manages to deduce the right conclusion even when there is no way he could possibly figure that out from just the information he has.

"All right. I guess it is possible, or parts of it are. I'll think about it some more."

Dumbledore nodded. "Then I guess I shall go and inform Amelia, and the Order now." He sighed. "And I suppose you would like me to formally introduce you into the Order, and keep you involved in its activities?

"Well..." Harry shifted awkwardly. "Please don't take this the wrong way, Professor, but I don't think I really want to be part of the Order of the Phoenix –"

Dumbledore gazed at him tiredly. "Oh? That seems uncharacteristic of you. Would you not normally ask to be included and kept in the loop for such activities? I have been trying to treat you less like a child."

"Well, yes, and I appreciate it, but that's not it..." There was no tactful way of putting this. He wasn't quite ready to take Dumbledore as his enemy – the old man didn't seem evil. In fact, he was obviously well-intentioned, or Fawkes would leave him; what little he knew about phoenixes at least agreed on that. Nor was it certain that he had tortured Narcissa Malfoy to death. But still... "I just don't like your methods, Professor."

"Ah." The old wizard looked very ancient indeed, as he stared sadly at Harry. "And you believe that you can do better? That you can fight your war without making sacrifices, without taking losses?"

"I don't know. But at least I want to try."

The old wizard sighed. "Very well. I cannot say that this is entirely unexpected. Even so, however, as I told you on the first day we spoke, I do believe that you and I are game-pieces of the same color, Harry. You do oppose Voldemort, do you not, even if he is the wizard who mentored you, and you have come to think of him as a friend?"

Harry nodded. There was no way he could even consider taking Albus Dumbledore as his enemy without being slightly more offended about a dark wizard who nailed the skins of Yermy Wibble and his family to a wall, or who had made Hermione believe that she would turn to cold-blooded murder, or who had bound Bellatrix Black to him with dark magic, or who had mocked Lily in her final moments, or who had done all those other acts of torture, murder and general terrorism by comparison with which merely murdering Harry's parents was not even worth mentioning... It was painful to think that it would have been Professor Quirrell behind all that, and some part of him still didn't believe that he and the late Dark Lord were the same person, but regardless of that, Lord Voldemort was his enemy, plain and simple. Whether that meant he had to die was a different question, but should he stand in the way of Dumbledore killing him if there was an opening? Could he be that sure of himself?

"He is my enemy," Harry simply replied.

"Would you like me to relinquish command of the Order to you?"

Harry blinked, taken aback. "What?"

"Minerva has already shown that, when pressed on the point, her first loyalty is with you rather than me. Others might make the same choice. You are our symbol of hope, Harry, and if anyone can defeat him, it is you. You might turn out to be a better leader than I was, or have become now."

"No, I... I don't think I'm ready for... no."

"Very well." The old wizard stood up, and was suddenly dressed in formal black robes. Despite the look of sadness his face was still wearing, he seemed formidable. "Then I shall continue to oppose Voldemort in any way I can, until you tell me to back off and get out of your way. I expect that you shall form your own plans, but do not hesitate to call on me when you need me for any purpose. You may have lost faith in me, Harry, and you may even be right in that. However, my loyalty will always be with you."

-o-o-o-o-o-

Author's Footnote: this text may seem to contradict chapter 53, where Bellatrix says she got the wand from the Potters' house. In fact, it was based on an earlier version of the text, where Bellatrix said this instead:

"Your wand," murmured Bellatrix, "I hid it in the graveyard, my lord, before I left... under the tombstone to the right of your father's grave... will you kill me, now, if that was all you wished of me... I think I must have always wanted you to be the one to kill me... but I can't remember now, it must have been a happy thought..."

This paragraph was altered afterwards, probably to clarify the question where she would have got the wand. Which is unfortunate for me, as I took the different interpretation for this spin-off. :) So, please pretend that Bellatrix left ambiguous where she got the wand!

As for the Fidelius Charm: this charm is not the same as in the original Harry Potter books, where its use is somewhat inconsistent (and would be overpowered if used rationally). Most importantly, you cannot be your own secret-keeper, the protection simply breaks when the secret-keeper dies, and the spell can only be used on a location, not on other secrets. I've written up some musings below of how I roughly envision it could work (and still be mostly consistent with all but the last Harry Potter book), but these details will not be important.

The Fidelius Charm is actually not a charm, but rather a piece of ritual magic (hence why it gets to be so powerful). The ritual is performed by a witch or wizard of great power (the caster), targeting a not-too-large location (the secret), and using one or more volunteers (the secret-keepers). The key to the ritual is trust: the location stays safe as long as a trusted person (or multiple trusted people) chooses to jeopardize their own safety over betraying the secret location (and presumably the people within).

* Once performed, the location is hidden from sight, plotting, charms, divinations or any other magical or mundane means. There are no known ways to get around the protection. Even if you know for a fact that there are people hidden in 12 Grimmauld Place, you have no way of reaching the place unless you are explicitly told about the location by a secret-keeper.

* Only the secret-keepers can tell other people about the secret. The people who are told do NOT become secret-keepers, so they cannot give other parties access. Secret-keepers must be witches or wizards, and cannot be added after the completion of the ritual. Sharing the secret can only be done willingly: if it is spoken under Veritaserum or Imperius, or plucked from their mind using Legilimency, the person in question will still not be able to find the location. This does not preclude torture, however, as a tortured secret-keeper still has a choice whether or not to reveal the secret of the location. To stay in keeping with the novels, let us say that the caster does not need to identify the secret-keepers by name, but they are for instance identified as the people inside the location at the time of the ritual; if anyone wanted extra safety by deceiving the caster about the identity of the secret-keepers, the volunteer could use polyjuice potion. Or, say, carry a certain rat in their pocket to get multiple secret-keepers. :)

* If a secret-keeper is inside a location under the Fidelius Charm – any location, not just their own – their secret-keeper magic starts stressing until it reaches breaking point after one hour and they are removed as a secret-keeper (see next point). When they leave the Fideliused locations, this stress starts slowly decreasing again. So they can visit the people whose location they are keeping secret, but never for more than an hour, and afterwards they have to stay away for a day or so before it's safe to visit for an hour again; they cannot just step out for a second to reset the timer.

* A person is removed as a secret-keeper if they are (a) dead, (b) inside a location hidden by the Fidelius Charm for too long, (c) unable to share the secret willingly for too long (with a similar "stress" timer as above) – where "unable" could for instance be because they are insane, in a coma, under Imperius, in a magical sleep or imprisoned, or if they have sworn an unbreakable vow that would interfere with having a choice in the matter.

* The spell breaks if the location has been abandoned by humans for over a day, if the caster dies, or if there are no secret-keepers left. When the protection starts fading, everyone inside the location will be aware of this, and they will have several minutes before they are exposed.

* Temporary sacrifices (for as long as the protection is active – note that for the unbreakable vow, as described in chapter 74, two out of three sacrifices are of this temporary nature): the location sacrifices accessibility. The secret-keepers sacrifice their own safety (they run a severe risk of getting captured and tortured while they're keeping the secret) and cannot strongly protect themselves from magical tests to verify whether or not they are a secret-keeper. Finally, the caster sacrifices a small portion of their magic to keep the protection active.

* Permanent sacrifices: the caster sacrifices three months of their life (sacrificing "life" will be explained in later chapters). The secret-keepers permanently sacrifice a portion of safety, in that they lose the power to be subjected to powerful personal wards (e.g. blood wards or wards that stop you from getting traced by name). Since this must be an actual sacrifice, this implies that you can only be a secret-keeper for one place in your life. For someone in Dumbledore's position, this sacrifice is simply too dangerous, which is why he could never be a secret-keeper.

So, you can have multiple secret-keepers, but you'd better trust every single one of them not to betray you even under torture. There's no point being your own secret-keeper; if you stay inside the hidden location for more than an hour (for example to sleep), the spell breaks. It makes sense for an enemy to kill a secret-keeper in the hope to break the spell, but then the people in the hidden location will have warning (and it won't work if there are other secret-keepers), so persuading them to speak would be preferable. You could hide a family by persuading a good person completely unrelated to them to be a secret-keeper (without telling them who's in the location they're hiding), which mitigates the risk to the secret-keeper, but then they will have little reason to suffer and/or die for you if their secret-keeperness should be discovered (plus, since the secret-keeper can access the location, they can probably check who's inside it without being noticed, and then they might just choose to betray you for money or other gains).

(I hope I made this watertight. However, I have little doubt that the munchkins among you will figure out further ways to break this. :) Edit: thanks to reviewers for pointing out the "step outside for a second" loophole.)

Chapter 95: Nihil Supernum, Pt 2

When Herimone's eyes opened, and she saw the gray air with a tiny bit of sunlight filtering through, her first emotion was surprise.

I'm... alive?

And then she registered what else was in the limit of her vision. Six Aurors in their purple robes, surrounding her. All of them were looking very grim. And all had their wands pointed at her, ready to fire.

Oh no...

"Hermione Granger," the foremost one spoke. "You are under arrest for jailbreak, attempted assisted mass-jailbreak, and destruction of national weapons."

She was tied up, she realized. And of course they had taken her wand. But on her shoulder, bright and warm, the phoenix still sat.

"You will be taken in custody in the Aurors' rooms in Azkaban," the man continued. "Where you will be interrogated under three drops of Veritaserum."

"No!" she gasped in horror. Of course this would happen. "Not veritaserum! It's dangerous!"

The man smirked, obviously unimpressed. "For your helpers, certainly. For yourself I daresay it will hardly matter."

"No! It's..." she searched her mind for something to say, remembered Professor Quirrell's formulation in the special lecture. "I used magics not to be spoken of with those who cannot cast them!"

The man just smirked. "Nice try. Take her up."

They levitated her from their brooms, onto the roof and toward the door to the Auror Headquarters. Hermione desperately tried to think of ways to make them not do this. But what could she say that they would listen to? She was a convicted attempted-murderess who had just broken out of prison, she didn't get to frame the conversation or pose any conditions. And ten days of Occlumency training from a book would be nowhere near enough to resist Veritaserum.

Then they took her through the door, and she saw the ancient wizard, standing among several men and women in Auror garb, as he gazed at her with a look of concern in his eyes.

"Professor!" she yelled. "Help! Please tell them they must not make me explain what I did!"

The Auror guiding her pushed her in a chair roughly, and the ropes binding her shifted to include the chair. "Give it up," he sneered.

"What's this?" A woman stepped forward. Hermione recognized her from the trial. She had been one of the few to vote against imprisonment.

"The girl obviously doesn't want to reveal her helpers, Madam Bones," the leading Auror said. "She claims she has dangerous knowledge, so we shouldn't interrogate her."

"That is easy to test, Auror Gutierrez. When a witch or wizard tells you they know of magic that is not to be spoken of, you do not force them to, unless you know they are lying. A single drop of Veritaserum will be enough to confirm."

The bottle was brought forth. "Open your mouth, girl."

She did so. One drop would be fine. She could at least still refuse to answer, then. She tasted the slightly-bitter liquid on her tongue, and swallowed.

"Now, Miss Granger," the woman asked, in a crisp voice. "Would it be hazardous for me, personally, if I were to give you a second drop?

Could the woman cast a Patronus? It was likely, if she had come to Azkaban at all, that this was the case. "I think so."

The woman – Madam Bones, Susan's "auntie", she knew – turned to the other Aurors. "We will keep it to the single drop. I will perform the interrogation myself, just in case. Do you have any cell blocks free? Without holes in the wall, that is?"

"A block, third level," the one-handed Auror Hermione had only met once before answered. The woman nodded, and Hermione floated loose from the chair at a flick of her wand. "Let's go." She turned to the bird, then. "And I suppose you may fly along. Not that your kind cares about permission."

Harry quietly cursed the situation as he sped away from Azkaban in a random direction. Why now?

He'd known the plan to help Hermione was dangerous from the start. He'd seen half a dozen ways for it to go wrong: they could have been caught going to Azkaban, the Aurors might have suspected something was up because Hermione wasn't going insane, they could have caught her reading when she wasn't expecting it, she could lose control of her Patronus... but it hadn't occurred to him that she might do something like this.

You really should have seen it coming, Gryffindor pointed out. You told Hermione Granger how to destroy Dementors, and then left her inside Azkaban. If anything, we should be surprised that it took her so long.

Hermione had done the right thing, the thing Harry should have done a long time ago. The frustrating part was how close his careful planning had come. Just yesterday, Padma had managed to perform the True Patronus Charm, and they had spent the rest of the evening considering their options. In a week, he could have bought Hermione out of Azkaban; with the promise of asking Hermione's parents for the money, Dumbledore would likely have consented. And then, with three True Patronus casters and Lesath helping out with sleeping hexes, they could have attacked Azkaban without dying. Today, Padma had started brewing Polyjuice Potion. In a month, when the potion would be ready, they could launch their attack together. The plan wasn't complete, but they'd have a month to refine it, prepare, and look up relevant spells. Four children, polyjuiced as toddlers, would fit together under the cloak. If they got caught, Harry could take all the blame – Padma had found an old spell, binding people in servitude to a Noble House, which would legally exonerate them from anything Harry ordered them to do. And if anyone could deal with the political fallout that would undoubtedly follow, it was the Boy-Who-Lived, scion of a Noble House, who just so happened to be in debt to Lord Malfoy by such a significant amount that the man would have a powerful motivation not to press for his execution or life-long imprisonment.

Hermione did not have those protections.

But she seems to have a phoenix now, which is a rather powerful symbol in itself, Ravenclaw pointed out. And we only had half-hearted plans. How sure are you that you could have kept the others out of trouble? How sure that three Patronuses could have taken down Azkaban without anyone dying, or without the Aurors stopping us too early? How sure that Lesath would have been prepared to come willingly, not just because we asked? And if we truly consider Hermione our equal, isn't it better to have a 100% chance of trouble for Hermione than a 20% chance for each of Hermione, Padma and Lesath and 80% for ourselves?

The prisoners are safe now, Gryffindor added. Would you really have preferred them suffering for another month?

Besides, Slytherin spoke. It will be significantly easier to achieve our political goals if we are not perceived as irresponsible. As it is, we will not need to go into debt, and in the aftermath of this, it should be easy to approach other countries and offer to get rid of their Dementors. Will that not be worth it?

Harry gritted his teeth, and his inner Hufflepuff spoke in one voice with the central Harry as they answered.

Not unless Hermione survives.

Amelia Bones levitated the girl into the middle cell of the designated cell block, locked the grate, and cast Bulbali. Three bulbs of soft yellow-white light appeared in the air, illuminating the area. Then, she waved her wand, and the ropes binding the prisoner fell away.

"I am sorry for the harsh treatment, Miss Granger," she said, in a gentler tone than she had used before. Her niece had told her about Hermione Granger, who was a friend of hers, and it had sounded very much like, well, like the kind of girl to whom a phoenix would come to help other prisoners, and not like a crazy murderer. "I realize that you are not a bad person. But you have shown magics today that should have been impossible, and caution seems prudent, even when you are wandless. Would you see any way of escaping if I allowed your phoenix into the cell with you? Phoenixes cannot use their particular Apparition-like magic within the boundaries of Azkaban."

The girl shook her head. "I don't think I can do anything without a wand."

Amelia nodded, and reopened the grate for a moment. The phoenix flew in and settled itself in the girl's lap. She'd have to check what the protocol said about prisoners with phoenixes – as fas as she knew, the question hadn't come up since Azkaban was first built – but for now, she didn't want to deal with the ruckus of keeping the creature away from its master.

"Now, there's a lot of questions I have for you." She took her notebook and ballpoint pen from her pocket. Muggle technology could sometimes be very practical, for example when you didn't want to carry around an ink well. "And while I won't give you any more Veritaserum, don't think you'll get away with not answering a question, we have procedures for that. First of all, what was that spell that you used to destroy all the Dementors here?"

"It's a version of the Patronus Charm," the child whispered.

"Did you discover it yourself?"

She shook her head.

"Who, then?"

"Harry Potter. He didn't want to tell me at first, because it was too dangerous, but he gave me a note to explain it in case I ever needed it. I read it when I was here."

"I see. So I guess you're not going to tell me how you did that."

She shook her head again. "That would be a really bad idea."

"Very well. Will you tell me, then, how you got your hands on a wand?"

The girl took a deep breath. "There was an otter –"

A sick, twisting feeling, like a thousand wriggling worms, was squirming in Li's stomach.

He knew what was going to happen next. He'd known from the beginning that they couldn't keep protecting the child forever. Sooner of later, the massive breach of protocol would be discovered. And then heads would roll, starting with his. They had all been part of it, but Li had started the whole thing and he would step up and take all the blame. He'd planned that from the first day, when he found the others joining in, and they had all known that he would. He had counted on getting a dishonorable discharge, even though he quietly suspected that Madam Bones would be understanding; the others would not have much more to fear than a formal warning. And that was worth it, to be able to look into the mirror and see a man with some shred of honor left.

But this... This was rather more severe. Someone had smuggled a wand to the girl, and she had used it to break out and somehow destroy all Dementors and nearly allowed other prisoners – dangerous ones – to escape, and the fact that that was supposed to be completely impossible didn't do anything about the point that she would not have been able to do it if there hadn't been a Patronus in her cell day and night.

Leela glanced at him briefly, an unreadable look on her face. Every once in a while one of his colleagues would look over. Guilty, pitying looks, which nevertheless admitted of no doubt: he would still take all the blame. One target would be enough to take Lucius Malfoy's anger at hearing about the events surrounding his prisoner. One Auror who would stand trial alongside the child. She would undoubtedly receive the Dementor's Kiss, phoenix and obviously good intentions or not. Was the same fate reserved for him, for unwittingly accommodating the outbreak? Or would he be sent back to Azkaban, to serve as a prisoner instead of a guard? It was scant comfort that there were no Dementors around the place anymore. He knew that it would not last long.

The six of them – the Aurors who had been in their waking period at the time of the Event – were sitting together in the Aurors' Headquarters, keeping a studious look at the screens showing the Azkaban surroundings, which had just been extended to also show Disillusioned objects. So insufficient were the wards of the prison, now that its Dementors were gone, that to see what was happening, they had little better to rely on than their eyes. The Ministry's best casters were strengthening the wards, but it would still take days to get something resembling actual security again. Other Aurors were patrolling the halls, or flying around the building. But the Azkaban Aurors were kept here, together, undoubtedly by design. It would not be long, now, until Director Bones returned, and placed them all under arrest.

Li waited.

The child finished explaining about the mysterious memory.

"I see," Amelia said slowly. And she did. The memory-plant was well-done. Not only did it completely hide the identity of the girl's benefactor, it also reinforced the idea in her mind that someone might have memory-charmed her before. If required to state again under Veritaserum whether she had tried to kill Draco Malfoy, Amelia suspected the girl would say no. Not that this was important enough to warrant testing, right now. There were more pressing matters, little though she liked them.

"What concerns me is how you managed to cast your Patronus. Even with a wand, your magic should have been drained in your sleep, and you look far too mentally healthy for a first-year child who has spent the last week and a half exposed to Dementors, even only during the nights. You had Auror protection, didn't you?"

The girl fidgeted. But she had to answer, just like Amelia had had to ask, even if she completely understood why some Azkaban Aurors would have sent a Patronus to guard the child during their hours. She might have done the same in their place, but the Minister of Magic, Lucius Malfoy and other important officials would never accept a non-prosecution in this case.

"I didn't need Auror protection," the child said eventually, weighing her words exactly. "I could sleep in the cloak."

Amelia's hand paused on the paper. "Cloak?"

Harry couldn't check his watch, not without getting out from under the cloak, and that would just be stupid. But he was pretty sure he'd flown for twenty minutes at least, more likely half an hour. So he halted the broomstick in mid-air, put his hand in his pouch and whispered "deck of cards".

Oh. Right. This was going to be tricky without seeing them. He carefully removed the cards from their carton, and then put both the cards and the carton back into the pouch. Then he whispered "King of Hearts".

A playing card shot into his hand. Taking a deep breath, he tore it in half.

The girl had been given the Cloak of Invisibility, which had shielded her from the Dementors' gaze. She had left it in her cell, wrapping it around the pouch. Which was interesting, as the cell had been searched while the girl was brought in for questioning, and only the pouch had been found. It was a moderately powerful device, but her best spellcheckers had nevertheless been able to find the secret enchantment on it.

It was quite obvious that the girl was hiding something, and Amelia had a pretty good idea what that was. But she made very sure not to ask questions that couldn't be dodged. The girl's tone and little hesitations might give the truth away, but the words were innocent enough, and those were the only ones she needed to transcribe. It might not be entirely proper, but she would honestly be able to say that she had written Granger's exact words down, and the girl would be able to confirm that much under Veritaserum.

"So," she summarized in the end. "You have told me what you know of the night of your arrival, and I have a pretty good idea of how you managed to resist the Dementors' drain. Now, tell me about today."

"I just couldn't bear it anymore," Hermione Granger answered. She looked Amelia straight in the eyes. "People should not be fed to Dementors, no matter what they've done." Her voice had grown stronger, commanding, like you wouldn't normally expect to hear from a twelve-year old child. "And I realized that there was something I could do about it. I thought it would kill me, but that would be worth it. And then there was suddenly a phoenix in my cell."

Amelia nodded. She had heard a little of phoenix-lore, although no phoenix had ever come to her. "And I bet the creature encouraged you. But a phoenix could not get you out of the building. How did you make that hole?"

The girl bit her lip. "I'm not sure I can say."

"You're not sure? Would it be dangerous for me to hear?"

"I don't know! I had to promise not to tell anyone, but I don't know why not."

"I see. Who did you promise?"

She hesitated, but then lowered her eyes. "Professor McGonagall."

Interesting. Albus Dumbledore was sure to know more about this. "Very well. What happened after you created the hole?"

"The phoenix took me outside, carried me down to the pit, and I cast my spell. I was sure it would kill me. I was supposed to die, so I wouldn't... Anyway, it flew me down so I would be as close to the Dementors as possible. I felt myself fading, but somehow my strength kept coming back, but the Patronus only got larger and I couldn't control it anymore even when I stopped feeling the Dementors, and... And then I must have passed out."

Amelia nodded again. "I suspect the phoenix sustained you, crying on you from above, and thereby stopped you from passing out earlier or dying." For a while, at least, she mentally added.

"I didn't know it would do that."

"Few people do, beforehand. When did you contact Harry Potter?"

She started, at that. "Just before I finished the hole. I wanted to say goodbye."

Amelia noted that down, too. "I think I've got a pretty good overview of the events now. Did anything else happen that you think I would like to know about?"

She stated the question very deliberately, hoping that the girl would pick up the hint.

"I also sent my Patronus to the other prisoners in my corridor and the corridor below a few times," Hermione confessed.

Another note. "Anything else?" The girl shook her head. "I don't think anything else happened that you would want to know." She smiled very weakly at that.

"Then I suppose we are down to the question of your anonymous benefactor. I know you must hate telling me, but do you know who it was?"

She hesitated, for a moment. "I don't know who it was."

Nice try. "Who do you think it was?"

The girl bit her lip and rocked back and forth, but she knew she couldn't escape answering the question. "Harry."

Amelia Bones sat back. "Harry Potter is a first-year child. He does not have the sheer power to break through the walls of the fortress and restore them afterwards, never mind making a pouch like yours. I imagine he'd have trouble even getting out of the school." But Hermione Granger was intelligent, wasn't she? She would have known this. "Tell me why you suspect him."

"He would do anything to save me. He always does. Unless I tell him not to."

"As you did in the trial." She had had her doubts, from the beginning, whether that was really a bluff like Albus Dumbledore had claimed. Obviously this child had fully believed the boy. And the threat had just been a little too mad to expect to be taken seriously, even for an 11-year-old who had just promised House Malfoy his enmity. Too mad, unless he fully expected to be able to follow up on it. "Any other reasons?"

"The otter knew about the Patronus Charm, it warned me about the dangers, and Harry never told anyone, he only gave me that piece of paper."

"But you also knew about the Patronus Charm, and you do not remember putting the books and the wand into the pouch in the first place. So, you were obviously Obliviated. It could simply be that you tried casting the Patronus Charm before you were Obliviated, almost died, and then left this as a warning to yourself."

"That's possible," Hermione conceded. But she didn't seem to believe it. "Any further reasons?"

"The science books. Harry has lots of those. And one of them was on timeless physics, and – and Harry uses that, in a special magic of his that I shouldn't talk about."

Which might have something to do with the hole in the wall or the Patronus, she thought. Or something else. Just how many things has the boy discovered?

"Did you ever see him with any of those books?"

"No."

Amelia Bones nodded slowly. It was a reason for suspicion, but it wasn't evidence, it would never stand up for the Wizengamot. If the girl was right, and the Boy-Who-Lived had played a part in her rescue, then he was certainly very cunning for a first-year child. That, or his helpers had been.

"Any other reasons?"

"He has an invisibility cloak. I used to think that it was the Deathly Hallow, but then, the one I got felt differently."

"But you think it was the same one after all?"

"I don't know what I should think!" the child exclaimed. "How do I even know whether my memories are real?"

It would be checkable, at least, whether the boy still had his cloak. Two weeks might be too brief to buy a new one, as rare as they were. Although, given the pouch, a fairly powerful witch or wizard must have been involved anyway.

A name came to her mind then. Albus Dumbledore. The weak-hearted old fool might well have cared enough about the innocent child to come to her aid. Would he have taken that kind of risk? It seemed a bit foolhardy, even for him, to risk everything for a Muggleborn child, bright and sweet and brave, but ultimately not important, not even a pawn in the war that was lying before them. But then, would it be a risk to him? Nothing in all that Hermione knew could possibly identify the witch or wizard who had helped her. Indeed, if it was Dumbledore, he had even cast the pouch's protections weaker than he could have.

"Any other reasons?" The girl obviously wasn't going to volunteer the most incriminating parts while there were other answers she could give. Three drops of Veritaserum were a lot more convenient when interrogating suspects, but then, there were some upsides to not having the girl forced to blurt out any relevant details she could think of.

"No," Hermione whispered.

Madam Bones stood up. "Thank you for your explanation. I shall now go back and discuss what must happen."

And she stood up and left the cell block, locking the metal door behind herself.

"Who's there? Show yourself!"

Harry blinked in disorientation as he arrived in a different place. A weathered-looking room, but serviceable, with a fire crackling merrily in the fireplace. And in front of a chair, his wand drawn, stood –

Harry drew off his cloak. "Mr. Lupin?"

"Harry?" the faintly scarred man in the old clothes asked with a start. "What are you doing here? Did you run away from Hogwarts?"

"No, I – it's complicated. I need to get back to Hogwarts. Are you the one who sent me the cards?"

"Cards?" Mr. Lupin asked, confused. "No, I never sent you anything. But I can send back you to Hogwarts, after I make a few checks that it's really you." He started speaking incantations.

Harry wasn't just going to leave it at that. "Where am I?"

"Polyfluis Reverso!" said the man. "This is the Headquarters of the Order of the Phoenix. Metamorphido!"

The headquarters of Dumbledore's allies? But... Santa Claus had always seemed opposed to Dumbledore. And Professor Snape had said that the portkey just led to an empty house. But he was in the order of the phoenix, so he must have known more...

Could Snape have been his anonymous ally? But Snape was supposedly loyal to Professor Dumbledore, or at least had been so at the start of the year, when Harry had been sent his father's cloak with the first note from Santa Claus. And why would he have James's invisibility cloak? He had hated James, and Lily had not spoken to him since they were in school. Besides, Dumbledore had told Harry to use this portkey. He must have known, too.

If you see a plot, look at who ends up benefiting, and assume it was the intended result. That was one of Draco's lessons. He had never really used it, but, he realized now, he should have. The note with the Invisibility Cloak had told him to be suspicious of Dumbledore. The later note had repeated those warnings – for strange reasons, Dumbledore was not the kind of man who would take a child's heirloom away, no phoenix would accept that. If Dumbledore did evil, then it was because the war had driven him to weigh his actions in logical, heartless calculations. And so, the only effect of the vain warning with the cloak was that Harry had ended up trusting Dumbledore more.

"Veritas Occulum! And that's the last one, you really are who you seem to be. Would you like to go back now or is there anything you want to discuss first?" The man's face showed concern. Of course, he would not have expected Dumbledore's pet hero, who was supposed to be carefully guarded in the school, to pop in all of a sudden.

He really should go, if he wanted to meet Dumbledore half an hour before his departure of Azkaban and still have five hours of his Time-Turner remaining just in case. But he also wanted to know.

"You were a friend of my father's, right?"

The man nodded.

"Do you recognize this cloak?"

"Of course," Mr. Lupin said. "I've been under it quite a few times."

"Do you know whether Professor Dumbledore had it in his possession when my father died?"

Mr. Lupin frowned. "Yes, he did. Didn't he say so when he gave it to you?"

Why me? Harry thought with a mental groan. But instead he just shrugged, and said: "The Headmaster asked me to meet him in his office. Do you think you could send me there?"

"Why am I not surprised to see you here, old meddler?"

Albus Dumbledore had been waiting for her in the corridor. "I care for the child. And it seems that your Aurors have the situation well under control."

"That remains to be seen." Amelia moved her wand. "Expecto Patronum. Tell Scrimgeour to pass the warning to all patrolling crews that an intruder might still be in Azkaban. Make sure no one goes in or out without permission."

"You believe that she had help?"

"She had an invisibility cloak. A special one, apparently, that kept Dementors from affecting her. It disappeared from her cell in the five minutes between her escape and the cell being searched."

"Ah. Do you mean the Cloak of Invisibility? For that is the only one I know of which might have any such power."

She gave him a searching look. That was quite an inference. "What do you know about that?"

"The Invisibility Cloak of Ignotus Peverell, long-since lost track of, is one of the three Deathly Hallows. Many properties are ascribed to it, although few confirmed. Depending on the source you read, it hides the wearer even from Death's gaze, provides impenetrable shields and stops aging in whoever wears it. I would not believe those so lightly, but almost certain is that it does not degenerate with time, cannot be directly targeted by magic, knows its owner, and, some way or other, always finds a way back to him or her. I have not heard anything about Dementors, but such an ability would certainly not be incongruent with the various tales of its powers."

If that were true... Could the cloak have somehow taken itself back to its owner? Or was Dumbledore just trying to sell her onto some idea to hide the far more obvious truth?

"You suspect me?" the old wizard asked at her searching look.

"I would not put it past you to help an innocent child, no."

"I appreciate the sentiment, Amelia, but in this instance I am quite guiltless. Please, feel free to search me. I do not have the Cloak."

"I would not ask –"

"But you think. I do not mind it, and it might be better to clear this up immediately. I realize that I am an uninvited intruder in this place."

She nodded, and started her incantations.

"So tell me," the old wizard asked carefully. "Is there any chance, for the girl?"

"You know the law, Albus. Any escape from Azkaban is punished with the Dementor's Kiss. No excuses. There won't even be a trial. The only reason not to do it on the spot is that we may need to interrogate her further, and that the only Dementor left in Britain is the one we keep in the Ministry. The certainty of the Kiss for any escape is one of the most important things that keeps the prisoners and their friends from ever contemplating escape: the knowledge that worse is possible, and likely."

"She did not mean to escape, I think. Harry Potter seemed convinced that she was going to die."

"Intent is not the point. She left her cell, so she did escape." She sighed. "I want the girl to lose her soul as little as you do, Albus. I don't think we have ever done that to someone with a phoenix, let alone a child who shouldn't have been here to begin with. But unless the honor of a Noble House is involved, my hands are tied. I don't suppose you have kept any Noble connections hidden?"

"None. I am certain that the young scion of Potter would accept her service if she were to swear to him, but –"

"– the Wizengamot will not accept that if the contract was not in place at the time of the crime," she finished his line. "But speaking of Harry Potter, young Miss Granger did seem to believe that he was the one who gave her the wand and the cloak."

"You would have him executed too?" the old wizard spoke with a pained voice.

"No. In fact, I don't think we can prove anything against him. And since the Boy-Who-Lived enjoys a certain popularity, a mere accusation before the Wizengamot will not lead to a conviction, no matter how much pressure Lord Malfoy might apply. But if he were indeed involved, if we could prove that, then he could ask to have his case brought before the Wizengamot. And in that case, I suppose that I, as the Head of the Department of Magical Law Enforcement, could judge the girl's crime to be inextricably linked to the boy's, and relinquish the right of judging her to them."

"Ah."

They walked in silence through the last corridor. The old wizard looked conflicted.

"You consider asking him for a confession?" She wasn't sure whether she wanted it. The hope of seeing the girl released, or at least saved from the gruesome fate of the Dementor's Kiss, was enough to make her wish for it. But what would the two children's chances be? If they involved the boy, the most likely path would lead to two innocent souls being lost.

"It would be foolish to the extreme," the Hogwarts Headmaster bit. "We need him; if anything the last week has made that clear. Lord Voldemort has returned, and he has started lashing out, for purposes unknown. Harry Potter is the only one who has a chance of defeating him for good." He sighed. "But he has made it clear that he does not wish to follow my command, and he cares about the Granger girl more than anything in the world. Who am I to make the choice for him?"

He gestured with his wand, and the silver phoenix sprang into existence. "Go to Harry Potter," he instructed, "and say this: Harry. As you feared, Miss Granger has attacked Azkaban, and destroyed all its Dementors. She has survived, given testimony, and will likely be executed before the weekend is over. There will be no trial, as she is no part of a Noble House. Tell me, Mr. Potter. Were you involved in this?"

Chapter 96: Nihil Supernum, Pt 3

Traveling by Floo was not quite as unsettling as portkeys, but it would take some getting used to all the same. Harry spun and spun through green flames, until suddenly all motion halted and he almost fell over at the shock. Then he quickly stepped out of the fireplace, just in case.

The Headmaster's office was empty, save for the many sounds. Harry took out his – thankfully unlocked – Time-turner, and spun it once.

"Hello Harry." The old wizard was sitting at his desk, looking at a golden hourglass he held in his hands. "Before I speak, I must know: have you received my message yet?"

"Message? No, what message?"

"Time will make that clear." The Headmaster put the hourglass down onto the desk. "For now, there are a few things we must discuss. I have already used four turns of my Time-Turner today, and would prefer not to go further back for now. In twenty minutes, I must bring you back to Minerva, as though you never left. Have her seal your Time-Turner again and then leave the room instantly. After that, you must be seen. Make sure that people – ideally other students, who are not Occlumenses – know where you are every moment until you receive my message. Not your parents. We do not want to involve them, especially not your mother, as to stain Lily Potter's reputation is to stain yours."

"Would that really give me an alibi? I mean, the Ministry know that I have a Time-Turner, right?"

"They know that it is locked to the hours of nine to midnight, and that Time cannot be looped inside Azkaban. That means that my Patronus can only have reached the youngest version of you, no matter what I asked of it, and that only your youngest version could have been in Azkaban."

"Ah," Harry said, quickly calculating the implications. "That would work. Professor, what happened there?"

The old wizard shook his head. "I cannot tell you. Not yet. But after you receive the message, find a place away from the public eye. Leave invisibly, and come to my office. The password is Fizzing Whizzbee. You will be able to go back in time after nine as though you never left."

"All right..." Harry was really starting to get worried now. "You really can't say...?"

"You will know soon enough. But first, speaking of going invisible..." He opened a drawer, and took out a small package. "This is a high-quality Invisibility Cloak, designed to look and feel just like the one Hermione Granger remembers you having. I have obtained it from a friend who, I am certain, will not betray us. The additional enchantments, I performed myself."

Harry opened the package, and took out a cloak that looked exactly like his own. It tingled, and felt warm on his skin. He threw it around himself and disappeared, the cloak seeming to hug him. And while it was nothing like the real cloak, Harry had to admit that it was very well done. Someone who didn't know any better could well be tricked into believing that this was the third Deathly Hallow, handed down the generations from Ignotus Peverell.

"This is exactly what Hermione Granger remembers you having," the old wizard said. "And it might well fool lesser men. But if they ask you, you must not say that you ever showed it to me, for those who know me well must realize that I would recognize it for a fake instantly."

"That should not be hard," Harry said, not bothering to keep the sharpness out of his voice. "Since when I got my cloak, there was a note on it saying not to show it to the Headmaster, as he might try to take it from me. Does that sound familiar to you?"

The Headmaster just looked at his hands.

"I do apologize for the deception, Mr. Potter," he said at last. "I know that it was wrong to manipulate you. I have no justification to offer, other than what you have undoubtedly already derived yourself. You did not know me then, but I think you understand me well enough now."

And Harry did. He was annoyed by the stupid plot, but in the end, his current view of Dumbledore was based on entirely different observations. And in that, tricking a child who is doomed to be the hero eventually into trusting you didn't seem all that incongruent. Of course, he would still have to carefully reevaluate his perception of the man, taking all information into account when he got a quiet moment, but he didn't expect that this new data would change much. In fact, all things considered, he should probably have done that before – some of his views might have been based on the manipulations of Quirrell, who had every motivation to bias him against the leader of the anti-Voldemort-movement.

"Were you also the one who sent Hermione those notes?" he asked, keeping his voice carefully controlled.

"No. I thought it was the Defense Professor, but –" he helplessly raised his hands. "I really don't know anymore. But time is getting short." He glanced at the hourglass again. "Would you give me your cloak, to keep for you? They might well search all your possessions for it, and I can hide it more effectively. I swear that I will return it to you the instant you ask."

"I suppose." Harry took the cloak from his pouch and handed it to Dumbledore with a pang of sadness. But the Headmaster could have taken it from him any time, he did not need deception if he were dishonest. Harry fed the new, inferior cloak back into the pouch.

"Let us go," the ancient wizard spoke.

The two of them caught on fire and reappeared in the familiar office of the Deputy Headmistress. Professor McGonagall spun, surprised.

"You're back? Now? How –"

"I shall explain this to you shortly, Minerva. For now, could you please lock young Mr. Potter's Time-Turner again, as though it were never opened?"

She looked confused, but didn't protest as Harry dropped the shell into her hands. She placed the enchantments, and returned it.

"Thank you," he muttered to the both of them, and was out the office.

Friday April 16th, 1992, 4:18pm.

Harry strode through the corridors towards a place where he could be seen.

How would an innocent Harry act?

An innocent Harry who had just received that message, and had been left in Hogwarts by Dumbledore, would be confused, certainly. And tense, because Hermione might be dying unless Dumbledore could intercede. But he would not want to tell people about this, because if Dumbledore could stop Hermione, then it might never be found out that she had somehow got a wand...

Acting tense and nervous and non-informative, then. But where? He couldn't go to his parents if he wanted to keep them out of it, the library might be empty, and if he hung around in the Ravenclaw common room, then Padma might get involved, and he really needed to keep attention away from her too. If she was asked to testify, she might be given Veritaserum, which would be a disaster with all the things he had entrusted to her.

Hermione knows the most dangerous of those secrets too, the voice of Ravenclaw whispered. And she is certain to be given Veritaserum. But apparently Dumbledore had still been able to send a Patronus, so if she had spilled the secret, it must have been controlled...

He walked into the Great Hall, where a few children from mixed houses were sitting together at the Gryffindor table, playing a large game of Gobstones. Harry sat by them and watched the game. He was not going to have much trouble looking tense and nervous.

Someone asked him whether he was okay. He waved them off.

Someone asked him whether he wanted to join the game. He said he preferred watching.

Some time later they asked again. This time he actually did participate for two rounds, and got squirted with a foul liquid. He politely passed up further opportunities to play.

There were more people giving him strange looks. He was acting unlike he usually would, but there was little he could do about that. It wouldn't even make sense to take a book from his pouch and try to read, because he wouldn't normally do that in so loud an environment.

And then the blazing phoenix burst into existence, amid gasps from his fellow students.

"Harry," it said. "As you feared, Miss Granger has attacked Azkaban, and destroyed all its Dementors. She has survived, given testimony, and will likely be executed before the weekend is over. There will be no trial, as she is no part of a Noble House. Tell me, Mr. Potter. Were you involved in this?"

The silence in the Great Hall was complete as everyone stared at him, and cold clarity fell over Harry. Of course the government of magical Britain would not allow exceptions to its crazy rules just because the "crime" of breaking out in this case was a phoenix-driven attempt by a brave girl to destroy the darkest creatures in existence at the expected price of her life. That would be sane.

And of course he wasn't going to stand for that. As Dumbledore knew exactly how involved he was, he wouldn't be asking the question if there wasn't someone else listening. If Harry were involved, it would go before the Wizengamot. And while he had little good to expect from that particular body, he should be able to manipulate his and Hermione's way out from that.

You do realize, his Slytherin side said, that you are staking your own life on that hope. You have declared enmity on Lucius Malfoy only last week, and you'll be putting yourself straight into his power, without so much as a wand to defend yourself.

We will not let her be killed, Hufflepuff and Gryffindor spoke together. Not while there is a chance to save her.

Are we escalating again, because we do not want to lose? Slytherin asked. As Professor Quirrell said, losing, or at least pretending to lose, is for everything, even people.

In this case, winning is the more obvious choice, Ravenclaw said calmly.

Harry glanced around at his schoolmates, who were all staring. Most of them had reviled Hermione after they heard of the trial, collective memories changing afterwards about how the kindest girl in Ravenclaw had really been a violent madwoman all along. Seconds had passed by. Harry had to speak up now, and in a way that would get them thinking about their own biases, and might help Hermione later.

"Did I break into Azkaban," he answered, his voice liquid crystal, "when the Wizengamot sent an innocent there to be eaten by Dementors, and give her the means to protect herself? Yes, I did.

"Did I teach her a spell to control Dementors, which can only be used by those who truly care about others? Yes, I did.

"Did I intend for her to use that spell to destroy Dementors, to bring an end to the ceaseless suffering the government of magical Britain inflicts on its prisoners, a use that was almost certain to kill her? No, I must confess that I did not. But then, she was always a better person than I was."

The phoenix Patronus moved sideways and dissolved into the air.

The other children continued to stare wordlessly at Harry.

"Let this be a lesson to you," he spoke, addressing them in ice-cold tones. "There is no need to believe stupid things just because everyone else is saying them."

And with that, he turned on his heel and left the Great Hall.

Friday April 16th, 1992, 4:55pm.

Amelia Bones stared at the Patronus speechlessly, after it had delivered its message.

Albus Dumbledore just sighed wearily. "Much as I expected."

"He does not sound like a child at all," she found herself saying.

"He is the hero." Albus shrugged helplessly. "Amelia, since I don't think I am needed here, do you mind lending me a broomstick, and clearing with your Aurors that I may depart? In an hour, the International Confederation will vote on the question whether countries should be permitted to take Muggleborns from their parents at birth. It will raise questions about Timer-Turners if I give further testimony here when most of the Wizengamot will know that I am there at the time."

"Of course," she replied. "Just give me a moment."

She opened the door into the Aurors' Headquarters, where the six non-sleeping guards of Azkaban were looking over the screens. The tension in the air was almost tangible as she walked in.

"Bahry!" she barked. "Arrange a broomstick, and accompany Mr. Dumbledore here to the edge. I have already checked him, and will clear it with the others." It would be foolish to tell the Aurors to let the old wizard get away, as someone might be able to impersonate him, but the Azkaban Auror was sworn into the wards, so his company would not be easy to fake.

If Bahry was surprised, he didn't show it. He just jumped up and led the way towards the storage cabinet.

"Madam Bones..." Auror Xiaoguang, whom everyone called Mike, was giving her a pleading look. "Would you tell us what you found?"

She just shoved the transcript to him. "Read it for yourself."

He did so, hiding only a very slight hesitation.

His eyes widened.

"She had an artifact to protect her from the Dementors?" His tone was a mixture of wonder and relief. He'd never been good at spying and undercover missions, she recalled. Perhaps she should arrange some extra lessons on controlling body language for him, although considering the fate he had obviously barely escaped, she might excuse this lapse in his outward appearance. Looking around, she saw other shoulders sagging, and the tension in the room noticeably weakened.

Auror Xiaoguang continued to read, a frown on his face. Finally, he passed the transcript back to her.

"Will she receive the Dementor's Kiss?" he asked, a note of pain in his voice. "The poor child only did what she thought was right."

"She might not," Amelia answered. "As Granger suspected, the scion of Potter has accommodated this outbreak. He has confessed as much. The Wizengamot will decide on this case, now. Speaking of which..." She turned to her Patronus. "Auror Astour. Please send a delegation of Aurors to Hogwarts, to apprehend Harry Potter on charges of conspiracy to mass-jailbreak and destruction of national weapons."

Friday April 16th, 1992, 5:05pm.

Up the spiraling stairs, into the Headmaster's Office. The gargoyles had been perfectly responsive to his whispered password, despite the invisibility. Harry knocked, and entered. Professor Dumbledore was sitting behind his desk.

"And so it was done," the old wizard sighed. "Forgive me for not telling you earlier, Mr. Potter. I merely wished for the choice to be yours, not mine. As you had answered exactly as I expected you to do, if I had spoken too early, then I might have inadvertently forced your hand."

Harry nodded. "That makes sense. But then why did you have me be seen? If you knew I was going to confess anyway, why get me an alibi for today's presence?"

"Neither you, nor Miss Granger, can I protect," the old wizard spoke wearily. "That responsibility, I fear, shall be fully yours. But there are three less valuable things in the balance, and those I have been seeking to safe-guard."

"Which three?"

"Myself. Minerva. And your cloak."

"Ah."

"It should be easy to protect Minerva, I think. Her role was minor, and few would suspect her. I know you do not lie easily, Harry, but would you deny it if anyone directly asked you for her involvement?"

"If necessary," Harry conceded. It would be dangerous to lie to the courts, as he might get caught out in that later. Would he be able to just not say anything? "I certainly do not want to drag her into this mess. Or you either."

The old wizard nodded slowly. "It shall be harder to steer suspicion away from me. It is obvious to everyone who would care to investigate that you must have had help breaking into Azkaban, and I am a natural suspect, save for that most who know me would consider me too wise for such a foolhardy undertaking. Today, I have gone to Azkaban uninvited, at your prompting, as Miss Granger sent her Patronus only to you, and there are more than a hundred witnesses who saw that I was told of what she was about to do before it was known to the DMLE. What is more, I was in Azkaban when the cloak which Miss Granger remembered leaving in her cell mysteriously disappeared. If there is any reason to believe you were there, then they will conclude that I brought you, and my part in the disaster will be all to obvious." He fixed Harry with a piercing look. "If you can save yourself by sacrificing me, Harry, you must do so. I am not the king on the chessboard. But if it would not save you, or if there is any other way out, I ask you to be careful. Although we do not always see eye to eye, I hope you acknowledge that I may be crucial to hold off Voldemort, whether you live or not."

Harry tore his gaze away. He felt very guilty all of a sudden. He didn't deserve such a sacrifice, and he wasn't even sure if the old wizard was right in his analysis of Harry's necessity. Certainly Harry couldn't see how Dumbledore would have any chance against Professor Quirrell Turned Evil, but given the latter's mysterious plot, it might well be that Harry could only make it worse...

"Why did you ask me to confess?" he asked, his voice breaking. "You would not sacrifice yourself for Hermione Granger, why allow me to do so?"

"Because the choice ought to be yours," the old wizard said quietly. "And perhaps I would, now. She was always valuable. Now, serving as your conscience, with a phoenix upon her shoulder and the power to destroy Dementors, Hermione Granger is certainly worth more than a hundred thousand Galleons."

"About that... Did Professor McGonagall mention that Hermione's parents might pay –"

"The point is moot. Her crime is now far greater than mere attempted murder, and is not owed to Lucius Malfoy, but to the country. And your own noble name might be revoked for charges of treason, which the destruction of national weapons is filed under."

Harry nodded, thinking. "It was probably a mistake to take the cloak from her cell. It is easy to explain why I involved you today – that was in actual fact Professor McGonagall's idea – but I don't really have an explanation for that one."

"The original Cloak of Invisibility is an ancient and mysterious artifact, Harry," the Headmaster said gravely. "It is truly a device of legends. There are no people in living memory who are known to have studied its properties; none but me, and that is a close-guarded secret. I believe neither James nor his father from whom he inherited it have ever given it to another for study. Which means that the tale that Ignotus's Cloak will always find its way back to its owner may be promoted as the obvious explanation, if you do not say anything that will contradict it. This is a long-existing story, which those who seek the Deathly Hallows know well. I have mentioned it today, in the hope that it will be interpreted as a powerful retrieval charm that predates the wards of Azkaban."

"Ah," Harry said. "But if the cloak is ever found, then it's easy to test that it does not do that..."

"Indeed. It must not be found in your possession, for this reason and others. The Stone and the Cloak were never as coveted as the Wand, but there are still dozens of those who search for the Deathly Hallows who would happily slit your throat to obtain it. The Cloak is extremely valuable, priceless even. That is why I took the risk of having you take it away. If the Ministry found it, they would not lightly return it to you, especially now that it has been revealed that the Cloak allows you to resist Dementors – which will undoubtedly rekindle the faith in some of the more arcane tales of its powers. Even as it is, with people suspecting that you may possess it, you might not have peace for the rest of your life, as others would seek to take it from you."

"Why? I mean, I agree it's pretty useful, but if they didn't know that it would resist Dementors, why would people want it so much?"

"Even just to complete the set – supposedly, to unite the three Hallows is to Master Death, although I believe that that part of the tales is just a myth, for the Three Brothers did unite the Hallows, and yet they died. There are many other properties ascribed to it as well. Most of them are false, as I verified, but from what your father told me about his father's experiences, I am quite certain – although I could not test it myself, and would not show the Cloak to anyone else – that it blocks the Killing Curse."

"That is not as important to me as to most people, seeing as I have other ways to avoid it."

"True," the old wizard conceded. "But you are its master, as I never was, and you might come to understand it better. The connection to Dementors would never have occurred to me."

Only because you do not think of Dementors as being connected to death. "So do you have a suggestion for how I'm going to pretend not to be its owner?"

The old man shrugged helplessly. "You have almost five hours to come up with a good story, and then act the part. I will help you with any questions you may have.."

Somewhere in Harry's head, Slytherin snickered. It appears that the Headmaster has finally learned not to think of us as a child.

You merely need to save yourself and Hermione Granger from getting the Dementor's Kiss, without straying from anything she said, suggesting that you own the device which obviously helped her, incriminating anyone else, or being caught in a lie that would cause future problems, Hufflepuff added. No pressure.

This seems nowhere near as hard as breaking Bellatrix Black out of Azkaban, Ravenclaw said. Stop complaining.

"Mr. Lupin knew of my father's cloak," Harry pointed out. "Do you know whether he is an Occlumens? If they call on him, he would certainly recognize that the one you gave me isn't it. Plus," he added with a frown, "he knows I wasn't in Hogwarts the entire day."

"Mr. Lupin is a werewolf, Harry," the Headmaster said calmly. "And while that is no stain on his character, most of our kind do not think of them as people. It will not occur to anyone that he was a friend of James. And since your father's other friends are either dead or in Azkaban..." He trailed off. "I shall ask Remus to not be seen for a few days regardless. But as he has no fixed residence, and it is very unlikely anyone will make the connection, I do not think you need to fear anything from that side."

"All right," Harry said. "But it might still be a little too much of a coincidence that I have acquired an imitation of the True Cloak, and just happen to be involved in a crime with the real thing."

"No," the ancient wizard shook his head. "Many artifacts are made in imitation of historical examples. Your cloak follows a description I read when I was a teenager. As good invisibility cloaks go, it is not at all unusual. I would not so readily have agreed to make Miss Granger remember a cloak that appeared special to her otherwise."

This is almost going to be easy, Gryffindor remarked optimistically.

Don't say stupid stuff, Slytherin suggested.

"Thank you," Harry said quietly. "I guess I'd better go now, and think about things. Will the password be valid for the rest of the day if I have further questions?"

"It will. Oh, but Harry –"

Harry had already stood up, and turned around. The old wizard looked pained.

"I hate to even contemplate this, but I must... If you do not survive the proceedings, who do you wish to name as your heir?"

Harry swallowed. But Dumbledore was right: he did need to think about it.

"Hermione, if she lives. Padma if not."

And with that, he donned the new invisibility cloak and left.

Hermione Granger sat silently on the stone bench in the near-darkness of her cell. There was no Patronus light to keep her company anymore.

But there were also no Dementors.

She had no idea what would happen next. Would they just leave her in this cell? Kill her? Get new Dementors? She knew she should be afraid, but instead, she just felt calm. Peaceful. She had made her decision and gone through with it, and that was all she could do. She had survived, which she had not expected, and which might not turn out to be a blessing. But whatever would happen, would happen, and she would meet it when it did.

And that left the question of today's mystery...

"Are you here to stay?" she asked in the darkness. The warm weight in her lap shifted comfortably. "Caw."

"Forever?"

"Caw!"

"Staying with me won't be a very exciting life for a phoenix, you know. I'll probably be in a cell like this for the rest of my life." She considered for a moment. "However long that may be."

"Caw."

"What's your name?"

"Caw?"

"Oh, I should make one up? Are you a boy phoenix or a girl phoenix?"

"Caw?"

Of course, she thought. Phoenix are undying. Perhaps they are also unborn. And if they have no beginning or end, there would be no reason to reproduce, so why would the species have gender?

"I think I'll think of you as girl," she decided. The English language just didn't have convenient gender-neutral pronouns. "And I'll call you... Xare."

The story of Harry Potter's statement had run over the school with the rapidity of fiendfyre, so it was no surprise to Minerva when Flitwick's Patronus informed her that three Aurors had entered the grounds.

When she came into the Entrance Hall, three crimson-robed figures came in through the door. Students were peeking in from the Great Hall, and from other corridors.

And there, suddenly, was Harry Potter, pulling an Invisibility Cloak off himself as though he had been waiting for them there. The foremost Auror did not hesitate, but approached him immediately.

"Harry Potter," she said. "You are under arrest on charges of aiding and abetting: jailbreak, destruction of national weapons, and treason. You will be taken into custody to be interrogated under three drops of Veritaserum."

The boy stood quietly, as he was patted down and his wand, pouch and cloak taken from him. And then the four of them left, the Aurors' wands all trained on Harry, as though he were a dangerous criminal about to pull some amazing wandless magic, rather than an eleven-year old child.

Minerva gritted her teeth. She had known that it was coming, but it still hurt.

The situation was highly serious, she knew. Prisonbreak. Treason. Even if both children had obviously only done the right thing, the simple fact was that they had broken the law, and that these laws came with very high punishments. Even just breaking into Azkaban, which Harry had confessed doing, would normally land him a four-month sentence. And Hermione's act had freed the minds of hundreds of severe criminals, many of them Death Eaters, in a prison that could not easily be defended without its Dementors. As heroic and inspiring as it had been, the simple fact that half of Voldemort's closest servants might have been enabled to escape would weigh heavily on the Wizengamot's minds. Add to that Hermione's vilification as an attempted-murderess...

Perhaps that part of the problem was fixable, at least. Harry had told her that Draco wouldn't talk to him, but...

She summoned her Patronus. "Go to Severus Snape," she asked. "And tell him: please ask Draco to come see me after dinner."

It was immediately clear that something unusual had happened, when Lesath Lestrange sneaked into the Great Hall in the quiet, unobtrusive way he had learned to use years ago. People were running from table to table. Despite the low number of students – most were still home for the holidays – there was an excited babble all around. A few children had tear-streaked faces, but they looked more happy than upset. Only the teachers at the Head Table had serious looks, wearing frowns as they bent over to talk to each other.

Lesath scanned the Slytherin table, and found the person he was looking for. He sat down next to Silvia Dorskey, a sixth-year prefect who hadn't exactly been friendly but at least was always civil to him.

"What's going on?" He whispered to her.

She looked surprised. "I would have expected you to know by now."

"Why? What happened?" he pressed.

"Potter was arrested an hour ago. We all saw it! They accused him of conspiracy for jailbreak and treason and something else, I forget. And people were already saying that he had broken into Azkaban, given Granger a wand, and that she used that to kill all Dementors there. And then of course some people panicked, but the children with Auror-relatives are saying that nobody escaped, just that all Dementors are gone." She looked thoughtful. "That's all I know from reliable sources, anyway. Would you like to hear some of the wilder rumors? Hey, you've gone all white."

"Yes, I... I..." he stammered. "Thank you!" He scrabbled back from the bench and fled to the bathrooms right off the Great Hall, feeling his wand shaking in his hand almost beyond his control.

The darkness can be broken.

That's what Potter had said, and Lesath had thought that he believed it, but he hadn't really. But now he saw that his Lord was right.

The darkness can be broken.

The Granger girl, one of his master's other servants – or maybe friends – had done what he himself had failed to do. She had freed father from the Dementors' grip, and even if that wasn't quite like real freedom, it was enough. Potter had been arrested for it. Was this what his master had had in mind, when he had given Lesath the task of passing on the True Patronus Charm?

He looked down at the wand in his hand. It shook, as he trembled a little, but the tip was gleaming, ever so faintly, with a silver light.

Dementors could be destroyed. Mother and father both lived, and didn't have to suffer anymore. Master Potter had painted a vision of a beautiful world, and he was on track to make it come true. The first step had been made. It might or might not be up to Lesath to do the rest. But if Dementors could be destroyed, anything was possible.

The darkness really can be broken!

"Expecto Patronum!"

The light burst out of him, turning the bathroom to silver and then white as it grew, impossibly bright, brighter even than Potter's Patronus had been. He could imagine feeling the Dementors, those pits of horror and misery, at the edges of his spell and then fading away as the Patronus tore them apart.

Stop! He told himself. Stop, or people will see it! You must not betray Lord Potter by showing that you can do this!

The light softened then, and further, until he could make out the shape of a human, looking a lot like a young boy. And then, with a movement of his wand, the Patronus disappeared. But he would recast it later, where no one could see him. And if his Lord were not to return, then he would teach others, as he was commanded, and after that he would make sure that no Dementor would remain on the face of the earth.

He stumbled over to one of the sinks, far weaker than he had felt before. That spell had taken a lot out of him, but it was worth it. He washed his face, which was streaked with tears, and quietly pocketed his wand, as though nothing had happened.

They came for him, then, the Gryffindors and also some from the other Houses. But he didn't care. His father had endured Azkaban for over ten years; he could handle ten minutes of pain. Besides, no matter what they did to him, it couldn't take away the bright Patronus fire that he now held close to his heart.

"You wanted to see me, Professor?" Draco kept his face carefully neutral. He had heard, of course, about the arrest, and he had a pretty good feeling what this would be about, but not what she wanted of him.

"Yes, I did. Would you please sit?"

He did so. The woman did look rather stressed, he thought. And there was a Pensieve on her desk. Curious.

"Mr. Malfoy, I shall come straight to the point. You have testified under Veritaserum that you tried to help Hermione Granger before. Would you be willing to do so again?"

Draco blinked. "You would have me help the witch who tried to kill me?"

"No!" she exclaimed. "No, of course not. But I know from my classes that you are intelligent, and from what others tell me, you are just. If Hermione Granger was not the person who tried to kill you, would you be willing to help her then?"

Draco felt his heart beating loudly. "Who else is responsible, do you think?"

A strange look crossed her face, but it disappeared before he could properly interpret it. "What I think on that subject is not important now. There is no proof either way. But what we can prove," and here she turned a hopeful gaze on him, "what I hope we can prove, is that it was not Hermione. I don't think the Aurors really considered all possibilities when investigating the case – they simply assumed guilt. So that is what I was hoping to convince you to do: consider the possibility that it was not her, and if we can prove it together, then speak up. Only if we can – you would not have to defend her without being convinced that she was never your enemy."

Draco considered this. "I certainly would prefer that the person who actually did it is punished rather than an innocent pawn." His voice gave nothing away as he added: "Did Dumbledore ask you to do this?"

"No." She shook her head. "Professor Dumbledore is currently at the International Confederation of Wizards. This is entirely my own doing."

She was probably telling the truth, he thought. And if this could help them find any evidence that it had really been Dumbledore...

"What would you have me do?"

She gestured to the Pensieve. "To start, would you be willing to share your complete memories of the duel?"

Chapter 99: Day of the Dementors

"Harry? You must wake up."

Harry groggily opened his eyes, and looked at the aged face of the Headmaster. It felt like he'd hardly gone to bed at all. "Wazza time?"

"Quarter past six in the morning. Get up, and get dressed. Hurry."

"Six?" Indignation rose, together with a slight headache. "Professor, I need at least four more hours of sleep." After the trial, the Aurors had returned his pouch, cloak and wand, but not his Time-Turner. Time-Turners were a privilege, not a right, and it would probably require some negotiation before they returned one to a boy who had confessed as blatant a disregard for the law as Harry had. So Harry, exhausted though he was after all the events of the day, hadn't managed to fall asleep until one in the morning.

"You do not have that luxury today. I already gave you as long as I could."

The words hardly penetrated his muddled consciousness, but there was something in the old wizard's tone... "What happened?"

"You will know soon. But tell me this, if you would: whom did you teach your Patronus spell to besides Miss Granger? Was there more than one other? Many lives may depend on this."

The sleep fell off him and was replaced by terror. What is going on? He registered, now, that the old wizard was looking extremely serious this morning.

"Padma Patil and Lesath Lestrange," he whispered. He couldn't think of what else to say.

"Lestrange?" The Headmaster looked briefly surprised, but almost immediately regained his composure. "That's good news. I shall wake the others now, and then come back to bring you to my office."

The ancient wizard waited until Harry had pushed away the blankets and started to move – probably to see that he wasn't going to fall asleep again – and then disappeared in a burst of flame.

Five minutes later, the four of them stood together in the Headmaster's Office. Sleepy, worried faces gazed around. Lesath looked very out of place. At least the headache was gone, after Xare had chirped a few notes of phoenix song.

With a wave of the Headmaster's wand, two large sofas appeared. "Sit," he suggested.

"In a bit over an hour time," he spoke gravely, once they had obeyed, "the man you know as Professor Quirrell will strike again." He glanced at Lesath as he said this, perhaps wondering how the boy would react if he knew that Professor Quirrell was the same man whom his parents had sworn their lives to. "Almost every single person on earth will hear an announcement in their own language, revealing the true nature of Dementors."

Hermione gasped. She had been there, so she understood. Harry felt his heart sinking deeply. How many Dementors exist in the world?

"Wait, how do you know that?" Padma asked. The Headmaster nodded to her.

"This," he said, taking a Time-Turner from his pocket and showing them all, "is a Time-Turner. Every turn allows you to go back in time one hour, but there are limitations. No person, object or even information can go back further than six hours, no matter how many Time-Turners are used. A single Time-Turner cannot be used more than six times in any twenty-four hour period, and a single person cannot go back more than six times in such a period. And most importantly, you cannot change the past. Doing anything that would cause a contradiction will have great and terrible consequences. Time has Laws, even if we do not fully comprehend how they work."

"I don't understand," Lesath said. "Why are you telling us this? What's the problem?"

"If you know the truth about Dementors, you cannot cast the normal Patronus Charm anymore, even if you could do it before," Harry explained.

"Ah," he said, eyes widening. "Gotcha."

"So I guess..." Padma said. "You want us to cast our Patronuses?"

"Indeed. With ordinary wizards no longer able to protect themselves and others from their power, Dementors are without a doubt the most dangerous and uncontainable creatures in existence. They need to be destroyed as quickly as possible."

"Why are you only telling us this now?" Hermione demanded. "If you have time travel... we could have been destroying Dementors five hours ago!"

The old wizard sighed wearily. "You could not. As I said, time has Laws, and it seems that our former Defense Professor has taken some precautions to back us into a corner. Madam Bones, when she heard the message, instantly resolved to warn you and Mr. Potter before it happened, but she found that it would create a contradiction. She couldn't go back further than four hours at all, which suggests that Quirrell has acquired a Time-Turner of his own somehow, or at least gathered information from the future before sending his message. It took her almost fifteen minutes to formulate a plan that allowed her to go back in time at all, as most of the preparations she considered were blocked. She could shield her Aurors from hearing the message, but another note from the future has already informed us that those protections will fail. The main thing she could do was to rally a number of people, who have been working through the night to prepare for the moments after the message is given. Hopefully, our precautions will make the inevitable less of a disaster, though disaster it will certainly be."

Hermione swallowed. "People are going to die, aren't they?"

The Headmaster bowed his head. "Thousands, if we are very lucky. Billions, if we are not."

"Billions?" Hermione gasped, sounding horrified.

"No way," Harry said flatly. "Quirrell would never orchestrate an extinction event. There is no conceivable benefit to him."

The old wizard raised an eyebrow. "Are you quite sure of that?"

"Well... no."

The Headmaster nodded. "We don't know what he wants, so we cannot count on anything. I suspects he went into it with future knowledge, knowing that whatever goal he aims to achieve will be furthered, or at least not harmed, by today's events. But that will most likely not prevent massive casualties. Children, I must ask... Will you help? I do not pretend it will be easy – in fact, despite our precautions this will almost certainly put your lives in danger – but can I ask you to fight today for the sake of the world?

"Of course," Hermione promptly answered. Harry also nodded, although a sick knot of fear twisted in his stomach. How many Dementors are there on earth? Would four of them be enough? Just the Dementors around Azkaban had nearly killed Hermione, and that was with a phoenix to help her.

"Of course I'll do what I can..." Padma was saying with a tremble in her voice. "But I've only done the spell when there weren't any Dementors around, I don't know whether I can..."

"You can," Harry assured her. He radiated confidence for her sake, even if he did not feel it.

Lesath shifted awkwardly and glanced at Harry.

Oh, right. He thinks I'm his Lord.

"It's your choice, Lesath," he said gently. The others might draw strange conclusions from this particular exchange, but that could be dealt with later. Like, after they had stopped half the world civilization from getting killed.

Are you mad? His Slytherin side hissed at him. Why should you leave him the choice? His freedom and even life are not worth the death of, say, a million strangers. And if it's going to be hard with four people, it's going to be pretty damn near impossible to do this with three.

This might well kill all of us, Gryffindor pointed out. The choice to sacrifice his life should be his own.

Just as long as you're prepared to override his decision after all if he refuses, Slytherin said coldly.

"I want to destroy Dementors," Lesath said, with an urgency to his voice. "But I also want... Could I ask... Can I visit my father, after this?"

The old wizard look down on him with a gaze of sympathy.

"He will not recognize you," he pointed out quietly. "But if you want it regardless, I am sure that it can be arranged. In fact, Azkaban will have to be redesigned anyway."

"About that –" Harry began, but Dumbledore shot him a quick, sharp look.

"You cannot make demands for doing what I know perfectly well you will do anyway. Besides, we cannot gather the Wizengamot in the next hour to settle on any kind of binding deal. So shall we have this discussion later?"

"All right, just don't think I'll forget about that. But on behalf of Lesath... Could I ask that his mother's life is spared, should she be caught? I'm not asking that she goes free, I know that she's a bit too dangerous to just let go. But unless she desires otherwise, she should be left alive, free from mental or physical torture, and her son allowed to visit."

Lesath perked up. The old wizard frowned. "That is a rather large request, Mr. Potter. I sympathize with your viewpoint, but I am not sure that Amelia is going to agree to that."

"You are asking Lesath to risk his life," Harry patiently pointed out. "He is going to save thousands of people today, isn't he? The least you can do is grant him this one life in exchange. Besides, Bellatrix might not in fact have been given much choice about leaving her cell, so punishing her for the escape would be unfair."

The old wizard gave him a long, hard look, then glanced at Lesath, who was looking very hopeful all of a sudden. Finally, he nodded slowly.

"I can make no promises. But if that is indeed your wish, Lesath, I shall see what I can do. Now, can we move on to the day's planning?"

Amelia Bones, apparently, had got some of her Aurors to send Patronuses to known phoenix owners and inform them of the impending disaster. Of course they had all been willing to help (those who understood the message, anyway – she had had little luck communicating with the Swahili witch), and several had immediately come over to the DLME. Those, she had quietly told about the nature of Dementors and Hermione's now-unlocked explanation of how to cast the True Patronus Charm, but none had been able to do it. She had also worked on getting the cooperation of several major governments, and Aurors and Healers in all countries had been prepared for duty, although they had not been told what for.

There were pockets of Dementors in most countries in the world. In some places, like France, they were contained by constant Patronuses and never given any victims to drain of life. Likely, these Dementors would be very, very aggressive when their guardians were no longer able to contain them. In some places, like Azkaban, they were controlled but used. Some governments or organizations employed them as weapons against each other; in other places they were deliberately given an area of land with Muggles to use as they wished, with neither Dementors nor humans allowed to leave. These Dementors were the only ones who regularly got to use the Kiss, but they might still turn on their guardians given the opportunity. In yet other places, they were allowed to dwell in dark, filthy places, but kept under control with promises not to interfere with their feeding on passersby, provided they did not use the Kiss. There were also loose Dementors, not under anyone's control, in more abandoned areas.

They had ten minutes, at most, to deal with the most urgent threats. Maybe half an hour more, if they were lucky, before some of the Dementors kept at bay with promises would realize the change in their situation. It was entirely possible that Quirrell had also put motions into place to inform the Dementors, in which case they wouldn't even have that. For many of the smaller pockets of Dementors, their exact location was unknown; those were most likely to be found by following the trail of their victims.

In discussion with Albus Dumbledore, Amelia had made a complete plan of action. Each of the True Patronus casters would be matched with a phoenix owner (except Hermione, who would just be matched with a powerful wizard), and given a Time-Turner whose chain was large enough to transport two people. The phoenix would keep them alive while vanquishing Dementors; the owner could knock them out if they seemed to lose control. Seven special rooms had been arranged in the DMLE where they could come back after each assignment; at the end of an hour, they could go to the next room and loop back in time. If other True Patronus casters could be found, they would go back in time to the second or later rooms and join the four. The door to each room would indicate how many Patronus casters were in there, and Amelia Bones would coordinate all warnings that came in. She would give assignments to whoever was chronologically first, passing them as notes without knowing who the assignment was going to. By keeping the plan unchangeable and limiting information flow to the strictly necessary, the risks of messing with time were contained, at least, even if they were still significant.

"We have twenty-four of you for one hour," Dumbledore reminded them all. "Assuming you survive, and nothing goes wrong. Unfortunately, we cannot count on either, and we must avoid risking a contradiction that would block you from going back in time at all. We are already violating the standard procedures for dealing with time significantly: you will be interacting with your future selves by following your assignments, since if your future self had not handled the more urgent assignments, you would be receiving those instead. Avoid any further interaction with yourself. If you are wounded or otherwise in trouble, you must go to one of the assigned rooms in St. Mungo's, the Great Hall of Hogwarts, or whichever place makes sense to you as long as no younger version of you has been to the same place. If you find that going back to the second room would cause a contradiction, go to the third, and so on. If you cannot go back at all, go to the seventh room, where Amelia will give you instructions to deal with the remaining Dementors. Your assigned helper will take charge, but you must be prepared to help yourself – and them – if things go wrong. If your phoenix owner dies or becomes incapacitated, or if your phoenix needs to be reborn, send for help from me or anyone at Hogwarts; we will come for you, and you will be assigned a new assistant."

"You're not coming?" Padma asked, looking meaningfully at Fawkes. The old wizard shook his head.

"I cannot. I have gone back in time the full six hours yesterday, and no twenty-four hours have passed since. I shall do what I can from here, for whichever situations might arise. Do you have any further questions?"

They shook their heads.

The Headmaster waved his hand, and a table filled with all the best breakfast foods appeared. The House Elves, apparently, had been in on the preparations.

"Then, eat. Your day shall be wearying; you will need all your strength."

It was Monday, April 20th 1992, 07:29am.

Professor McGonagall was overlooking the four House tables at breakfast. Children chattered, ate, and showed each other holiday pictures. Newspapers with the (heavily censored) story of yesterday's trial were passed around. The atmosphere was relaxed. Even most of the staff had no idea of what was about to happen.

She waited, tensely, as the seconds ticked by. These children were her responsibility now; Albus would be busy in the Ministry. He had urged her to do whatever she could to maintain the peace and stop panic from breaking out.

Even expecting it as she was, the voice still managed to take her by surprise. Dry, humorless, and with crystal clarity, the words formed in her head.

DEMENTORS ARE A PHYSICAL EMBODIMENT OF DEATH. YOU CANNOT FIGHT THEM ANYMORE. YOU CANNOT RUN. TODAY, THEY WILL ATTACK. PREPARE TO DIE.

Cutlery, cups and photographs fell clattering to the table or the floor. Students gasped. Some were jumping up, others sat rooted to the benches. Even she was trembling. Albus hadn't quite given the details of what the message would entail, but of course the less you knew about the future the better.

At the Gryffindor table, Dean Thomas shouted "Expecto Patronum." He had been among the few first-year students who had managed to produce a corporeal Patronus before, both with and without a Dementor present. But no light sprang forward this time. He stared at his wand in horror, even as all eyes in the Great Hall had turned to look at him.

And then it really started to sink in. There was shouting. People jumped up from their places. Some students even started screaming. Others tried to cast the Patronus Charm, but failed. Some of the Muggleborns fell on their knees and started to pray.

With three loud blasts of her wand, some semblance of order was restored.

"Stay calm, everyone," she ordered crisply, appearing perfectly calm. (She was good at that, and the students needed it now.) "You are in no immediate danger. Remember, there are no Dementors in the British Isles anymore. Miss Granger took care of that." She couldn't say that sensible people were already working on the situation, because there was no way that she could know that without Time-Turners, but... "And I am certain that Dementors in other countries cannot just get to people and attack everyone immediately. They take time to move too, and most are kept away from busy areas. This should give the government plenty of time to do something about it."

"What does it mean?" second-year Marietta yelled. "What was that voice?"

"It seems," she answered, her voice raised over the cries that were starting up again, "that our Defense Professor has some dark motive involving Dementors. He pulled a similar stunt yesterday, but Mr. Potter dealt with the situation." She let that hang in the air for a moment.

Heads swiveled towards the Ravenclaw table. "Where is he?"

"Mr. Potter and Miss Granger have been summoned to a meeting with Madam Bones, to discuss some of yesterday's events before class." It was the story Albus had told her to use, should anyone ask where the two famous children were. "Given Madam Bones's reputation for efficiency, I suspect both of them have already been recruited into a DMLE team dealing with the situation. But do please recall that Miss Granger has a phoenix, and in the extremely unlikely event that a Dementor should come here, she could be on the spot within seconds."

It helped, she guessed, but there was still a lot of muttering and fidgeting, still worried looks everywhere. The children didn't seem very comfortable with these reassurances. And they shouldn't be – even if they were not in any real danger, their families were, especially those with relatives abroad, or in the DMLE. In the wider world, disaster was happening.

What they needed, besides promises of protection, was something to do. Something they could do to make it better. Something to not feel completely helpless.

"In fact," she stated clearly, and waited for the worst of the noises to die down again. "There are many omitted details in the news coverage of yesterday's events. One of the things that hasn't been mentioned was Hermione Granger's explanation of how the spell to destroy Dementors is cast. It is harder than the normal Patronus Charm, but perhaps it is still worth trying to learn it." This, too, was her task today. Passing the children the True Patronus Charm was unlikely to help: even Padma had taken a week, Harry had said before Dumbledore took the children off to the Ministry, and he wasn't here now to guide them. The Ministry and Albus would be focusing their efforts on people like Nicolas Flamel, who had a demonstrated affinity for this kind of spell. But there were hundreds of young people in the school, and they would be fools indeed not to give the children a chance to learn. At the very least it would distract them from worrying.

She took a deep breath as the Hall fell completely silent to listen to her.

"The spell is called the True Patronus Charm..."

Chapter 101: Knowing the Enemy

Tuesday noon. Harry and Hermione were seated in twin chairs in the Headmaster's office.

"Why did you call us here, Professor?" Hermione asked.

"Because I need your advice on how to deal with the consequences of yesterday's events."

She still looked tired, Harry thought. "Why aren't Padma and Lesath here?"

"There is some hope that they might yet be saved from being heroes," Professor Dumbledore replied with a slight smile. "For you two, I'm afraid, it is entirely too late."

Hermione snorted sadly. Harry, however, fixed him with a cold glare. "Have you told all concerned parties that they are to stop murdering the remaining Dementor-victims?"

The old wizard nodded, no longer smiling. "I have passed on your request to leave them for Muggle doctors to examine, and most Ministries have agreed. As the majority of the remaining victims are now in the care of their relatives or hospitals, there is little to be won by forcing the issue regardless. Given the scale of the situation, covering up their state is as impossible as it is futile."

"How many..." Hermione began, trailing off as she didn't seem to dare finish the question.

"Worldwide, a little more than half a million people have died," the old wizard answered sadly. "And yet more are severely wounded. The brunt of the death toll did not come directly from Dementors, but rather was a result of the panic and chaos they caused. Even Britain was not spared, for, while there were no Dementors here, Voldemort has used the distraction to strike directly. It seems that in most cases, his damage was done with very little effort: emotional spells to cause panic, blasting curses, a few well-placed Confundus Charms... Although there have been some direct attacks with the Killing Curse as well."

"What?"

The Headmaster grimaced bitterly. "It appears that he did not want those living in our country to feel secure while their foreign peers were in danger, a motive in which he has succeeded quite thoroughly. Muggles in Britain were hit harder than those elsewhere in the world, at least in the total number of casualties and destroyed property. And yet, even now, the Ministry will not accept that Voldemort has returned. At least they have started taking my admonitions about our Defense Professor seriously. I suppose it doesn't signify much how they choose to name him, as long as they are equally on their guard."

Harry nodded. 'Quirrell' was easier than 'You-Know-Who' anyway.

"Meanwhile," the Headmaster continued. "The representatives of major Muggle governments who were aware of the existence of magic – that is, most of them – have stepped forward and told the world what they know. There is video footage of Dementor attacks and wizards casting spells. This is far beyond what Memory Charms can clean up. The International Statute of Secrecy is at an end."

"Good," Harry bit. "Getting rid of that was long overdue, and now maybe we can help the thousands of wounded of yesterday's disaster."

The old wizard just looked at him sadly.

"You are young in the ways of the world, Harry. Do you really believe that life would be better for Muggles if they knew of us?"

"Do you know how many people die of cancer each year?" Harry threw back.

The old wizard sighed. "Too many. Too many to be conscionable, yet also too many for us to help. Do you realize how large the Muggle world is compared to ours? And how many things they would ask of us? Most forms of cancer can be cured by magic, but the operation is far from trivial, and the handful of qualified Healers we could spare would suffice only to serve a fraction of those in need, even assuming their services are not required for other diseases at all."

"It's still better to cure some people than none!"

The old wizard shook his head. "In the short term, perhaps, but you fail to consider the next generation. Magical healing will naturally gravitate towards the richest part of the population. With a magical cure available to those who can pay for it, far less effort will be expended into finding non-magical treatments. In the long run, new development stalls, and almost everyone is worse off than they could have been without our help. Do you think the vaccines whose praise your father sang yesterday could ever have been invented while witches and wizards were still providing healing for the royalty and nobility?"

"So you're saying," Harry summarized angrily, "that you want to let people die when they can easily be saved, just to give the big pharmaceutical corporations a greater incentive to keep developing medicines?

Actually, he has a point, Slytherin pointed out. Those corporations invest in medical research because they expect a huge pay-off in the end. Whittling away on that might cause all kinds of issues. Can we get an economist in here?

"That sounds so harsh," Hermione said quietly.

"It is harsh," the old wizard agreed. "But this is the lesson history has taught us over and over. You might not have covered it in History of Magic yet, but the International Statute of Secrecy was actually preceded by many smaller, local pacts, in times when Muggles did not travel much. Thus, we have seen the same pattern many times over. Within a hundred years of the secrecy pact – when all those who have seen magic with their own eyes have either gone to their graves or been sworn to secrecy – Muggle society flourishes. With the loss of faith in the supernatural, Muggles start attempting to control the world they live in, the grasp of religion weakens, and equality between the social classes rises. The rich remain privileged, of course, but without wizards backing their claims on lands and people, they are no longer seen as inherently better than the poor. Of course some places have grown faster than others, and even now, there are still many countries left behind, but I also understand that Muggle politicians and organizations are working on that. In two centuries, perhaps, all humans might come to live a reasonable life. Or so it would have been, but for yesterday's events."

He sighed again, piercing Harry with his eyes. "Now do you see what we risk losing? What it might do, to the fabric of society, if the magical and non-magical worlds are to merge again? Because the same is known to happen in reverse. There are other tales, although fewer and older, of wizards joining a Muggle community, and invariably poverty grows over the next generations."

"That has to be avoidable," Harry argued. "We have science now, and science doesn't just turn off when you know about magic. I'm sure if we plan this and organize properly, we can avoid wrecking the Muggle world and maybe also drag the wizarding world into the twentieth century."

The Headmaster shrugged helplessly. "I'm not sure how much opportunity we will have to do that, with tensions being as they are. With the casualties we saw yesterday... It will take all our efforts to avoid descending into war. Especially here in Britain, where the people's feelings have been primed by the magical attacks last week, and where no saving grace exists in Muggle perceptions. Abroad, their opinions are mixed. There is understandable anger; Professor Snape has told me that the television shows many videos of the Dementor-attacks themselves, of the aftermaths, and, unfortunately, also of wizards killing the Dementor-victims, which the Muggles naturally do not perceive as the act of kindness it was intended to be. But even as many Muggles are giving in to fear mongering and yelling for retribution, there is also coverage of wizards doing emergency healing, and of you children casting your Patronuses. There are interviews with some of those who experienced the feeling first hand, and they mostly express the belief that you were helping them. Here in Britain, however, we do not have that counter. As all our efforts were focused abroad, the news here is almost exclusively repeating the few images of a witch or wizard doing destructive magic, along with images of the aftermath of Voldemort's attacks: the body counts, fallen buildings and heavily wounded eyewitnesses. Add to that last week's row between the prime minister and the Minister of Magic over the way we dealt with those first two attacks..."

Harry frowned. "How did we deal with those attacks?"

The old wizard looked pained. "After the Inferi attack, an enormous fire was staged to destroy what evidence there was. Most of Easingwold was burned to the ground, officially by a pyromaniac who contracted the 'virus' and went crazy. All corpses were burnt, of course, regardless of the preferences of the families. The Muggle government sent help in the rebuilding when we left, but the damage is vast, and Cornelius has been unwilling to contribute to the rebuilding, saying we have done enough. Nor could he do much to help with the backlash against the Muggle government for the rather implausible story – certainly the prime minister was not pleased with the inevitable political fallout for being forced to speak such transparent lies. In the school, over my protests, the Obliviators staged a gas leak where all the children and teachers died. I barely managed to keep them from being killed; as it is, the children and teachers in question are being kept apart under Ministry custody for the moment, and are planned to be Memory-Charmed and, in the children's case, given up for adoption in the coming years. We can return them to their parents now, but I fear irrevocable damage to our reputation has been done."

"Yes," Harry said, his eyes hard. Just what kind of unspeakable, evil morons are running our government? "So there is no time to lose. You must step forward, apologize, return those children, offer what help we can with the wounded people and damaged property, and explain just what the hell is going on. And you'd better do it now!"

"I cannot speak for all of magical Britain," the old wizard sighed. "Much less the entire world, and I would be breaking several international treaties by providing an explanation."

"Ask for forgiveness, not permission," Harry suggested.

"If I do that," the Headmaster said gravely, "my political opponents will perceive it as me making a grab for more power by setting myself up as the spokesman for our world, without even their consent. They will never stand for it, and will deliberately go against what I say. As such, it would be worse than useless: it would be destructive. And thus we bicker rather than stepping forward as I agree we absolutely must. I suppose this is one point where Voldemort was right, little though I like saying it. We suffer from not being united."

"And that is what he wanted us to conclude," Harry nodded. "He wants Britain to be united under a strong leader, and he wants me to be that leader. That's at least a part of why he did it. It's not like I hadn't seen something like this coming."

Hermione, who had been staring open-mouthedly at the two of them, spluttered at this. "Seen this coming? What?"

"You didn't tell her?" Harry asked.

The Headmaster shook his head. "Not that part."

"What part?"

Harry turned to Hermione. "You know he's been mentoring me. I'm pretty sure, from all he said and did, that he wants me to lead the country. He tried to convince me to set up this scenario where You-Know-Who returns and I defeat him, which would make me a great hero in the eyes of the magical world. Don't look at me like that, I told him I didn't want to do it. So that's why he got you sent to Azkaban, to force me to play along so I would be able to manipulate Lucius Malfoy. I still refused, so I've been expecting him to set up another scenario where I couldn't refuse to be the hero. And that seems to be pretty much what happened yesterday."

She frowned, thinking about it. "But then why would he attack in person? He could have known that you were too busy saving people on the other side of the world."

"Why indeed," asked Dumbledore, raising his eyebrows.

"I don't know," Harry confessed. "I wondered at first whether he was just setting himself up as terrifying, but then it doesn't make sense that he's mostly attacking Muggle settlements, which most people in the magical world aren't even going to care about. And yesterday, too, the casualties were almost entirely among Muggles."

"I don't think he ever liked Muggles much," Hermione said timidly.

"No," Harry agreed. "He fears them. He told me about the atomic bomb and how scientists came close to destroying the world. And then there was his Christmas... speech..." He fell silent, as he suddenly understood what Riddle was planning.

"But if he fears them, then why is he antagonizing them?" Dumbledore wondered.

"He wants war," Harry breathed. "He thinks we can win."

The pieces of the puzzle fell into place with crystal clarity. "He's terrified of what Muggles might do, intentional or not. With nuclear weapons, there's too much power in the hands of a few people, people who have never proved themselves responsible. If another world war breaks out, wizards will be annihilated along with everyone else."

"This does not explain why he would push for war," the old wizard pointed out.

"He's pushing for war in one country. The Muggle world is not united in itself, it never has been, and as you just said, all the worst aggravation has been here. There's no way a 'war of extermination' initiated by the British government, or even the European Union, would actually work: we could hide out, or flee to other countries. What's more, they couldn't really use their worst weapons against us, because magical people tend to live among Muggles – for example, the Ministry of Magic is located in London, they're not exactly going to throw a bomb on it. No, that's never what he was afraid of. What he fears is far more realistic: Muggle countries fighting each other. Several nations have been on the brink of war for decades. The cold war has pretty much ended, but all those weapons are still out there, it might be as simple as one crazy person getting elected into the wrong position to start it all off again!"

The others were staring at him, but he ignored it, and went on thinking aloud. "He's been planning this for over twenty years. Set up an evil dark lord, create a hero to fight him, have everyone swear loyalty to this hero, cause the Muggles to declare war, and then use the hero to win that war. It would really be the war to end all wars, because it would end with an eternal magical dictatorship – perhaps even a benevolent dictatorship, Muggles wouldn't need to be oppressed very much to stop them from destroying the earth; you'd just want to destroy all weapons of mass destruction and keep some oversight over military activities and potentially destructive research. Monroe was meant to be the leader whose 'light mark' everyone would take. But it didn't work out, he wasn't enough of a storybook hero, so people preferred to stand back over actively following him. And he couldn't make the Dark Lord worse, because if Monroe was seen to be the weaker party even briefly, he would lose favor in the eyes of the world. So he retired Monroe, and made the Dark Lord the most terrible dark wizard to have ever lived. He didn't make him win, but barely, so that when he set up a new hero who defeated this dark lord without any help, it would seem to everyone like a great miracle."

"You?" Hermione whispered.

"Me," Harry nodded. "I don't know whether there actually was a prophecy that he conveniently used, or whether he set that up too – he might have figured out how to manipulate the Department of Mysteries, or otherwise he deliberately had me 'defeat' him, leaving only a remnant of himself behind. But either way, he created a new hero, one who would defeat the greatest dark wizard who ever lived at one years old, who would become an icon before he ever did anything of his own, and who would then go on to do even greater things. Such a hero could gain the loyalty of Gryffindor and Slytherin alike, and might be able to unite the country if Muggles should become a real threat. He intended to be able to manipulate me, perhaps through possessing me as you hinted, Professor, or otherwise more directly, as he has done by teaching me. It is no coincidence that he came to Hogwarts this year."

"This all sounds really dark and scary," Hermione piped up, after the silence had stretched a bit, "but this is Professor Quirrell we're talking about, right? He knows that you were raised by Muggles. He probably knew that your mother was Muggleborn, too, and there was always a pretty high chance that her family would be the ones to adopt you. Why would he think you'd be willing to fight a war against Muggles?"

That was a good point, but Harry immediately realized the answer. He looked at Professor Dumbledore. "You told me once that it was your fault that I had abusive parents. Did you actually plan for that to be the case?"

The Headmaster shifted uncomfortably. "I knew already that you had a loving family at the time, or I would not have brought it up. But when I sent you to live with your aunt, I did not know for certain what the outcome would be. I hadn't seen Petunia in many years, and Lily rarely spoke of her sister. The simple truth was that I feared for your life and your future. The remaining Death Eaters might well seek revenge on you for the fall of their leader. What is more, powerful, wealthy pureblood families were already filing for your adoption, either to use your fame for their own ends, or for yet darker purposes. The claim of a direct family member, even a Muggle, would supersede theirs, especially because it would offer the possibility for blood wards, which provide the best possible protection from harm. As Lord Voldemort had killed most of those family members in the months leading up to your parents' death, that left me with only one option."

Ah. So that's why Mum's parents are dead, too.

"So you assigned me to a sister who you knew to have always been unhappy, and who had been envious and hateful of Lily during her school years," he summarized flatly. "A sister who had every reason to hate magic because it had alienated her sister from her, and had been the cause of her parents' death very recently. You thought she would mistreat me."

The old wizard looked grave. "I would not have allowed you to come to harm, for certain – the wards would stop any significant physical damage, and an old friend of mine, Mrs. Figg, agreed to move into the neighborhood to keep an additional eye on your well-being and your development. I confess that I considered it entirely possible that she would not love you, at least not from the start. I had planned to bribe or force her to take you, should it be necessary, but she did not at all protest at the request. I am really glad for how it turned out, Harry."

And Professor Snape said that he never knew that Lily had made peace with her sister. If he was Voldemort's main source about the Potters, then Voldemort would not have known either.

"Would you really have forced her?" Harry asked. It probably wasn't important, in the large scheme of things, but he couldn't just let this go. "I mean, that would not only be wildly immoral towards her, but would also have put me in a not exactly nurturing environment. Don't you have any idea what neglect and resentment in guardians can do to a child, even if they never physically hurt him?"

The Headmaster shook his head. "You might have had a rough childhood, but it would have been preferable over being given to the Jugsons, Notts, or even the Crouch or Fudge families. I could never have adopted you myself, being old and unmarried, and the Ministry does give preference to the older families in such matters."

"I guess I can sort of see why you'd do that," Harry acknowledged. He would probably have been more upset if Mum and Dad had not, in actual fact, been wonderful parents. As it was, he could imagine why Dumbledore would have preferred him being neglected over being raised like Draco, or having a convenient childhood 'accident'. "But let's look at this from the point of view of an outsider, who didn't know Mum, only the relationship she and Lily used to have. She had every reason in the world to hate and fear magic. If that hadn't been resolved, being forced to take a young wizard in the house would have been very stressful for her, and it would be entirely reasonable if she couldn't bring herself to care for, or even bare to look at me. And for what you just said, You-Know-Who killed every near relative except for Mum. That has to have been deliberate. He knew that, given the choice between having me adopted by blood purists or mistreated, you'd choose the latter."

Dumbledore's eyes widened as Harry spoke, his face showing shock.

"Which tells us something about his original plan," Harry concluded. "I was meant to come to hate Muggles, and more. Even if nothing truly bad happened, he expected that I would be neglected, mistrusted, never been cared for, nor had any role models to show me normal human relations. I haven't really studied developmental psychology very well, but I'm pretty sure that that could have messed me up in all kinds of ways. Hating Muggles is just the first, I might have ended up hating other people altogether. Or being so morally and emotionally deprived that I ended up... well, like him, I guess, never caring for anyone at all."

The Headmaster trembled a little. "Oh Merlin, what have I done? I didn't see, I didn't realize –"

Hermione shot Harry a look and carefully touched the old, gnarled hand.

"I didn't end up like that, though," Harry continued, following her cue to reassure the old man, although he wasn't entirely sure whether it was deserved. Something Quirrell had said came back to him. Heroes and villains are just different sides of the same coin. Growing up neglected and isolated was the best environment to nurture a hero, but it would also create severely broken people, maybe even psychopaths. Dumbledore might have understood the former, but he had missed the latter. "This was just what You-Know-Who expected, but in the end, everything actually turned out in the best possible way. I have wonderful parents, who willingly chose they have me, and they taught me plenty of empathy and respect for what Muggles have achieved. So, while in the future I think you really should discuss this sort of decision with someone like Professor McGonagall, there was no harm done."

The old man shook his head, looking pained. Finally, he recovered some of his composure.

"This time, perhaps, all turned out for the best, but there was another time, another child. I did not send him there, but I failed to recognize the signs..." He took a deep breath. "More than fifty years ago, I went to bring young Tom Riddle his Hogwarts acceptance letter. He lived in a Muggle orphanage. From what little I could gather at the time, it was a harsh place to grow up – not abusive, but quite devoid of love. There were simply too few staff members to bond with the children. He was also isolated from the other children, since they considered him, in their words, a 'freak'. He, I thought, deemed himself to be above them, but perhaps that was merely a response to their treatment of him." He sighed deeply. "It never occurred to me that he might simply never have learned to care for people. If it had, perhaps I would have acted differently. It might not have been too late, then, to find help for him. But instead, I merely kept his secrets, and never revealed to anyone what I learned of his home environment."

"Tom Riddle?" Harry asked, suspicion starting to dawn.

"Tom Marvolo Riddle," Dumbledore nodded. "He who would later become Lord Voldemort."

Hermione looked startled. "That name wasn't in any of the books!"

"It is not common knowledge," the old wizard replied. "Voldemort would not want it generally known that he is a half-blood – witch mother, Muggle father – a fact which, I believe, may be part of the reason why he distanced himself from his given name. I suspected the connection when I learned that Voldemort was a Parselmouth, a very rare talent which Tom had let slip he possessed the first time we met, before he knew just how rare it was. I managed to confirm the connection when Tom Riddle returned to Hogwarts to ask me for a teaching position, using a combination of blood magic and the Hogwarts wards. I did not dare reveal his identity in public, however,, as I did not have enough proof to convince any but those who would believe my word. It might damage Voldemort if I did so, but only a little; it certainly would strengthen the cultural prejudice against half-bloods and by extension Muggleborns."

Harry considered this. "Okay, I'll assume it accurate for now." Well. Plausible at least. "I'm not sure how important this could be, but I would like a full briefing on everything you know about this Tom Riddle at some point in the near future. For what you tell me, it certainly sounds like he intended for me to grow up exactly like he did, though. He must have noticed that this part of the plan hadn't worked out when he got to know me, but he works with what he has. So he's been training me, and playing on my affections to push me in the desired direction instead. Perhaps the original plan was to turn me into a small version of himself, backed by all sides of the political spectrum, leading the wizarding world through the war and then setting up a magical dictatorship because I would consider it the most sensible solution. With that not working out, the idea might be that I will have to win the war quickly in order to minimize casualties."

"This sounds like a very risky plot," Dumbledore said with a frown. "There are many assumptions, many things which could go wrong. I would not expect the Ministry to lightly give you power, for instance. You are only eleven, after all."

"I don't pretend to have the full picture here," Harry argued. "Just the rough outline. He probably has plans for all kinds of eventualities, and he'll be working in the background to steer the war into the direction he wants. Perhaps the plot spans several years, and he's trained the Hogwarts children in Battle Magic to prepare for some final battle once the magical government gets desperate enough to pass military command to me. Or he's setting magical Britain up to lose, which will set the tone for a future war in other countries. That future war will probably happen anyway, come to think of it, even if we win here. Basically, I don't know exactly what he's doing, not the details. I really have to go and think about this properly for a few hours to see whether I can figure it out. I'm just fairly sure that it involves starting a war and having me win it one way or another, and that the end point is meant to be a global magical dictatorship, where Muggle scientists are no longer a threat – quite possibly because there is a lasting peace that means there won't be a need for further wars."

"The endpoint, at least, sounds remarkably familiar," the old wizard said with a weak smile. "If what you say is true, then he is not so different from Grindelwald after all, or from those dark lords seeking to subjugate Muggles before him."

"Except that he does not necessarily seek to rule himself," Harry pointed out. "And his motivation is born from fear rather than contempt. He wants to keep Muggles from dragging the magical world along in their fall as they destroy the planet. For that purpose, he needs the control over great destructive powers – like nuclear weapons – to be out of the hands of people who have never learned to be responsible with that sort of thing. Which, given their nature, probably means destroying them all, along with the facilities where they're made."

"So he intends for a wizard to rule the Muggle world, for their own good and ours," Dumbledore nodded. "He is not killing wantonly, he does not seek the destruction of all Muggles or even those politically opposed, he merely wishes for a magical dictatorship underneath a benevolent and powerful ruler. There was a time when I would have agreed with such a goal."

Hermione gasped in shock. The old man smiled at her. "Don't worry. I got wiser. And I daresay Harry is already much better than that." He pierced Harry with his deep blue eyes. "You do seem to understand him very well indeed, Harry Potter. Much like I understood Grindelwald, once."

Harry nodded. "Yes. You thought he was my dark mirror, didn't you?"

"And is he?"

"I guess I see the point." Harry had thought about that a few times in the last week. "We think alike in many ways. Except... he's just empty. He doesn't care about other people at all. Like, he doesn't hurt people for fun, but if it helps him in some way, he doesn't mind what pain he causes either. And if he sees people doing stupid things, he just gets cynical about it, rather than trying to fix them. Or he suggests 'fixing' them with the Kiling Curse."

"Whereas your Patronus spell is, as I gather it, almost its exact opposite," the old wizard suggested.

"Yes," Harry agreed. "I guess in the end, that's what makes the crucial difference between us. I put great value on other people's lives. He cares only about his own."

"The difference, in short, is your capacity for love?"

Harry paused. He had the feeling the Headmaster had suggested something like this months ago, and that Harry hadn't taken him very seriously at the time.

"Well played, Professor. Well played."

The Headmaster just smiled and winked.

"So what do we do about this?" Hermione asked. (Harry noticed that she said we, which was good, even if she still seemed to want to rely on Dumbledore.) "It sounds like we can't win whatever we do."

"Little though I like suggesting it after what Harry just said," the old wizard said heavily. "I think we'll have to figure out how to kill Voldemort. Even if there may be alternative options now that we have some idea of what he's planning, we would want to have the possibility if the opportunity should arise."

Hermione paled. Harry just turned to business.

"For that, you'll have to tell us a bit more about how he's immortal in the first place. So far, you haven't exactly been forthcoming with information. From what little you told me, I still have hardly any idea what is going on."

The Headmaster shifted uncomfortably. "As I have told you before, my knowledge on that subject is woefully limited –"

"Maybe," Harry growled. "But even that little bit, you still haven't told me completely. For example, you mentioned some Myrtle person dying for his immortality before. That's something you didn't mention when we talked about this the last time."

Dumbledore frowned, seeming to fight with himself.

"You don't want to say," Hermione said quietly. "Is it that bad?"

The old wizard looked grave. "Yes, Hermione, it is the darkest kind of magic. But," he turned to Harry, "I confess that the main source for my reluctance is concern over your response, Harry. I know that you seek immortal life, for yourself and others, but I would not have you try this road to immortality, for that way darkness lies. You might be able to talk yourself into it, if you were to find a willing victim perhaps. You do not believe in the existence of souls, so you might fool yourself into thinking that this ritual holds no risks for you. But I am certain that it will destroy the goodness in your heart, and I fear to the utmost the consequences for the world if you go down this path."

"I promise you, Professor, I will use my best moral judgment. No, let's make that stronger. If Hermione thinks it's a bad idea for me to use whatever you're going to tell me, I won't do it, and I'm not going to do any irreversible magics without being entirely sure what effect they will have. Can you be okay with that?"

"Caw?"

Hermione fondled Xare as Professor Dumbledore gazed at her intently. Then, he reluctantly nodded.

"Very well, then. I shall tell you two all that I know, although I must ask that what we discuss today does not leave this room." He paused, waiting until they had both nodded in agreement, before resuming. "I have spoken to you before of a dark and terrible ritual, by which a fragment of the soul is torn off and chained to a worldly device. Such a device is called a horcrux. I do not know, precisely, of the arts involved in the creation of this foul thing, but I am almost certain that part of the process requires a murder. While the horcrux persists, that part of the soul will prevent the part that resides in your body from passing on. Even if the body is killed, the soul is tied to this realm by the part in the horcrux, although it is greatly weakened and will take years before regaining the strength to take possession of a host body or, with sufficient help, even to acquire a new body of its own. Voldemort has dropped hints to his servants about his immortality before, and I am quite certain that he killed Abigail Myrtle when he was still in school. As no apparent motive existed for that murder, I suspect he made a horcrux even then."

"Just because you don't know of a motive doesn't mean there wasn't one," Harry pointed out. "And if you actually knew for certain that a schoolboy had killed a fellow student, I imagine he would be in Azkaban, so could you please just give us the raw facts, and then maybe inferences afterwards?"

"Most of what I know is based on inference and guesswork, I'm afraid," the old wizard replied. "What little I know of horcruxes comes from a book I remember reading briefly during my student years before putting it away in disgust, and otherwise a collection of suggestive book passages, half-disintegrated scrolls and ancient tales passed on from parent to child. To become a powerful wizard, you have to learn to read between the lines, and this is what I have done for want of a better option. But, I shall try to do as you ask."

"So... Myrtle?" Harry pressed.

"She herself knew of no motive," Dumbledore said. "Her ghost told me as much. It took me a while to coax her into speaking of her death, however – at first she was quite preoccupied with haunting the girl who had bullied her in school. Her testimony suggested that her killer was a boy, speaking in hisses, although she never saw his face. Given how exceedingly rare the Parseltongue ability is, I am certain that the boy in question was Tom Riddle. Yet, she didn't even know him besides being aware of him as a Prefect in a different House. I suspect that, due to her isolation, she was merely a convenient target..." He trailed off, and looked grave. "Unfortunately, a ghost's testimony in court is not accepted, as ghosts can neither take Veritaserum nor be punished for lying in court, so Riddle was never even questioned over her death. At the time, I do believe he had already learned Occlumency, however, so it would not have been enough regardless."

"I see," Harry said. It wasn't very convincing evidence, but it was plausible that Riddle had used a random student as a victim in some sacrificial ritual. It didn't follow that this was an immortality ritual, but it was still worth filing away for future reference.

"What does a horcrux look like?" Hermione asked in the silence.

"I do not know of any distinguishing features. The object to be turned into a horcrux could be anything, although it might need to be something of emotional value to the owner. I suspect, given that Voldemort put a part of his soul on it, it will be something grand, but I can guess no more than that. There are certain spells to recognize a horcrux when it is nearby, but unfortunately I have no clue what they are."

Harry frowned. "And the trick to undoing the caster's immortality is to destroy the horcrux?

"Indeed," the old wizard nodded. "All my sources agree on that: when the device is destroyed, the caster is once again truly mortal. To destroy them is not easy, however; neither mundane methods nor any but the most powerful of magics will be able to penetrate a horcrux's protections. I once heard a tale of a dark wizard whose possessions were all burned after his death, yet a single painting remained untouched by the flames, a painting that exhibited a remarkable intelligence and personality. Neither swords, cutting curses, dedicated charms to remove the magic from paintings or anything else worked, until the painting was finally destroyed using fiendfyre. That, and basilisk venom, are the only two feasible ways of destruction I learned of."

Harry nodded. "But to destroy this horcrux, I presume, we need to find it. Does he need to keep it close to himself?"

The old wizard shook his head. "The only purpose of a horcrux is to bind a soul to this realm; I do not believe that there is any reason its creator would ever need to come back to it."

"Great. So it could be anywhere."

The old wizard smiled sadly. "Yes. I was hoping you might have some ideas where he could have hidden it, as you are so familiar with the way he thinks."

Harry frowned, thinking. Where would I hide something I wouldn't want anyone to find?

Something inside him shriveled up and died.

"I do. Sorry, there is no way you're ever going to find it."

"Why?"

"He actually asked me this before, where I would hide something, and the answer amused him for some reason. I don't know exactly what I came up with, but I'm pretty sure dropping it at the bottom of a non-descript piece of ocean, getting it at a random spot in the earth's core and sending it out into space were some of them. If I can think of that, then so did he. In fact –" He trailed off as another realization hit him.

Crap.

"Harry, what's wrong?" Hermione asked. "You look very white all of a sudden."

"Have you ever heard of the Pioneer Probes?"

"So you're telling me," Dumbledore summarized, looking very tired now, "that Voldemort's horcrux is probably on a trajectory out of the Solar System."

"Yes." Harry shrugged helplessly. "I think we could probably calculate its exact location, but... well, you may want to see how much wizards can help the space program."

"But when did that happen? They launched a probe to outer space before the moon landing?"

"No." Harry shook his head. "Both pioneer probes were launched in the seventies."

"But that doesn't match up! He killed Myrtle far earlier than that, and the books on horcruxes were already missing in 1960."

Harry considered. "Are we sure that there's only one?"

...

...

The Headmaster was staring at him in horrified silence. Hermione looked from one to the other as though she, too, had no idea what was going to happen next.

"If it was me," Harry continued, "I wouldn't trust my immortality to a single object that could be damaged or found or whatever. No matter how many precautions you put on your phylactery, it's never enough. But if this is the kind of thing that you can do more than once – and from your expression I gather that you don't have any knowledge indicating that it is not possible – then that seems like a pretty good idea to do, really. If you don't mind killing people, that is," he added as an afterthought.

The ancient wizard buried his face in his hands. "We are all doomed."

"Not necessarily. There might be other options than killing him, right?" Harry reminded him. "I don't know whether he has a large number of horcruxes in impossible locations. I do know that if he has found a road to immortality, that he will have done everything in his considerable power to ensure that it doesn't get destroyed. So I think we can pretty much give up on this line of thinking, and should consider something else. I guess in the worst case, we could even give him what he wants, because his ulterior goal doesn't seem to be that dark."

"Would you really do that?" Hermione whispered. "After yesterday?"

Harry closed his eyes to shut out the memories. "No. I guess I'd rather not do it. But it's an option to consider."

The Headmaster smiled wryly. "I see you have at last learned of the Phoenix's Price."

Harry looked down at his feet. If continuing to fight would cost another few million innocent lives, should he, really? Was a magical dictatorship with himself at the helm so bad as to make such sacrifices worth it?

"He taught you to lose," Hermione said quietly into the silence. "You're thinking of losing now, aren't you? Of giving up in the face of a superior foe?"

Harry looked up. She was right.

"Not yet," he said grimly. "We'll see how it plays out. His goals are somewhat aligned with mine, but I don't like his methods, and I have no intention of conquering the Muggle world. Let's not stop thinking after one setback. Perhaps we cannot kill him, but can we imprison him? If he is possessing a body, can we bind him to it?"

The Headmaster shook his head. "Everything I know of possession says you cannot. If he creates another body for himself, perhaps that would work, if he had no way of committing suicide."

"Okay. You say the horcrux is about souls. Now, I don't believe in souls, and as far as I can tell, neither does Quirrell. Are there other explanations about what it does?"

The Headmaster shrugged helplessly. "If there are, I do not know of them. But that is saying very little, since, as you know, my knowledge of horcruxes is limited."

"Right, so let's focus on the world 'soul' for now. Do we know any other magic that is said to have something to do with souls? Can you bind or... destroy..."

They stared at each other in sudden understanding.

"Well," the old wizard broke the silence eventually. "I suppose Dementors did have some purpose after all. It's a shame you just destroyed all of them."

"Which was one of his plans, of course," Harry grumbled. He began to understand what Moody had meant when he said you always ended up doing or thinking exactly what he wanted you to do or think. "I don't suppose we know where Dementors originally came from? Can we make new ones?"

Dumbledore shook his head. "They breed, when they are given enough souls. But where they originally came from, no one knows."

"All right, if we do find another Dementor, it may be an idea to keep it rather than straight-out destroy it, but otherwise, let's shelve that idea for now. Do we know of other ways to bind a soul? Or other magics, creatures or devices that somehow have 'soul' or 'spirit' in their description?"

"Possession, mainly, which is done by briefly moving your soul and magic out of your body and into someone else's – although there is some academical disagreement on that point – but this does not seem useful to our situation. Exorcism rituals cast out the possessing soul, which is contrary to what you are looking for. Otherwise, there are the resurrection stone and ghosts, but these only provide a way to interact with specific people who have already died. Killing, in particular the Killing Curse, is said to crack the soul, but I believe that this merely helps in creating more horcruxes."

"Hrmz. Well, it's worth thinking about, and I'll keep reading about possession, frustrating though all the contradictions are. I'll try to come up with other formulations that might be relevant." His stomach rumbled audibly.

"Yes," the Headmaster nodded. "But come to my office whenever you have any new ideas you wish to discuss. You are always welcome."

As they trudged back towards the Great Hall together (Hermione didn't want to use Xare for everything), Hermione looked a little bit subdued.

"Are you okay?" Harry asked. "I know it probably takes some getting used to."

"I'm not sure there was much point in me being there at all," she muttered. "All I could do was sit and listen and be completely horrified by everything the two of you were discussing."

"Well, we've been having several of these sessions. Dumbledore is used to fighting a war, so he can be very hard when he needs to be, and, well, I'm creative, you know me. But note that just because I think of stuff doesn't mean I'm going to do it. It's all about getting into a habit of coming up with good ideas, and then you can disregard the more immoral and impractical ones later. If I disregarded ideas because my brain shut off when going into that direction, then I'd miss a lot of good and perfectly ethical possibilities, and I'd be less good at figuring out what the bad guys want to do. You shouldn't blame yourself for not thinking like that, you're just not that kind of person. And you did bring up some pretty good points, actually."

She nodded, and walked on in silence.

"What's this with you being possessed?" she asked eventually. "You said something about that earlier, but I didn't really know what you were talking about."

"Oh, that. Well, Professor Dumbledore thinks my dark side is actually a possession by You-Know-Who gone wrong. Apparently dark wizards can take over other people's bodies, but normally that requires them to 'leave their own' and be fully concentrated on dominating you. But he found a story about this child who got dominated by a dark wizard who was also active at the same time. So he thinks that You-Know-Who tried to possess me by only putting a part of himself in me, and that he then accidentally killed himself, was kept alive by the horcrux, and the part of him that was possessing me sort of grew into me and became a separate part, but with no real control unless I get very angry."

She frowned. "A part of him? Like, a part of his soul?"

He stood stock still. That hypothesis made an awful lot of sense. Of course Riddle had multiple horcruxes. He didn't give a damn about human sacrifice. He had so many that he could afford to take some risks with one of them, and turn a vulnerable object like a human into a horcrux as well. A horcrux could be something as simple as a full backup of your mind at the time of making it; Harry's dark side had no will of its own, but it did seem to have intelligence.

"Should we go back to Dumbledore?" Hermione asked in a high voice.

Harry shook his head, and started walking again. "Not now. I want to think about it first. If he realizes that I'm a horcrux he might just decide that I need destroying."

"He wouldn't do that!"

Harry sighed wearily and pulled her along. "What do you think you know, Hermione, and how do you think you know it?"

Chapter 102: The Muggle War, Pt 1

Wednesday morning, in Westminster Palace. Thomas Johnson sat in the packed audience benches. Yesterday evening, the Minister of Magic Cornelius Fudge had visited the Prime Minister, and in a rare show of consideration offered to address the House of Commons. Thomas had barely managed to secure a seat, but as a high-ranking official in the Ministry of Defense, he had some leverage.

Perhaps it was unfair. He already knew all about magic, and had even been reading the Daily Prophet every evening for the last three years. Being married to a witch had many perks, even if it meant lying to his friends and family because of the silence vows. But Sarissa had told him that the Minister of Magic was a blustering fool, a puppet controlled by the more powerful players on the political field, and he wanted to see this for himself. The live broadcast might not work for long, as too much magic disturbed electronic devices, a problem which he had encountered far too often in their household. (Fortunately, Sarissa didn't have much need for magic at home, her day job researching spells in the Nimbus company giving her an outlet for her witchy urges.)

Minister Fudge was supposed to deliver a speech at ten in the morning.

It was now 10:02.

People were shifting uncomfortably, the Prime Minister looking livid. The supposed Minister of Magic was nowhere to be seen near the palace, and if the man didn't show up, it would reflect badly on him. Even if he did, the lateness was a sure sign of disrespect towards the governmental body.

Finally, at six minutes past ten, a man suddenly appeared in the center of the room with a loud *pop*. All conversation ceased amidst gasps.

The wizard drew himself up with a pompous look on his face. A portly man wearing a pinstriped suit and a lime green bowler hat, he looked positively ridiculous. The man cast a surprised look around the room.

"Ah, good morning, Minister Fudge," the Prime Minister spoke.

The Minister of Magic nodded briefly. "What's with all these people, Prime Minister? I expected to speak just with you and your ministers."

The Prime Minister's face briefly flashed in consternation, but then quickly smoothed itself again. "These are the elected representatives of the lower House of parliament, sir." He wisely forgot to mention the spectators on the Strangers' Gallery, Thomas thought. Not to mention the cameras.

"Yes, well," the wizard grumbled. "I'm already breaking the Statute of Secrecy as it is, just by being here. It needn't get any worse."

"I assure you, sir, all the people in this room are aware of magic. It's been rather hard to miss, these past few days." His voice held just a hint of reproach.

"Oh, I suppose." The man flicked his hand dismissively before turning to face the Assembly, and cleared his throat.

"I've been asked to inform you of the current situation. Well then. The attacks on Monday and earlier this month were done by a dark wizard, Quirius Quirrell or something like that. Don't ask me why, he probably just has it in for Muggles. You may rest assured that we are taking the matter very seriously, and the Department of Magical Law Enforcement is doing all in its power to apprehend the man." After a pause he added, in tones as though he were bestowing a great favor upon his listeners: "I can also offer you a thousand doses of bone, muscle and tissue regeneration potion to help with the aftermath of Monday's... of Monday."

There was a brief silence, then the Minister of Public Health cleared his throat. "There are over five thousand heavily wounded, sir. Perhaps a little more ...?"

The wizard started, and stared at the man who had spoken. "This is an extremely generous offer! A thousand such potions would take a Master Potioneer over half a year to make, you know."

Thomas groaned silently. Just point out that most of those people don't need limb regrowth, you fool. A thousand potions seemed to be about the right figure to help the people who had third-degree burns in public places, needed amputations, or had ruptured internal organs beyond repair. The offer must have been designed to cure those people who were beyond the abilities of Muggle medicine to help. Unfortunately, it didn't seem like Fudge was about to explain this reasoning.

The Minister of Public Health seemed lost for words for some moments, but quickly recovered. "Thousands of people will suffer for much longer than half a year without the help, sir. Perhaps you might consider...?"

The wizard snorted. "We are already giving you more than half the current supply of St. Mungo's! I'd think you'd be grateful!"

"We do appreciate it, sir," the man answered, with a definite edge to his voice. "But one of your citizens hurt our people, and your offer of assistance only accounts for a fraction of the wounded!"

"Well, that's hardly our problem, is it?" The portly man blustered. "It's not like we sent the man after you!"

There was a buzz of indignant muttering and several angry exclamations at that. The Speaker called for order, and the Minister of Defense stood up.

"Before we continue this... discussion," he spoke in a deep voice, "I was wondering. What is currently being done to apprehend this dark wizard? I see little point in haggling over healing potions if this man is just going to pull a similar stunt next week."

"As I said," Fudge said haughtily, "we are working on it."

"Yes, sure, I understand," the man continued. "But that is a phrase we have heard many times in these chambers, and it may carry many different meanings. Would you be able to tell us how you are progressing? Do you know his residence? Where he will strike next? His methods? Whether he is acting alone or is part of a larger network?"

"He wasn't even sure of the man's name," a woman interjected bitterly. "Or what he wants."

"I'm the Minister of Magic, not the Head of Magical Law Enforcement! It's not my job to concern myself with details like that."

"If a criminal from my country killed and wounded over a million people in one day," the Minister of Defense spoke harshly, "I would damn well hope that the Prime Minister knew his name, at least! And from your response, it sounds like you either have very little clue what's going on in your own Ministry, which would speak volumes about the quality of your magical 'government' if true, by the way, or you simply don't want to admit that you have absolutely no leads on this dangerous individual who seems to be targeting non-magical people in particular."

"Excuse me?" Fudge exclaimed.

"Look," the man continued. "We can help. This is obviously an urgent matter of national and international importance. If you or someone else can illuminate what your people know about this... this terrorist, his motives and especially his abilities, we can dedicate several teams of our best police force and army groups to his capture."

The wizard snorted. "You seriously think Muggles have a chance at finding and defeating a wizard? That's preposterous."

The Defense Minister ground his teeth. "Muggles, as you call us, are not so helpless as you seem to think. Send us someone to explain, or even better, demonstrate magical abilities, and we'll employ our most advanced spying and engagement technology. With an understanding of what magic can do, we may be able to develop both defenses and weapons. Even if it turns out we truly cannot take him down ourselves, it is sheer arrogance to believe that our help could not be useful at all."

The Minister of Magic bristled. "Now see here, I'm not going to teach a bunch of Muggles what magic spells look like! The very idea! If I had know you would be so demanding I wouldn't have come here!"

"You expected us to say 'yes sir, no sir' and lap up everything you said, didn't you?" The woman who had spoken up before asked. "Do you really expect us to sit and wait while you get your act around and handle this terrorist? And for that matter, I find it really hard to believe that a single terrorist could wreak such damage. He cannot possibly be working alone."

"Believe what you will," the Minister of Magic answered coolly.

"Very well then, I shall tell you what I believe," the Muggle woman answered back. "I believe that there's a group of highly dangerous individuals out to wage a magical war of terror on normal people. I believe that you and your magical Ministry are either on their side, or covering for them because you're too afraid of what we might be able to do to you if, heaven forbid, we should come to learn how magic works. I believe you are not going to expend any more than a token effort at uncovering this group, because you don't give a toss about what happens to Muggles. You don't feel anything but contempt for us, do you?"

The wizard glared at her. "I see no reason to respond to that."

"Is it true?" Another asked. "Are you just planning to stand by and let us get killed?"

"I hardly expect it to make a difference," another man, Lee White, sneered. "If the rest of his people share the incompetence of their leader, we might as well be on our own."

Thomas flinched. Lee White was an idiot, a troublesome back bencher with little political experience and no sense of diplomacy. His attention-seeking and "plain speaking" antics were bad enough normally, but the leader of the magical side of the country was not someone whom it seemed wise to insult.

Cornelius Fudge stared at the man. "How dare you speak to your superiors in such a way?" He demanded.

"Superiors?!" Someone else shouted, shocked. "Are you mad? Who made you –" and then cut off as the Prime Minister frantically signaled for him to shut up, as the pompous little wizard turned red hot in anger.

"I see that I have given the wrong impression by coming here tonight," the man finally said in what was probably supposed to be a cool tone, but quite failed to hide his loss of composure. "Just because I deign to explain a few things to you doesn't mean that you have the right to question and judge me!" He briefly tipped his hat in a gesture of goodbye.

"Wait!" One of the women stood up and yelled to him. "Wait, please, sir! Please, what about the children?"

The Minister of Magic turned to her. "Children?" He repeated.

"The school children from the Saint Mary's primary school. The Prime Minister has informed us that they might still be alive?"

"Oh, them," the wizard said. "Yes, I forgot to mention that. I suppose we might as well send them home now."

"Thank you, sir. And... are they all right?"

"They're all missing a leg," the man shrugged, looking somewhat calmer now that he was being addressed in properly deferential tones. "But otherwise they're unharmed, last I heard."

"What did you do to them?" A man asked, and then added, grudgingly, "sir?"

"I did nothing," the Minister of Magic replied in a prickly tone. "This Quirrell guy apparently went and cursed their legs off. We've just moved them to the Ministry for the time being."

"But why did you take them away in the first place?"

"Well, they were all missing a leg! We could hardly leave them there. The International Confederation would never stand for such a breach of the Statute of Secrecy."

"So you kidnapped three hundred and twelve children," a woman said hollowly. "Made their parents believe they died in a horrible explosion, and now hold them prisoner against their will in this Ministry of yours, presumably never to return home. And you did all this just to keep the public from discovering the truth?"

"What else would you have me do?" Fudge blustered. "We can't just violate our most sacred law for a bunch of Muggle children!"

"What about our laws?" Another man shot. "The laws of this country? And no," he added loudly to the person sitting next to him, who had nudged him and shot him a warning look, "I'm not going to be all 'yes sir' and 'please sir' and 'thank you sir', and pretend that this man who didn't even get elected by the public is somehow above me, just to stroke his ego."

"And I am not going to let some uppity Muggle lecture me!" Cornelius Fudge almost shouted. "You will hold your tongue, mister, if you like it where it is!"

"Are you threatening me?"

"Please remain calm, sir," The Speaker requested.

"If you live on British soil," the man continued after a brief pause, cold dripping from his voice, "you should follow British law, and not hide behind ungoverned institutions."

"That's a little presumptuous, sir," the wizard answered in similar tones. "Perhaps you should follow our laws instead."

"You would seek to rule us?"

"Well, I wasn't going to bring it up, but if you insist on pushing the point, then yes, we just might!"

Lee White jumped up. "You realize this means war, don't you?"

"Mr. White, you forget yourself!" The Speaker barked. "You do not speak for this assembly!"

"No, it's fine," Cornelius Fudge said, his cheeks red with anger, his voice shaking. "I see now that Lord Malfoy had the right idea all along. I should never have come here. The only proper way to treat the lower sorts is to kill or subjugate them!"

He nodded firmly, and disappeared with a crack of Apparition.

The Minister of Magic appeared in the Wizengamot Hall, where those of them who had bothered to show up were waiting.

"Ah, Cornelius," the Chief Warlock boomed. "How did it go?"

"Well, I'll say! Those arrogant... Those presumptuous..."

Amelia's heart sank. Just how badly has it gone wrong?

"What happened, Cornelius?" Albus Dumbledore asked.

"Those arrogant Muggles had the audacity to declare war on us. On us!"

"What made them do so?" Dumbledore demanded, over the gasps of surprise. "What did you say?"

"I delivered the message, just like you asked me to! And then they got all unreasonable, saying they didn't believe me and demanding more! The very idea!"

The Chief Warlock frowned. "Muggles have every reason to tread carefully in our presence, and little reason to take offense to an explanation, a gift and an apology for not being able to do more. Did you say something that could have provoked them, Cornelius? Perhaps a misunderstanding?"

"More likely," Lucius Malfoy cut in, "the Muggles perceived him to act weakly, and saw it as an invitation." He smiled wryly. "This is what I've been saying over and over again. We cannot live peacefully side by side with Muggles. Either we establish our superiority, or they will try to dominate us! Today we have seen where trying to reach out a friendly hand leads us, will you listen to me now?"

Amelia sighed in frustration as the arguments flared up again.

Thursday afternoon found the House of Commons in uproar again.

"Look, I'm just saying," Zack Scott spoke elaborately, "it is obvious that we cannot fight these people. They have magic, for God's sake! If we want to survive, the only thing we can do is submit. The next time they come to us, we apologize, show them the respect they want, and accept whatever demands they make."

"We don't even know that they are going to make any demands," Rita Reham pointed out wearily once again.

"But we must agree on the response if they do!"

The Prime Minister looked ponderously at Zack Scott while people argued around him. The usually calm, manipulative man was behaving uncharacteristic of himself. Of course it was possible that the shock of the revelation of magic, and then the superior attitude of the Minister of Magic had caused his current behavior, but, well...

Could magic be used to take over someone's mind, or impersonate them down to the very fingerprints?

He'd been wondering for the last hour. During a break in the discussions, he had approached Zack and asked him a personal question about his wife, and Zack had looked him squarely in the eyes and given him an answer only the real Zack Scott would have known. So it had to be him, and yet... something felt off. Unfortunately, despite knowing about magic for several years now, he'd never seen many hints of what it was capable of.

A loud cough in the doorway; his personal secretary stood there, looking disturbed. He nodded his apologies and left his place, quickly stepping over to her as curious glances followed him. The woman silently passed him a note.

Zack Scott's wife on the telephone just now. He was found bound and comatose half an hour ago. Currently in hospital.

With a jolt he looked up from the paper, staring at the man who had been addressing the assembly.

The impostor met his eyes, raised an eyebrow, and sneered. Then he whirled around, and disappeared with a soft *pop*.

On Thursday night, the Palace of Westminster went up in flames.

Life went on. Despite the nation-wide panic, you couldn't just drop all your responsibilities and take to the streets – and what would that accomplish, anyway? So, after reading the morning paper, and worrying quite a bit about all the recent developments, Mary drank the last of her coffee and went to the hospital to start her shift. She wondered idly whether Zack Scott would wake up today. The politician who had been found naked and unconscious in the cellar of an abandoned building while to all appearances he was speaking in parliament at the time was in one of her wards, and it was intriguing, even if more than a little scary, to be so close to the events that were shaking the country.

Mary clocked in and walked to the ward to inspect the patients, but she stopped in her tracks right before the entrance.

Blood was seeping out from underneath the door.

Shaking, fearful of the sight that might meet her eyes but knowing that someone would have to do it, she opened the door and gasped at the blood, and the body of her colleague lying mutilated on the floor.

"Were you the one who sounded the alarm?" A creepy voice whispered in her ears. She whirled around, but there was no one there, no one still alive. Panic rising, she tried to run, but then realized she couldn't move.

"I think you might have been," the creepy voice decided.

"N-no," she whispered, only to be met with a throaty laugh from the same invisible source.

"Crucio."

On Friday afternoon, a group of rioters broke into old Tom's antique store, accused him of being a wizard, and set the place on fire.

"What the –"

Marco jumped back in shock as he entered his garden shed to put away his tools and found it already taken. A writhing mass of tendrils and vines covered every inch of the floor, wall and ceiling, and most of the space in between as well. What was more, the moment he opened the door, it almost seemed like the plant was turning to face them, absurd though that idea was.

He hesitated only a second, then turned on his heel and ran. Or he tried to, but the move only made him fall over, his left foot already ensnared by a thick green vine.

He struggled and screamed as the plant drew him inside and wrapped itself around his torso, but all his efforts only seemed to make it worse. The last thing he heard before darkness claimed him were the shocked yells of his neighbors.

On Friday night, when the pubs closed, large groups of drunken people took to the streets, terrified and very, very angry.

Patrick stood on the pavement between houses 19 and 23, laying out a large pile of wood and tinder.

The people in the neighborhood had always assumed that it was a mistake that the houses on the odd-numbered side of the street skipped number 21. Someone had brought up the suggestion to renumber the houses, a few years back, but it would simply be too impractical for the people living in the later houses to change their addresses. So it had been left, a strangeness everyone overlooked for convenience.

But with the recent developments, Patrick figured there might just be something more going on. There was magic in the world, wizards attacking the government, and didn't wizards have to live somewhere too? Why would a street engineer just miss a number, and then not correct it before people moved in? Sure, there were explanations, but perhaps the most natural one was that the house wasn't missing at all. If wizards could impersonate a secretary of state to the point of knowing irrelevant personal details, might they not also be able to hide a house?

His mother thought he was crazy when he brought up this theory in the morning, but he wasn't just going to spend his weekend staying at home and doing homework like everything was fine. He was going to get to the bottom of this.

He poured oil on the wood, and threw a match. With a large woompf the fire flared up.

Patrick waited. The bane of invisible items, he had learned from his regular D&D group, was smoke. An invisible person standing in smoke would leave a gap. Other people could see that. And a house might be a slightly different thing, but it was worth trying.

He stared at the divide between houses 19 and 23 as smoke from the slightly wet wood wafted by. Absolutely nothing weird showed up.

Wait, no. The smoke was moving a lot more towards the 23 door than towards 19; it hardly seemed to move in that direction at all. Yet there was no wind. Even though his mind insisted that nothing looked strange at all, when he considered the movement of the smoke there was evidently something going on.

"What do you think you're doing, you little vandal, lighting fires in the street?" An angry voice demanded behind him. Patrick jumped, and turned. A middle-aged man stood there, arms crossed, eyes flashing.

Patrick stamped down on his reflex to run, and instead smiled brightly. "It's all for a good purpose, sir. I've just confirmed the presence of wizards in our street."

"Paul? What's wrong?"

Paul stared up at his co-pilot. "All the instruments have gone haywire all of a sudden!"

The woman blanched. "Well. I guess this is where we put our training to the test."

Around dinnertime, Patrick was no longer alone. A crowd had gathered around him, and the more people were there, the more ideas got brought up and accommodated.

They had tried to determine the exact divide between houses 19 and 23, and got a headache for their efforts. They could mark two places on the walls which seemed quite close to each other, but they couldn't manage to stand exactly between them, even though they could walk from one to the other in a single step.

Now, some people had created a good hundred Molotov cocktails. The inhabitants from houses 19 and 23 were not at all pleased with the plans, even despite their discomfort with the idea of living next to a wizard, but they didn't get much of a say in the situation. The police was wisely staying well away, and a number of people had brought fire extinguishers to stop any fire from spreading, just in case. A journalist with camera crew stood a bit to the side, capturing every moment. Other neighbors had reviled Patrick and the others for their stupidity, and fled their houses for safer ground, far away from where magic might be happening.

Patrick smiled broadly. This was his moment.

With a flick of his arm, he hurled the first bottle right at the center between the two markers they had been able to place. It exploded, not quite at the wall although he wouldn't have been able to say exactly at what point it did, and then the fire almost instantly died out.

The crowd roared – if they had still needed any more confirmation, they had it now. Patrick was pushed aside as the others joined in, and bottle after bottle was flung at the divide. Every time a bottle hit there was a brief explosion, and then the fire quickly died (except twice, when the thrower missed and hit one of the houses on either side, but these fires were both extinguished before any harm could be done). The wall on the outside of the markers became more and more charred, but the center remained perfectly clear.

At the thirtieth bottle, there was a sudden shimmering in the air, but nothing more than that.

The next thirteen bottles had a similar effect. And then, at the forty-fourth bottle, there was a flash of light and the group suddenly found themselves standing in front of house 21. Patrick blinked. He had suspected, but to see it happen like that was... was something else entirely.

There was a chuckle behind them. "Impressive."

Patrick spun around rapidly. Behind them stood a tall, muscular man, wearing gray robes, a piece of wood held loosely in his hand. Wand, Patrick mentally filled in. The air around the wizard was shimmering with a strange blue light – some kind of arcane shield?

"This was my mother's old house," the wizard spoke softly. "The wards haven't been renewed in ten years. Still, I wouldn't have expected a bunch of Muggles to take them down so easily. So, congratulations on your achievement."

Mrs. Jones, who lived at number 41, didn't wait. She grabbed another bottle and hurled it right at the wizard. The man, however, merely waved his wand and the projectile was flicked to the side, falling harmlessly on the street. Then he pointed his wand at the woman. "Sectumsempra."

Blood spurted from Mrs. Jones's face and chest, as though she were slashed multiple times with a sharp sword. The woman collapsed in a pool of blood, the assorted people staring in shock.

Patrick didn't want to look, but he couldn't tear his eyes away. Holy shit.

"Oh, you little fools. You haven't got a clue what you got yourself into, have you?"

The man's left hand dipped into his pocket, and then he threw something to the right, then to the left. On either side of the crowd, a wall of dark red mist appeared in the street, blocking any escape they might have contemplated.

"Let's have some fun, shall we?"

Patrick glanced to the sides, suddenly frightened. There was no going back from what they had started; the mist was probably dangerous, they couldn't flee anymore. Yet the wizard didn't seem to have any fear at all.

He made a snap decision and grabbed two bottles from one of the boxes even as William, who lived three streets over, was already flinging another bottle at the wizard. The man merely pushed it away again, right into another bystander. William roared, and tossed another bottle, and then a third from the box by his feet.

Too much was happening at once. The screams from the burning man, the whimpering from the slashed woman, and not too far away, a man yelling in some kind of agony after he had stepped into the mist. People were throwing Molotov cocktails at the wizard, staying as far away as they could, but he just flung them aside, until finally someone managed to hit him from behind.

The wizard merely stumbled as the explosive hit his shield, and he turned around and yelled "Reducto!" The man who had thrown the projectile just exploded, but Patrick, not one to miss an opportunity when it presented itself, threw his two bottles in quick succession at the back of the wizard, then ran to another part of the street to avoid being targeted immediately.

Some of the others had seen it too, the weakness, and they scattered. Can't stay too close to each other, he'll just fling our weapons back at us and set us on fire in groups. But if they could surround him, he couldn't defend all sides at once. If enough explosives could bring down the protections of a house, wouldn't they be able to take on a person too?

The wizard snarled as blast after blast tore into his shields, and he aimed his wand and cast "Reducto" and then "Reducto" again, each time exploding one of his opponents. But he had made a crucial mistake, Patrick thought. He had given them no choice, hemming them in and blocking their escape. They would all fight to the death, even grumpy old Mrs. Wind who always complained about the loudness of his music.

It was Patrick's friend Kim whose bottle hit the wizard's right-hand side, shattered the shield with a large flash and snapped his wand.

There was a brief moment of shock as the man stared in horror at the broken piece of wood, then looked at the people who were dying around them, half still alive, still standing. This is it, Patrick thought, wishing he still had explosives. They can be beaten.

With a scream of pain, the wizard was engulfed in flame as another bottle hit him from the back, and then he suddenly disappeared.

Patrick looked at the camera, the reporter and crew lying dead nearby. It was amazing how steady his voice was when he asked no one in particular: "do you think it's still running?"

On Saturday night, all the news stations covered the near-defeat of an extremely murderous wizard at the hands of a group of civilians.

Lisa was looking at the repeat of the news when suddenly the television went black. The digital clock on the stereo went out, and from upstairs she heard a frustrated yell from her father.

All the electrical devices in the house? She tried the kitchen lights. Nothing.

Standing in front of the kitchen window, however, she saw a large plume of billowing black smoke in the distance. That was probably related...

She was still staring at the smoke as her father thundered down the stairs half a minute later.

"Pack some clothes honey, quickly! We're getting out of here."

"What –"

"They blew up the power station! It's not safe to stay here."

Suddenly, the events on television seemed a lot less exciting, and a lot more frightening. "But where is it safe?"

On Sunday afternoon, large protests were staged in the streets, while new crowds gathered around those places where mysterious hints – like missing house numbers or building sites that had been wrecked for as long as anyone could remember – suggested that perhaps magic might be at play. At the same time, innocent nature healers, gothic teenagers and people outside the common social structure were abused or even outright attacked. Three people were killed in fights, and the police had to break up many more.

"Things are spinning out of control rapidly."

Amelia nodded grimly at the old wizard sitting across the table. "Yes. They are."

"I should never have agreed to let Cornelius deliver the message," Albus Dumbledore sighed bitterly. "Five thousand Galleons' worth of potions, paid from my own vault, and he manages to turn it into an insult. And then he bungles what we all agreed would be a simple explanation and honest question-answering by insisting on establishing his superiority. I suppose it was naive to think that the fool would do something quite so sophisticated as following instructions."

Amelia smirked. "Yes. You always were the optimist, Albus. But do not blame yourself too much." She sighed wearily. "I agreed to it, too. I do not believe there was much choice in the matter; the Wizengamot would not allow you to go, and once Cornelius offered there was no way to send me instead. You know the kind of offense he takes at people he believes are trying to usurp his position."

Albus stared into space. "I wonder whether I should go regardless. Explain things, extend a hand of friendship, without the Wizengamot's blessing if need be."

She could have slapped the old fool. "No! You know they will never accept that! Once upon a time, perhaps, you might have got away with brashly flaunting the Wzengamot's will, but right now your public support is lower than it's ever been, especially with so many thinking that you're the kind of person who would send young children to die to your plots. If you defy its decisions now, you will be ousted from the Wizengamot, ousted even from Hogwarts. It will be the end of you, don't you see?"

Albus just shook his head. "Perhaps it is worth the end of my political career, if I can only stop this war in its tracks."

She rolled her eyes. "You won't stop the war in its tracks, at best you'll add a moderating influence for a while. But then what will we do? After your fall from grace, Lucius will hold the vote in the Wizengamot, and will be all but uncontested in his call for dominion over Muggles. How will your sacrifice stop the war, if that's exactly what Lucius will pursue?"

He closed his eyes. "I know. I just... wonder, whether I couldn't do what is right for once, rather than merely what is politically expedient."

She looked at his face, old and weary. "What would you tell them, anyway?"

"That we're not all like that," Albus Dumbledore breathed. "That most of us want peace, just like they do. That we – some of us – will help them, when we can. That what they're seeing is merely the consequence of a single man we have no way of controlling, and a divided government fearful of change."

Amelia snorted. "That would be lying – it isn't a single person anymore, not by far. There are various elements in our society who are taking every advantage of the current hostile atmosphere they can, to get away with being cruel towards Muggles. We've arrested Willy Widdershins this morning for enchanting whole streets full of Muggle doorknobs to bite off fingers, and I think he's only the tip of the iceberg. I don't know who was responsible for the Devil's Snare, or for the sudden infestation of flesh-eating slugs in York, but both of those bear the classical hallmarks of Muggle-baiting taken too far. And did you hear what Macnair did to the people who managed to break the wards to his mother's house?"

Albus nodded. "Will he be punished for it?"

Amelia shook her head sadly. "We've taken him in for questioning, but the law does state that a wizard has the right to defend his house. Perhaps you might say he used excessive force, but the fact is that they were attacking him, and actually managed to take down his shields and break his wand. He can argue any defense was justified, given the power they demonstrated."

"So we cannot even tell them that the perpetrators are being punished."

"No," she agreed, "we cannot. And Albus, surely you realize that such a message wouldn't do any good at all? Even if every Muggle heard you, if your message was heartening and loving and convincing, it would soon be forgotten amidst all the other things which are going on. A hand of friendship is easy to ignore when it stands among people hurling curses at you. And you know he will not stop. No matter what we try, it's never going to work unless we can stop him. So if you have any suggestions..."

"I have no wisdom on how to kill Voldemort," Dumbledore spoke sadly, looking at his hands. "None at all, nor any clue how to even find him. I can think of only one thing to give him pause, that may at least still the bloodshed for now., and yet even that might not be achievable."

"Might not sounds better than is not," Amelia pointed out. She had little patience for mystery. "Tell me more."

On Monday morning, the ferries to Calais and Dublin both sank at the same time.

"Good afternoon, Lieutenant General Darrens."

"Welcome, Brigadier Johnson. Please, have a seat."

Thomas did as he was bid, looking curiously at his companions. There were six men in the room so far, only four of whom he knew, all high-ranked officers in the British Army, Royal Marines and Royal Air Force.

The door opened and two other men came in. The Lieutenant General bade them to sit down too, and locked the door.

"We're complete now," he said. "Thank you all for coming."

"What's this about, sir?" the last newcomer asked.

"The wizard threat, of course," Darrens answered. "You are all men of a certain influence. Together, we can set a course of action to save our country."

"Have we been commanded to act?" Major Meldon asked, surprised. "I have not received any notice. The government –"

"– is compromised," Lieutenant General Darrens cut in. "Didn't you hear what happened on Thursday? If they pulled that kind of stunt once, I won't believe for a second that they haven't tried it again, and without leaving a trace behind this time. And parliament knows it. Can't trust anyone anymore. Why do you think no orders have come from above, not even to disperse the riots in the streets? If they haven't yet been taken over completely, the atmosphere of distrust is making the government fully ineffective, that's why."

"They probably got the Prime Minister," one of the men Thomas didn't know spoke up. "Seeing how he told everyone not to risk their lives playing the hero when that mob almost managed to kill a wizard in the weekend."

"Right," the Lieutenant General nodded. "So we're on our own. Without the guidance of the government, the military has to be willing to take matters into its own hands. Are you willing, men? To do what it takes to defend our people?"

Major Meldon coughed. "How do you know we can all be trusted?"

"None of us are important enough to warrant specific enemy attention," Lieutenant General Darrens explained calmly. "So I'm going to guess none of us have their minds controlled. It's a gamble, I know, but there's sufficient power in this group to make a real difference, even if one or two of us should be compromised."

"I'm with you, sir," another of the men spoke firmly. "They've attacked our people. They've compromised our government. With all airports closed for fear of further interference, and now the boats, they've even taken away our chances to flee the country. They've started attacking our power plants – what if that was just a trial run, and they're taking down all of them next, including the nuclear plant over in Sellafield? We need to do what we can, while we can still do it."

"But what can we do?" Another asked.

"Well, I am sure as hell not prepared to roll over and accept our new magical overlords." the first speaker asserted.

Thomas looked concerned from one face to the next. His loyalties were divided, but he couldn't show that, here. "Are we really sure of who or what is the enemy, here? For what that supposed Minister said, this all might just be the work of a single terrorist."

Major Sandon snorted. "A single terrorist who systematically works on taking over control in the country? Bollocks. What if he succeeds, what's he planning to do, continue to wage war on them? No, if there is a single terrorist, he knows that they'll let him get away with it. Where are the good guys fighting this supposed bad guy? No one teleported into Westminster Palace to expose the impostor, no one stopped innocent hospital personnel from getting tortured, and no one came to arrest that madman when he exploded ten people on Saturday. So no, I'm not gonna give any credit to that bull."

"Agreed," Lieutenant General Darrens nodded. "So, men, are you willing to do what it takes, even without explicitly being given the order?"

There were nods around the table. Even Thomas slowly nodded. If he refused, they would think he was also "compromised", and do who knew what to him. At the very least, he would be asked to leave, if they dared to let him go, and he wouldn't learn what they were planning to do, and whether Sarissa might be in any danger. They had an international portkey to flee abroad if necessary, but he wouldn't be able to reach her until she got home from work in the evening.

"Right," the Lieutenant General spoke. "We know our disadvantages, including that we don't actually know all the things they can do. But there is one large advantage which I am willing to bet we have over them."

"Numbers," Major General Smith said grimly. "If there's one thing I gathered from the glimpses we saw, it's that there really aren't that many wizards. Their Minister thought that a single potioneer working for half a year was a lot – you don't say that sort of thing when you've got thousands working under you. I'm going to hazard a guess that there's a lot more of us than there are of them. That's why they have to resort to subterfuge rather than outright attack."

"Agreed," the Lieutenant General nodded. "I think we can safely say that the enemy controls our government – if they don't already do so, then they will doubtless succeed before the end of the week. But they could never control all the people. We have anarchy, gentlemen, but this doesn't have to be a disadvantage. We have seen this weekend that ordinary civilians can form a real threat to a wizard. Those people had only hand-made weapons – just think how much could be accomplished with proper explosives, grenades, dynamite, or even with handmade weapons designed to fight humans, like smoke bombs?"

"Hold on," one of the men who hadn't yet spoken piped up. "Do you want to arm the general population?"

"Yes," the Lieutenant General said simply. "It's our best hope. We'll open up our military bases, hand out proper weapons to willing citizens, tell them that the government is likely compromised, and pass on the word how to make Molotov cocktails, smoke bombs and pepper bombs. No matter what the wizards pull, there will always be people left who can resist them unless they manage to wipe out sixty million people."

"But the consequences!" The man protested."Putting weapons in the hands of untrained people –"

"– is better than having those same people completely defenseless," the Lieutenant General said authoritatively. "Yes, accidents can happen, but even if we lose ten of us for every one of them we can kill, that's a win."

"But what about afterwards? If you give the people weapons, you can't just undo that, they'll always be out there, accidents or abuse waiting to happen!"

"We can worry about the future after we reassure that we have one," Darrens bit. "It really isn't that big a deal. We'll still exercise some discretion as to what weapons are handed to who, I'm not proposing we hand a barrel of guns to the first lowlife who asks for it! The main thing is that we spread the power around the country, to allow enough people to give a good fight. If, in the future, anyone wants to run amok with heavy weapons in peacetime, they can already make explosives themselves anyway."

"What you're suggesting is a complete civil war," Major Meldon spoke carefully. "With wizards controlling the government, but ordinary citizens forming militias... neither side is going to win that easily, it's going to be long and bloody. I suppose, compared to the alternative, it may be preferable because it allows a shred of hope of freedom, but... Unless you're counting on UN interference?"

Lieutenant General Darrens shook his head. "I don't expect the UN to intercede, no. There's wizards in other countries too, and somehow I don't think they'll be on our side. It's entirely possible that the UK is just a test run, that the end goal is wizard domination across the globe, so the other countries will have their own hands full. Also, the UN really doesn't have much to offer that we don't already have by ourselves. No, my suggestion was going to be a preemptive strike."

"With what target?" one of the other brigadiers asked.

"Every target," Darrens stated with fire in his eyes. "We'll take down every single magical place we can find in one big sweep. It'll devastate them enough to buy us time, and if we capture some of the enemy, we can use that time to experiment with their abilities. The teleporting makes it difficult, but maybe they can't do that if they're tied up? Or if we keep them drugged? I'm sure the scientists can figure something out."

"How will you find such targets of opportunity?" Major General Smith said sceptically. "Looking for missing house numbers?"

"No, I was thinking of somewhat larger targets." The Lieutenant General reached for his bag and drew forth a number of maps. "You must realize that magic can be detected. As that teenager over in Winsford figured out, it's all about noticing anomalies, like a missing house number. Over the years, many people have reported such anomalies. Strangely dressed people arriving and mysteriously disappearing on a London train station every year on the same day, to name an example. Or a pub that certain people can only see from the corner of their eyes. And then one of my computer experts got some very peculiar results when analyzing satellite images in Russia, and she wrote a little program to look for more such apparent errors before word came from above that it was 'known, and highly secret'. Then there's the fact that a number of people – maybe one in a hundred, or in a thousand, I never tested it properly – can see things in such places when they know there's something special there. Like a pub, or a weird monument, or an extra street."

"So you want to send in the soldiers who can see those places and abduct any wizards they come across?" Thomas asked with a frown. Squibs, he realized. They wouldn't be able to get into all the places, but they should at least be able to see Diagon Alley, and probably St. Mungo's too. But how did Darrens know that? There weren't that many Squibs. Had he actually been experimenting with this for years? To what end?

"Where necessary," Darrens nodded. "Ideally, we try to use explosives to make those areas visible first, like the Winsford mob did. Unfortunately, quite a few of those places are in busy areas, so we're a bit limited in how much we want to do. Here, for example," he rifled through the maps and put one of London on top, "there is the pub I mentioned, and if I estimate correctly, there's something big behind it. These places over here –" he pointed at two other small circles "– are too close to normal people too. But where possible, we should send in the soldiers, or use heavier artillery. I've got the codes to launch nuclear missiles."

"Woho!" One of the men Thomas didn't know jumped out. "Are you frigging nuts? Throw atomic bombs on your own country?!"

"A few of these places are far from civilization," the Lieutenant General pointed out. "It would serve to make an excellent point and have relatively little ill consequence for our people."

"I, too, would rather avoid nuclear missiles," Thomas said sharply. "I do not believe this is warranted, and if we actually go down that path we'll have nuclear radiation issues for years in the future!"

"That, or the wizards contain it," Smith suggested. "They have magic, don't they? And if they cannot handle that, we might just have something to use against them. I say it's a good idea, if we can keep the contamination in hand somewhat. One thing though, I think we shouldn't hit all the areas we know about, because then the survivors will just hide in the ones we don't know anything about. We don't want them feeling safe. Hit some areas hard, really hard, but leave a couple others open. Save those for later. Make them paranoid. That kind of atmosphere might help to create a route for negotiation."

Thomas looked helplessly around the table. He had one ally, maybe, one sane person. The others looked all too eager; they wanted revenge after the brutal killings, torture and a few days of tactical warfare. He could protest, but he wasn't going to be able to stop this insanity. Perhaps that was what Darrens had intended, when he invited exactly this group, to create legitimacy in numbers while remaining unopposed? None of the other men Thomas knew were of a cautious nature.

But then why am I here? Had something – faith, perhaps – conspired to get someone on the side of the wizards invited to this meeting? Had Darrens mistaken him for a man as unrestrained as the others?

"That's a reasonable tactic," Major Meldon agreed, "but what targets do we hit? I see a lot of circles here, but it doesn't say what is there. I don't really want to hit a hospital or a school or something."

"They didn't care about burning a hospital with patients still in it," Sandon bit. "Why should we? I say go for it."

Darrens was already grabbing another map, one of the whole island this time. "All right then. I'd propose these areas for nuclear and regular strikes."

Thomas's heart skipped a beat when the man pointed at a small figure eight shaped spot in the Scottish Highlands.

-o-o-o-o-o-

Author's Note: With regards to the session in the House of Commons: unfortunately, I know next to nothing about how such sessions normally go, so I apologize for any strangenesses that don't really fit the British system, and hope I got it roughly right. :)

The Speaker (as some helpful readers explained) is a formal chairman-like position. While normally all conversation would go via the Speaker, I think that in this case it makes sense to simply have the members of parliament directly address Fudge, as he is an outsider giving an information session.

Some readers brought up that it's strange that Fudge wouldn't know Quirrell's name. However, Quirrell was introduced to him as something on the lines of "the Hogwarts Defense Professor (claiming to be Quirinius Quirrell, although that's probably just an assumed identity) who seems to have gone rogue, supposedly the same person as David Monroe, although Albus Dumbledore is saying he was actually Lord Voldemort all along". As such, Fudge has a good reason not to remember the first name, but that isn't something he can easily explain to Muggles.

Chapter 104: The Muggle War, Pt 3

With a *crack* of Apparition, Professor McGonagall reappeared on the forest ground.

"It's not just Hogwarts," she said heavily. "I don't know exactly what is happening, but the Ministry is in complete chaos. Apparently there have been attacks just about everywhere. The visitor entrance to the Ministry has been closed and there was a group of Aurors in the Atrium, like they were expecting trouble there. I could hardly find anyone to even speak to; most of the competent people were either gone or completely swamped. Shacklebolt told me that if we weren't in any immediate danger, we'd better stay where we are, because that put us in better position than most people!"

"That's crazy," Harry bit. "We're completely exposed here."

They were sitting in a small circle away from the others: the Hogwarts staff and Michael, Harry and Hermione. Some of the teachers had raised an eyebrow when Harry inserted himself and Hermione into the meeting, but Professor McGonagall had immediately included them, asking Hermione to send her Patronus to Professor Dumbledore. The Headmaster, it turned out, was still alive, but he was occupied and had little more to say than to put Professor McGonagall in charge of the student body.

"I spoke to a man on the magical maintenance team," Professor McGonagall continued. "For what he could tell me, there have been bombs on several major magical sites away from Muggle cities, at least some of them nuclear bombs. Muggles are also clearing the areas immediately around other places like the Ministry and St. Mungo's, so they might be planning to attack overnight. They even supposedly managed to get into Diagon Alley. The man only knew second-hand information, but what he said sounded plausible, and we already know several family houses have been attacked. If we're going to relocate, I have no idea where to. Nowhere in the wizarding world seems safe."

"Nowhere near Muggles either," Professor Sprout murmured sadly. "Present company excepted, of course."

Michael just shrugged. Harry would have expected him to be more uncomfortable as the only Muggle in the group, but his one week of teaching at Hogwarts had made him more familiar with magic, and Professor McGonagall had explicitly invited him into this meeting. Petunia had also been invited, but she had preferred to stay with the younger children. "Of course. But why not take the children abroad? Hermione can take anyone anywhere at will, can she not?"

"Tensions abroad are not as great as here," Professor Snape conceded. "But I wouldn't dare go anywhere near magical sites there, either. The risk that foreign Muggle governments will take the same view is too large. For that matter, as far as I could tell, the British Muggle government has been completely dysfunctional for some days. These attacks may well have been perpetrated by a foreign agency, and in that case we do not want to relocate to the seat of their own power."

"It might not have been any government at all," Michael contradicted him. "I'm not an expert in military security, but for what little I know, the command chain to fire nuclear weapons allows for several shortcuts in case of emergencies. I've even heard of an American facility where the launch codes were all set to a sequence of zeros, although I'm not sure whether that's true or just an urban legend. Regardless, I would guess that it was simply someone in our military."

"Perhaps," Snape shrugged, "but I wouldn't gamble on it. Being near magical areas, whether here or abroad, is a greater risk than staying put."

"What about abandoned areas abroad?" Hermione suggested.

"You forget Apparition!" Professor Flitwick squeaked. "It's important not to be completely dependent on a single phoenix, Miss Granger. If anything happens abroad, the children won't be able to Apparate home, or even Apparate at all, if they've never been anywhere close enough."

"Not to mention," Snape added, "other magical governments might not be too pleased if we take our war to their borders. Consider this. We are in a random piece of forest in the middle of nowhere. No one even has a reason to suspect we're here, and the foliage stops notice from above. Even in the unlikely event that someone in an airplane would notice us, they would not be able to tell us from Muggles. We have complete obscurity, in short. Add to that the number of people – staff and students – who may contribute to warding the area, and I imagine we are safer here than we would be anywhere else."

"But we have no ward stones," Professor Sprout protested. "It would take at least a day to find a good set and adjust them to the location."

"We don't need them, Pomona!" Professor Flitwick squeaked. "We can group-cast a large shield, and sleep in turns to keep it active. I'll get all the N.E.W.T. students in the Charms and Defense classes to join in! It will only be needed for one or two days at most, until things calm down enough that the children can safely go home. We'll put on some Notice-Me-Not, large-scale Protego, Muggle repelling, maybe Disillusionment..."

"Wait," Harry cut in. "Would this be the kind of thing that causes an empty patch on a photograph, or not being able to look down from a plane, or maybe people arriving somewhere they weren't intending to go? Because I'm pretty sure that that will also draw the wrong kind of attention."

Flitwick nodded. "You are right of course, we should avoid such issues. I'll take care of it."

"And what about dark wizards? We're all focusing on Muggles right now, but should we be afraid for any Death Eater activity while we're here?"

"Since many of the Death Eaters have children at Hogwarts," Professor Snape said impatiently, "I expect they would prefer not to endanger them."

"Right, I guess we have a plan then!" Flitwick got up, and started calling out for his N.E.W.T. students. With some final words, Professor McGonagall ended the meeting and the other teachers and Michael got up and dispersed. Harry, however, stayed put. There was little he could do to help, and he had a few things to think about.

What about Professor Quirr– Voldemort? he wondered.

I vote that we just call him Tom Riddle from now on, Ravenclaw suggested. It is more comfortable than the word 'Voldemort', more convenient than 'You-Know-Who' and, unlike 'Professor Quirrell', may actually refer to the original person rather than a front.

Fine, fine, Harry thought, Riddle. Shouldn't we be worrying about what he's doing?

I am going to put forward the opinion that he caused this, Slytherin suggested. It's a little too convenient that not only did the husband of a witch find out about the bomb in time to get a warning off, the attack also took place at dinnertime, when it was very easy to get everyone out of Hogwarts because almost the entire school was collected in the Great Hall.

In that case, Hufflepuff said ponderously, he never wanted to kill any of us. He's just making a point about nuclear weapons.

And royally biasing everyone against Muggles in the process, Slytherin added grimly. The destruction of Hogwarts will be a powerful rallying point. And we already know he probably doesn't want to kill us – we're going to have to rule the country, remember?

This may mean that we're in no danger from him, at the moment, Ravenclaw said thoughtfully. And by extension, the other students are safe because they're near us. But I would not assign this a greater than eighty percent probability. Then again, if he wants to harm the students, he could probably succeed no matter what we do.

"Harry?" A voice to his side asked. "What are you thinking about?"

Harry turned his head to see Hermione, still sitting next to him. "Just considering what might be going on. I'm not sure how much danger we're in, here."

"Well, is there anything we could do to be in less danger?"

Harry looked grim. "That's what I'm trying to figure out."

"One of our cadets noticed something peculiar during a test flight," the voice emanating from the telephone explained. They were on speaker, with several of the officers listening in.

The captain, as the senior officer, was the first to speak. "Peculiar? Was magic involved somehow?"

"That seems extremely likely," said the RAF officer on the other side. "We found that the young pilot had diverged from his scheduled flight plan, yet he couldn't account for the divergence and was confused about his own decisions. Given his excellent track record, we suspected that something more might be at play, and sent in others to scout the area where he must have gone off target. We have pinpointed several locations, lying in a rough circle, where the planes seem to go off track. We have not been able to confirm anything beyond that, however."

The captain frowned. "Do you think you have been found out? A sudden large number of planes would surely be suspicious."

"Not that suspicious in the area, we regularly test our flights there."

"I see."

"We are pulling our people away from the place to avoid notice regardless," the voice continued. "But we will fax you the coordinates. As you are the nearest military base, you may have to make preparations to respond in case of enemy action. We are also notifying the major police stations."

"Understood. Thank you for the information."

The call ended, and the captain looked around.

"We are not engaging," she spoke firmly. "We will be on the alert in case specific action is warranted, but I have not the slightest intention of sending troops into magical territory without good reason. Despite what some would have us believe, we are not at war with these wizards." She glared sternly at the faces in the room.

"According to the Major –" one of the lieutenants started to protest.

"The Major is acting on his own volition! His words made it very clear that there was no legal basis for his commands. I will not support this madness and throw us into something we have neither understanding of nor business interfering with. Am I clear?"

"Yes Ma'am."

Randall didn't say a word that might reveal his true feelings, even as he inwardly seethed at the captain's cowardice. He kept his face calm as they debated briefly on the preparations to be done, before finally the lower officers were dismissed and filed out to their respective duties.

No engagement. With barely a moment's thought, the captain had rejected all initiative towards the wizards, even further intelligence-gathering. How much more evidence did she need to see that they were at war? The government had gone silent – missing? – while power plants were destroyed, planes were crashed and civilians were attacked left, right and center. Their own high military command had recognized the reality of the situation and taken the unprecedented step of ordering the armature of the general population. Yet despite all this, the captain saw only strict rules, standardized protocols and risks. She didn't see the terror of the people. She hadn't seen the tears on the face of Randall's eight-year-old niece when she learned that she would most likely never have the use of her right hand again, after a doorknob had chewed on it. She hadn't spoken to the dozens of terrified people who'd joined them in the cafeteria of that hospital, many of whom had friends or relatives losing fingers or their whole hand, or who had got heavily injured just a week before. She, apparently, was happy to sit in a bubble of imagined safety, waiting until the world collapsed around her.

It didn't matter. The captain would end her shift soon, and then he would be the commanding officer, as long as he didn't breathe a word of his plans. He would, naturally, have access to the coordinates for the wizardly presence. And then – well, they had been given explicit orders from the Major to arm responsible elements of the general population. The captain might not be happy with his insubordination to her, but once she woke up, she'd be too late to do anything about it.

In the end, Harry simply decided to keep watch. He could push himself to stay awake until 4am, go back in time six hours, sleep under the invisibility cloak Dumbledore had given him, and then stay awake for the rest of the night. If Tom Riddle came near, Harry would know by the feeling of Doom. It wasn't much of a protection, and he'd be a little sleep-deprived, but he felt better for guarding the students all the same.

First, however, he needed to discuss with his parents.

He found the both of them with a group of students playing Hints. "Mum, Dad, can I talk to you in private for a bit?"

They immediately followed him. "What's wrong, Harry?"

Harry cast a silencing barrier. "I don't know how safe the two of you are here. I had you brought to Hogwarts because it was pretty well protected, but what Flitwick and the older years are setting up here doesn't come anywhere close. It may be better if the two of you actually go to Canada."

"No." Surprisingly, it was Mum who answered. "We're needed here, Harry."

Harry blinked. "How so? What can you do?"

"We can distract the children. Keep them from panicking – a lot of them were very restless before I got them all playing games. Most of your schoolmates are really upset, and your teachers don't have the time to comfort them, or to keep them busy."

"And what is more," Dad added, "all these children have just been attacked by Muggles. Many have lost everything they had. Add that to the way we have been portrayed in that strange newspaper in the last few days... I would say the most important thing we can do right now is to stop that seed of hatred from taking root. Show them that Muggles are just like them, like your mother has been doing by being her usual loving self." He fondly wrapped an arm around his wife's waist.

Harry hesitated. His parents were right, they could do a lot of good here, but –

"Staying here might really be dangerous, though. We're in the middle of a war where all three sides may have it in for you."

Dad frowned. "If that's really true, are you planning to come with us?"

"No," Harry slumped. "I'm needed here."

Mum snorted. Dad nodded. "Then we're staying. Don't worry so much, Harry. I would say the adults have it in hand. Your teachers made a good case that it's safer here than anywhere else."

Only if you can Apparate. But it was probably true that being near Harry was a protection in itself, and so was being near Hermione, as she would be able to take care of most emergency evacuations and would not discriminate against Muggles. "All right, then."

He left his parents behind and went to find Hermione, and then to have some words with Professor Flitwick.

With a burst of flame, Hermione appeared on Platform Nine and Three Quarters.

She looked around. No evidence of Muggles nearby. Perfect.

The platform would certainly fit all the students, and since it existed in an extended magical space could not possibly be seen from satellite photos. There were weaknesses, certainly – most importantly, the barrier that separated the platform from the rest of King's Cross Station. The magic that allowed interaction with the mundane world was rooted in the barrier; it it should be destroyed, then at the very least the Air-Freshening Charms would cease working, meaning a slow suffocation for all within, while the space itself contracted until nothing remained. But that only made it a bad long-term solution. If another emergency evacuation should be necessary, the platform seemed like a pretty good bet to hide for a few hours, safely away from Muggle eyes and still inside the country, so Apparition would not be an issue.

She gave herself a little nod, and went to check the home ground of a native (and now mostly dead) tribe in the Amazon as a second backup location.

Magical lanterns were conjured and hung between the trees, the last pieces of dinner eaten. The foliage overhead was enchanted to merely look thick and dark, so no passing airplanes would see anything unusual. Insects and small animals were dispelled to the edge of the ward line, which Flitwick himself drew up: a golden circle that surrounded the camp site, the basis to build heavier wards on top of. Most of the staff and the older students joined in, adding layer upon layer of protection to the wards, and setting a line of Muggle repelling charms ten meters away from the main wards. The group shielding was a work of art, with teachers awarding House points to those N.E.W.T. students adding the best protections to the shared project. Many of the younger students watched; others passed the time holding small duels or playing games with each other. The atmosphere grew a bit more relaxed; whatever may have happened to Hogwarts, everyone here was still alive, and safe.

Finally, sleeping bags were conjured, the lights extinguished, and students and staff prepared for the night. Harry sat himself down by the large tree he had selected for his later self to sleep underneath, and watched the older students who guarded the wards, staying awake to maintain the shield. Every half hour, he invisibly walked around the ward line, watching, listening.

It was well past midnight when they came.

The former Defense Professor stared in surprise at the many hundreds before him, the Muggles who had touched the detection webs he had woven in a wide circle around the campsite. He had not done this. Somehow, some way, these people had come by their own initiative.

Perhaps it wasn't surprising; many things had happened these past days that he had not set into motion directly. Attacks from wizards on Muggles and Muggles on wizards alike... It was truly a marvel how easily people allowed themselves to be manipulated. A few nudges here and there, that was all it had taken for the whole thing to take off magnificently. But how had these Muggles known to come here?

Silently, he entered the mind of one of the men and searched for answers, but he found only anger, a thirst for revenge, and a large amount of alcohol. The next three were not much better. But the fifth, at last, had a plan, and knew the exact place they were going to.

It was his own circle. The Muggle- and machinery-repelling lines, spelled to be raised when a large object passed through his detection ward. He had placed it to protect the children of Hogwarts after their flight, as they were a little too exposed for his tastes, too vulnerable for sudden attack from the air. But apparently, the wards themselves had drawn attention. He silently smirked. Perhaps he was responsible after all.

Never mind, he could stop it easily; he could kill them all before they managed to get much further, or simply knock them out, or send them away without memories of their intentions. But should he? Here was a golden opportunity. The Muggles were many, but the children of Hogwarts were trained well; if it would come to a fight, they should be able to hold their own. With losses, perhaps, but that was not unacceptable. If the worst of the risks could be averted –

His hands already held the parchment, and with a flick of his wand, a list of conditions appeared on it. Another flick, and the paper disappeared.

In another place, his servant would receive the instructions, and wait for two hours without further awareness of the outside world. Then his servant would test the conditions and give the answer to the child with the Time-Turner, who would return to the present and read it. If the answer was YES, the child would send it to him before five minutes had passed. If it was anything else, or if she found that time travel would lead to a contradiction, he would simply not receive an answer. It was the safest precaution, the best way to guarantee that his actions would not ruin his goals. If he did intercede, choosing the safe course, the conditions would almost certainly be satisfied. However, if allowing the Muggles would not affect the conditions either, if every future path was safe, then there was nothing to prevent his servant from verifying the conditions; in that case, the most likely stable time loop was one where he received a YES. If the decision to allow the Muggles to pass through would have adverse effects, then there was no stable time loop where he received a YES; most likely the time travel would not be permitted, and he would never receive an answer. Either way, he knew what to do. There was a chance of false negatives – he might be prompted to interfere when there was no need to, if Time caused issues – but an answer that it was safe would always mean that it was safe.

A new parchment appeared in his hands, with a large capitalized YES written on it.

The former Defense Professor smiled a cold smile and lifted his wards.

Filius Flitwick was roused by a hand on his shoulder and a whispered voice. "Professor, I think there's people nearby."

"You don't need to whisper," Harry Potter's voice spoke impatiently from not too far away. "We're behind a one-way silencing barrier, remember? And is there any reason why we wouldn't want to wake everyone up?"

Filius was already wide awake and casting a number of sense-improvement charms: augmented listening, dark vision, far sight. He shushed his students and turned his senses outwards. There were people there – many! They were dressed in dark clothes, many with hoods, and carrying items Filius did not recognize.

"Where are they?" A man asked in a low voice.

"Invisible no doubt," another voice sneered. "Try checking whether there's stuff you don't see."

"Hey, look over there!"

Squinting to see even with his magically improved eyesight, Filius found what the men had seen and his breath choked. Beneath the moonlight glinted a tiny fragment of silver, a fraction of a line; a small part of the foundation of the Muggle repelling wards which had not been cast carefully, and had been overlooked by the warding group.

"Oh yes, we're at the right place all right!"

Filius muted his extra senses and turned to his anxious students. "They're looking for us."

This was bad. The outer warding circle, since it was the largest and furthest away from the people maintaining its magic, was very light. It would have kept unsuspecting Muggles from coming too near the campsite, but unfortunately it did not seem like the word unsuspecting applied to these people.

"WAKE UP EVERYONE," Harry Potter's Sonorus-strengthened voice reverberated over the campsite. "HAVE YOUR WAND READY. BUT STAY PUT."

"Do you want everyone panicking?" A sixth-year student nearby snapped at him as people all around jolted awake and questions of "what?" and fearful crying sounded everywhere.

Harry Potter just shrugged. "I want them to be prepared."

Filius wasn't going to spend time on the argument. "Sixth and Seventh Years!" He shouted in a tone of command. "Reinforce the wards!"

He focused his hearing outwards again.

"I... How did I... Where am I..."

"They've done something here to confuse you, and make you want to go away. Chill."

Whamm! An explosive of some kind had been thrown and gone right through the Muggle repellers, landing on the forest ground and lighting up the area in a burst of flame. Filius yelped and canceled the hearing charms, then quickly healed his ears. The explosive hadn't hit the wards – the ten meter distance had been a very good idea, even if it did cost more magical energy to maintain it like that – but nearby, several young children started crying loudly.

"Miss Granger," Professor McGonagall spoke clearly, over the terrified sounds from the students. "You have explored alternative areas for evacuation, haven't you?"

"Yes Professor," Hermione Granger said from somewhere nearby. "Platform Nine and Three Quarters should work pretty well."

"Go check it out. Children, group up. Young children together, I want you out first. Older students, do not abandon the shield. We should have plenty of time to get everyone out of here."

Boom! Crash!

The smell of petrol filled the air and smoke pricked his eyes, even as the fire sizzled out quickly. Some of the Muggles had managed to hit the shield with some kind of fireworks. They might not be able to look directly at their target due to the Notice-Me-Not enchantments, but they could figure out roughly what the line was that they couldn't pass, and simply aim right ahead from there. The campsite was large enough to be hit by such a strategy. But Minerva was right; their shield was powerful, the Muggle weapons nowhere near strong enough. With this many people pouring their strength into the wards, nothing that wouldn't also kill all the Muggles around them had a chance of penetrating it. Magical attackers might have tried other tricks, but Muggle abilities were too limited, in variation if not in power.

Filius smiled confidently as he fed more magic into the shield.

With a burst of flame, Hermione appeared on Platform Nine and Three Quarters.

It took her a moment to register the human figures all around the platform, the soldier uniforms, and then it was already too late to react. She heard the blasts of gunshots even as she felt a sharp pain in her stomach, side and chest, and then someone cursed and another voice shouted "stop!"–

With a faint feeling of longing to just go home, she fell down on the stone ground, the pain starting to numb as the blood streamed out of her body and all sounds turned to a distant buzz. She didn't even feel the flames engulf her as she sank into darkness.

Explosions were coming from all directions. More and more Muggles were collecting just outside the edges of the wards, hundreds of them.

Harry was tensing up. Where was Hermione? She was supposed to have been back in about ten seconds, but she'd been gone for several minutes now. The younger. students had been neatly divided into year-groups, each year split into two or three. That was one comfort: at least his army was near him. But the greater situation was getting more and more worrying. Harry wasn't sure whether he should be more anxious about what might be happening that could hold up Hermione or about the rest of them, but the simple fact was that the evacuation plans were all centered on Hermione and Xare. If for whatever reason they were inconvenienced, the students would have to use side-along Apparition, which was difficult because most of the people capable of doing that were needed to maintain the shield. Nor could they go after Hermione without at least a few powerful wizards available, and the teachers would probably prioritize the many over the one right now.

There was one obvious solution. End it quickly. Then they could get the hell out of here and launch a rescue mission, if Hermione still hadn't come back.

"Be ready," he said out loud. "You only need one hand to hold your neighbor by the shoulder. Keep your wand in the other. Pass the word, make sure everyone's prepared for battle, as long as they keep holding on to each other."

"Who died and made you the boss?" A second-year nearby asked.

"No one did," Harry said calmly. "But I don't think any of the teachers has ever led a battle. Those who fought in the last war all followed Dumbledore, and he's not here right now."

"Eh, I wouldn't be so worried," Ron muttered from somewhere nearby. "That shield's going to hold for a while."

"It costs you nothing to have your wand ready," Seamus snapped at him. "Are you thinking of something, Harry?"

"We can't just sit and wait while they whittle away at our wards," Harry answered. "They're bound to try something smarter sooner or later. We stop them before they do that."

Dean, who was also standing near him, frowned. "Do you know whether the shield lets our spells through?"

"Not right now," Harry shook his head. He had checked this with Flitwick some hours ago. The Charms Professor had explained that they were using a version of Protego Maximus, which protected from most kinds of attacks and spell fire, but was fully symmetric: anything that could go in, could go out. The students could make it so that no spells were blocked, but this would leave the group exposed to hostile wizards. So Harry had suggested to use two layers of Protego, one with protection from spells and the other without. "But Flitwick and the others can drop the layer that blocks spells, keeping us protected from anything Muggles can throw at us while we will be able to curse them at leisure."

"Or we just use Killing Curses," a nearby Slytherin suggested. "I bet they go through the shield."

That was, in fact, the first point Harry had thought about, but he wasn't going to mention that. "No. We don't want to give them an extra reason to start trying to kill us, and it would cost far more magical energy than a Somnium. I'm going to talk with the Professors. Just keep your wands out, okay? And see that everyone else knows that, too."

He struggled away from the mass of bodies and looked around for Professor Flitwick.

"Potter! Why are you not holding hands?"

Harry looked up in Professor McGonagall's face.

"Hermione hasn't returned, Professor," he said, ignoring the hot ball of fear in his chest at saying those words. "We have to end this, quickly. The attackers seem to be entirely non-magical; they have weapons but no defenses. We should be able to take them all down in five minutes without any casualties. We can drop the spell-ward and mass-Somnium the lot."

Professor Flitwick came hurrying over, apparently having overheard the conversation. "I was just thinking it might be best to go on the offense, Mr. Potter! Massed spell fire will not hit all the attackers, but it will make them more hesitant to come close, I think."

"We don't even need to hit many," Harry shrugged. "Just leave them there long enough so their friends can see that they're still alive. Then summon some of the bodies. That should stop the others from throwing more explosives, as they would hit their friends before they would hurt us. And then we can nego..ti..ate..." He trailed off, suddenly realizing that the sound of explosions had stopped.

In the distance, outside the wards, a single man had managed to pass through the Muggle-repelling barrier; thrown, apparently, by three tall men behind him. The man's frantic scream cut off as they turned to look at him, and he shook, but composed himself, and scrambled up from the ground. A tall, muscular man, he looked imposing as he spoke: "Come forward, then, if you're hiding there."

A complete silence was his only response. Even inside the wards, conversation stopped as everyone turned to listen to the man.

"You murder our people," the man spoke with a passionate hatred in his voice. "You corrupt our leaders. You torture and mutilate our children. This is going to end tonight!"

"Filius, if this goes wrong, you're in charge," Professor McGonagall said quietly.

"Wha–"

With a *crack* of Apparition, Professor McGonagall disappeared, and reappeared outside the wards.

"Ah," the man sneered. "At last you dare to show your face."

"Your anger is misplaced, sir," Professor McGonagall said feelingly, "There is no one here but seven hundred school children and a handful of teachers. We were forced to evacuate when our school was bombed. We mean you no harm."

"Children?" The man repeated incredulously, even as a few of the distant shadows stirred. "So your kind starts young, too? What did they teach in that school of yours, murder and torture?"

"Disable the Disillusionment and the Notice-Me-Not," Professor Flitwick commanded. "They are managing to target us anyway. Try not to look too combat-ready, everyone."

With a ripple in the air, the dome became visible. Several people behind the Muggle-repelling line jumped in shock.

"Bulbali", McGonagall cast, shooting three bulbs of light in the air, which stayed there. The bulbs lit up the area, casting Muggle and Magical in a yellow-white light so all could see the students clearly.

"Children," she repeated. "No, we don't teach them to murder or torture. They learn to make healing draughts, for example, or transfiguring one object into another, or charms to move items they cannot carry."

"Those are supposed to be children?" The man snorted. "They look like they're about to shoot us. And we all know that your kind can look like whatever they want to look like!"

"You are seeing only what you want to see," Professor McGonagall said sharply. "These are children, almost all the magical children between eleven and seventeen in our country. They're our hope for a better future!"

"No," the man bit. "They're our future enemies. If those are real children, which is a big if, they're just the next generation of our enemies." He turned to the people behind him. "Don't you see the murder in their eyes? Those supposed children are little monsters, set to grow up just like their parents! I say kill them before they get the chance!"

There was cheering and roaring behind him, and all around the now-visible campsite, but Harry thought he also saw quite a few people shifting. Not everyone was comfortable fighting children, and not all of those people could make themselves believe that the students were only pretending to be children. But there were many who still looked eager, their faces now lit up by the glowing orbs, looking out over the children; many cheering, egging each other on. Too many. The children did look battle-ready, Harry supposed. There hadn't been enough time from McGonagall's snap-decision to try talking to the Muggles to get all the students looking terrified and maybe crying. But the Muggles were also riled up, mob-spirit overriding rational thought.

"We are not your enemies!" Professor McGonagall exclaimed. "Some witches and wizards do evil, yes, but that's just the worst of us, just like the worst Muggles hurt other people. Most of us are not like that, most of us just want peace. Magic is so much more than what you've seen! It can be used for so much good!"

"And yet you don't!" The man yelled. He was beyond reason. "Where are the wizards protecting people? Where are the healers? If magic can be used for that, it's all the more unforgivable that you just kill and maim and torture!"

"Drop the outer Protego layer," Professor Flitwick commanded behind the wards. "Be ready everyone. Just don't let them see you casting, and do not attack until I say so."

"We are not all like that!" Professor McGonagall exclaimed again. "Our people can live together, we do not need to fight!"

The man smiled humorlessly. "Oh, but we do. You see, we have no intention of letting your kind rule over us." With that, he pulled a grenade from his pocket, tore out the pin, and threw it at her. Her wand flicked upwards and the explosive flew into the air, away from humans, where it exploded harmlessly. But the action left her open and in that same moment, three more bottles were flung at her from the distant repelling line, and slammed into the woman even as Harry – standing right behind her inside the wards – yelled an inaudible warning.

Flames exploded around her body, reaching high like a bonfire before she collapsed, because she had not shielded up before leaving the wards. Harry looked up in shock as the man pulled a gun and shot repeatedly at the burning body to make sure she was really dead.

"Take this as a warning," the man yelled. "You are not undefeatable, and we will not accept your superiority!"

Harry just stared at him, and at the people behind him, still bathed in light from the bulbs which had been Minerva McGonagall's last magic. The man was shouting something more, and Flitwick was yelling to reactivate the Disillusionment, but it passed Harry by as he looked at the mass of people in a wave of disbelief. And in that moment, finally watching the Muggles closely in full light, he noticed that many of them were holding the same peculiar shapes in their hands. He squinted, and his heart sank when he saw what the items were.

Gas masks.

In a rush of insight he realized that while the smoke from the Molotov Cocktails, grenades and fireworks that still clung to the air hadn't penetrated deeply into the camp site, it had managed to pass through the wards, and that the Muggles would have seen that when the Disillusionment was lifted. And he realized that he could smell gasoline and burning, even though all the explosions had happened outside the wards. The shield blocked objects and probably liquids, but it was clearly permeable to gases.

"Bubbleheads!" He screamed, at the same time the man yelled "Now!". His wand snapped up. "Sonorus! CAST BUBBLEHEADS! Bublio!" Behind the speaker, people jumped into motion and sudden blasts rang through the night sky.

Hermione woke up with the taste of blood in her mouth. She felt a little faint, but not hurt. She was lying on something hard and wet... the floor?

She opened her eyes and the world spun a moment, but there was Xare, sitting on her chest, her eyes looking wet. The bird gave a soft caw and fluttered up.

Where am I?

She sat up and looked around, thoughts coming sluggishly at first. Was this... her parents' house? How had she got here?

The platform... The soldiers... As memory returned slowly, she felt queasy. She was sure she had been very close to death. Xare must have taken her to safety, healed her...

The forest! How long had she been unconscious? The clock said it was five past two, but what time had it been when she left?

With a jump, Hermione was on her feet, Xare on her arm in the same instant. Get us back!

Almost none of the older years got the Bubblehead Charm off before the tear gas grenades hit.

Harry watched, helpless to do anything, as the shield just evaporated, the people maintaining it no longer able to concentrate as they were doubling over, coughing, choking. The next volley of tear gas grenades fell all over the camp site, where maybe one in ten of the remaining students had managed to cast a Bubblehead Charm, and then another rain of explosives hit, this time not blocked. "Prismatis!"

The timely prismatic wall took the hit, but Harry was flung to the ground by the impact, the breath knocked from his body. Dizzy for some moments, he finally lifted his head from the ground to look at what was happening around him.

The sight that met his eyes was one he would never forget.

Broken bodies were scattered across the ground. How many were merely unconscious, how many had died in that instant? Wizards and witches could take more than Muggles, their bodies' natural magic preventing the worst injuries, but there were limits, even with purely mundane damage. Men (and women?) in gas masks ran through the chaos; the Muggle repelling line must have fallen along with the rest. Some had brought guns and were firing at the many wounded, others were throwing explosives. Children were screaming in pain, others merely flailing around on the ground, coughing and choking. Others were still up, Bubblehead Charms active. surrounded by Protego shields or Prismatic Spheres. There was a glimpse of golden fire in the distance – Hermione? Curses were flying around, the attackers falling where they stood, but they were too many. It was the chaos of battle, as half the school had been training in for most of the year, but this time it was lethal, and not everyone had been part of an army. Children, their black robes charred or burning, were falling, or blasted away by all kinds of explosives. Fires were spreading from tree to tree, burning those who had been knocked out, or who were too heavily wounded to move. Blood spilled out in liters, and in the distance someone screamed a word:

"Avada Kedavra!"

The small part of Harry that wasn't screaming at the sight realized that the attackers were never going to survive this. They didn't know what they were dealing with, so they had made assumptions and stupidly thought that they could win an actual battle against an unknown foe, where the other side had magic. Too many of the older students already wore bubbleheads, and they had shields that could withstand anything that wouldn't also kill the people nearby, and Professor Quirrell had taught them the Killing Curse, and they had seen their friends die in front of their eyes and could easily summon up the hatred required...

Do these people deserve to die?

Harry honestly didn't know. These were child-murderers and bigoted vigilantes proud in their ignorance, but they were also fathers and brothers who were frightened and might believe that they were just doing what was necessary. One thing was certain, though. If this massacre ended with all the attacking Muggles dead, it would become very hard to achieve peace.

He jumped up.

"Sonorus! DO NOT KILL THEM! IT WILL ONLY MAKE THINGS WORSE! ARMIES, WORK TOGETHER! USE BUBBLE-HEADS! Finite."

There was a moment where the curses stopped, and Muggle heads turned to look around for the source of the sound. And then other voices went up in the brief silence.

"Pinini Army, to me!"

"Mighty Bulls!"

"Gryffindors, protect the fallen!"

"Expecto Patronum!"

"Hetero Protego!"

A shimmering blue sphere appeared around Harry just as another explosion hit, and he was thrown backwards, saved only by the powerful shield some anonymous student had cast on him at the last moment. His body hurt like hell – had he broken bones in his back? – and he didn't think he could stand up anymore, so he just kept lying there. Just a few moments. There were more screams around, he heard, more choking and gasping, still more explosions. But there were also curses, and there was co-ordination. Children were working together with each other now, applying everything Professor Quirrell had taught them...

Draco was coughing, retching; his eyes burned, his throat was on fire. He'd dropped his wand somewhere, but he couldn't see, so he couldn't cast –

"Karete Rif. Bublio."

Instantly, his eyes cleared and a bubble appeared over his head. He blinked and looked up, seeing a fourth- or fifth-year Hufflepuff girl who was already moving away, running towards the next spluttering student.

His wand! Draco looked down and located it quickly. Now he could –

Blam! Draco's head snapped to the left where, not six feet away, a Muggle was shooting some kind of Muggle wand at the already falling body of the Hufflepuff.

No. This can't be happening. This can't be real.

With a smooth motion, the Muggle turned his black wand to Draco.

"Prismatis!" Draco reacted by sheer reflex just as another loud bang! emanated from the Muggle's wand, and something bounced off the prismatic shield.

"Somnium! Prismatis!" A girl's voice. In the chaos of the battle, he hadn't seen Padma approach, but now she was standing right next to him, extending his shield.

"It won't hold for the bigger explosions," she panted, "but I don't think they'll dare do that, with their own people running around here."

Draco didn't respond. He was still staring at the Hufflepuff, who was slowly bleeding out on the ground. And now that he was looking, he saw more bodies strewn around the forest ground. He felt sick to the core.

"Snap out of it, General!" Padma bit. "We need to regroup, get more people behind the shield."

It was the "General" that did it. Draco breathed deeply and nodded. This was not the time to be in shock. Fortunately, he had almost a year of training to fall back on. He looked around, forcing himself not to stare at the fallen.

"Bones!" He yelled, spotting the first-year behind a tree nearby. "Cover us. Padma, retreat to that oak!"

Neville was backed against a tree, three Muggles approaching with some kind of metal thing they were using as a shield. His prismatic shield had blocked the first shots they'd aimed at him, but now one of them was holding some small metal ball. He didn't know what it was, but it couldn't be good.

There was nothing for it. He dropped his shield and ran towards the attackers. "Special attack, Chaotic Leap!"

He didn't know who caught him – they probably weren't chaotic legionnaires, because he was twisted sideways, like the levitation hadn't been coordinated well or was done by a single, stronger person, but it was enough. With three quick Somniums, his attackers fell down. He landed in a roll, and looked around for whoever might need his assistance.

The shimmering blue shield around Harry had disappeared long seconds ago, but Harry was already on his feet, wand in hand, ready for a Prismatis but not yet casting it; you couldn't cast spells from behind a prismatic shield, and others might need his help. There was shouting all around, but it was hard to see far through the smoke drifting everywhere. He took a tentative step, ignoring the pain in his body, looking around.

Someone grabbed him from behind and yanked his head back hard against a tree, snapping the bubble. His wand was wrested from his grip, and a gun placed against his forehead. In his last second, Harry stared into a pair of blue eyes, full of hatred...

The man collapsed. Petunia Evans-Verres was standing behind the man with a thick branch in her hands. And there was another gunshot, and she gasped, and fell heavily on the ground as blood burst from her chest, and there wasn't time to do anything, only a wish that this wasn't happening...

But this time, Harry had no Patronus to protect him, or the people he loved.

Another gunshot cracked, and the masked man who had shot at them fell over.

The normally-so-dignified Professor Verres-Evans, his clothes torn and splattered with blood threw the gun away, and limped towards his wife and child. "Petunia!"

Suddenly, a golden light filled the forest, and a will of some kind pressed down on Harry. The screams cut off abruptly, and everything froze. Father's progress stopped. The student running past Harry halted in mid-bounce.

Dumbledore.

A shrill and wonderful sound pierced the forest, as the phoenix sang its battle cry, and as the masked men fell to the ground in a surge of power, the fires went out, and the golden light crept over the ground, surrounded defenders and attackers alike, healing their wounds where it passed.

He really was the most powerful wizard in the world.

But time had slowed down, not stopped. Harry couldn't move his head, couldn't yell, couldn't cast any spell, as he watched his mother die in slow-motion.

Blood fell from her chest and mouth, at a speed of one meter per minute.

Her eyes started to widen. Her mouth started to open.

And then the golden light reached her and enveloped her; her chest healed, the bullet that hit her dropped to the ground.

But it was already too late. Her eyes continued to widen, her mouth continued to gasp, and then time resumed. A small shock ran through her body and she exhaled, just as Harry could finally move again and half-jumped half-fell to her side.

"No, Mum, please don't."

There was a small ripple of something in the air, a feeling of care and worry, of curiosity and frustration, silly giggles and gossiping and an immense amount of love, of all that she was; a ripple that was soft and almost inaudible and yet too vast to be understood, and it faded before Harry could get a grasp on it, as the light in her eyes dimmed.

No...

Michael Verres-Evans knelt down beside him, his face screwed up in agony, as he put his hand on his wife's neck. He hadn't felt it, like Harry had, but he had seen it happen.

"Please tell me magic can undo this." His voice choked.

"There is no magic that can bring back the dead," Harry intoned hollowly. "Yet."

"Maybe science can..." Michael turned his tear-streaked face to Harry. "Her brain wasn't hit, if we can get a doctor to her now –"

"We can't." Even if he found Hermione, and got her to use Xare to move Mum into an emergency room on the spot, the enmity between Muggles and wizards would mean that she was more likely to be attacked there than helped. "But I can do this." He grabbed his wand from where it still lay on the ground, leveled it at the body, and poured everything down his arm into his hand...

"Frigideiro!"

"Hypothermia?" Professor Verres breathed as Petunia's body cooled down. "Can you get it to 5 degrees exactly?"

Harry nodded. It'd been one of the spells he and Hermione had experimented with, a lifetime ago, so he was able to control it exactly. The cold would protect her from brain damage. "But I'm not sure what chance a doctor would have, even if we got her to one before she warms up."

Father hadn't felt it, the outpouring of something as she died. But Harry had.

There's something more to dying than your brain not working anymore.

"But I'll find some way of using magic to do it." He was half-speaking to himself.

"You just said that there was no magic to bring back the dead." Tears were streaking father's face.

"Yet."

"Harry, you're eleven."

"Maybe. But I'm not going to let that stop me." Harry looked into his father's eyes, his gaze turning cold. "I already did two things believed impossible, this year. I will do this too. I swear. On everything I hold sacred, I swear, I will challenge Death and bring Mum back, and my other parents too, and Professor McGonagall, and the people who died last week... Everyone."

He expected his father to protest, with all the usual too young and Petunia would not have wanted you nonsense. But the professor just shook his head sadly, and looked down at his wife's body.

"It was your voice, wasn't it?" He asked a while later. "Shouting not to kill them?"

Harry just nodded.

"And I did kill." His voice sounded pained, now, and he stared at his hands. "I'm sorry. I can't even believe I did that. If you'd asked me yesterday whether I would ever... But when I saw that man shoot at you and Petunia –"

Harry said nothing. He just hugged his father long and hard.

"You're not a child anymore." It wasn't a question, just an observation. "I don't know whether you've gone into puberty or just skipped it, but you're not who you were before. You're taking command, deciding on other people's lives. And people listen. What happened to you?"

"I grew up," Harry said simply.

They sat in silence, waiting for whatever might come next.

With a flash of phoenix fire, Dumbledore appeared by their side. He looked older than Harry had ever seen him. It took the man only a moment to take in the sight of Petunia's body, and he choked back a pained groan.

"Headmaster," Harry said icily. "Where were you, when a bomb was about to hit the school and the children in your care had to be evacuated? And where were you when a mob of crazy Muggles attacked them?"

"Later," the Headmaster bit. "Dr. Verres, can I take you elsewhere? I have no capacity to protect you better here than in another place, and I fear for what the survivors may do when they realize that there is still a Muggle among them."

"A hospital would be good," Michael Verres-Evans grunted. "She's still 5 degrees, isn't she, Harry?"

Harry nodded. He had been regularly reinforcing the Frigideiro. His father gently took the body of his wife in his arms.

"Not Britain," Harry urged. "Not anywhere where You-Know-Who would find him. Go to a dark alley or something, don't let them see you phoenix in."

"I am not a fool," Dumbledore answered harshly. "I think I have seen a bit more of war than you have, young Ravenclaw, even counting your experiences in the last week."

Harry nodded. "I had to be sure."

"You're not coming?" his father asked.

"No dad, going into the Muggle world would be suicide, even if it's not Britain. It'll be hard enough for you to explain what happened without fearing that they'll attack me. But we will see each other again. I promise."

"I love you, son..."

Then Dumbledore reached out for his arm and the two of them disappeared with a flash of fire.

Harry found Hermione and Neville together, mourning over the corpse of Hannah Abbott. The girl, apparently, had bubbled up in time, but then jumped into a fight with two of the Muggles as they were shooting at children still blinded by the tear gas.

Ron Weasley had died in a similar way, as had several other Gryffindors; too brave to stay behind and hide and leave the older students with fully functional Protego shields to protect the unconscious and blinded and sneezing students. Undoubtedly, the outcome was better because they had fought. Su had lived, because Neville had pulled her out of a fire. Cho Chang, the second-year seeker, had managed to drag herself away when Ron engaged the Muggles throwing Molotov Cocktails in her direction. Several students had been saved by Parvati's use of Aguamenti on any burning bodies she saw. The heroic students had saved many who would otherwise not have lived. But the price had been really, really high.

The battle had lasted not five minutes, but in that time, about 80 of the approximately 700 Hogwarts students had died, and two members of staff: Professor McGonagall and Professor Vector. Most of the dead students had died in the first minute of the battle, when explosives rained down just as the shield had fallen. Many had been wounded, but they lived, and would soon be well again; between two Phoenixes and magical healing, gun wounds and third-degree burns were almost trivial.

Ernie MacMillan had died. Zacharias Smith. Pansy Parkinson. Michael Corner. Ron Weasley. Hannah Abbot. Roderick Murphy. Fay Dunbar. Kate Olney. Nitin Divekar. Mildred Peebles. Terry Boot. And those were just the ones from Harry's year.

Harry fought back his tears. To cry was to give up, and he wasn't going to give up. He had promised the Demented last Monday that he would find a way, and he'd promised his father today, and he would. He would bring them all back, no matter how. Hermione hadn't frozen Hannah, and Harry had been in too much shock to think about doing it for any other casualties than his mother before it was too late, but given the impossibility to sustain the temperature for long, and the expected lack of co-operation from the families, that wasn't likely to have helped regardless. There would just have to be another way.

He sat himself down by Hermione and Neville in silence, but he didn't mourn. He thought.

"It's my fault," Hermione whispered eventually.

Harry just looked at her. "No more than it is mine."

"What are you talking about?" Neville protested. "If you hadn't dragged all those unconscious children to your parents' house it would have been far worse!"

"I was responsible," she said with a choke. "If only I hadn't been too preoccupied with escape to consider that we might have to fight! If only I'd protested when Professor McGonagall said that the most vulnerable children should be together, rather than mixed with the stronger students – I'm an army general, I should have realized that that was a lethal mistake! If only I'd thought to send my Patronus to Professor Dumbledore straight away. How could I not have thought of that? If only I'd reacted a little sooner to those soldiers, or gone to the Amazon first..."

Harry just threw an arm around her, and held her tight as she sniffled on his shoulder. He couldn't say that she shouldn't blame herself, because it would be unfair to deny her the guilt that he assigned to himself as well. But they could at least give each other some comfort.

Chapter 107: The Muggle War, Pt 5

It was mid-afternoon on Wednesday, when the children were just catching a breath after Snape had made them do a series of intense emergency escape-drills, when Harry felt a tug on his arm and thought he saw a flash of gold. Dumbledore?

He stood up and left the room, supposedly to the bathroom. In the hallway, the old wizard appeared.

"Harry, there is something crucial we need to discuss. Will you come with me to the Ministry of Magic? Now?"

"Sure," Harry shrugged. "I doubt my presence is critical to operations here."

The Headmaster grabbed his arm, and with another burst of flame, Harry reappeared in the Chief Warlock's office, where a soft, comfortable chair was already placed in front of the desk. The former Headmaster of Hogwarts himself sat down on the chair behind the desk.

"At this very moment," he spoke gravely, "a closed session of the Wizengamot is debating your emancipation. The vote will pass in about thirty minutes time, and I will be sent to collect you, so you can take your family seat and participate in further discussions."

"About time," Harry said.

Professor Dumbledore just smiled tiredly. "This is a very unusual decision, Harry. A pre-O.W.L. student filing for independence would not normally be accepted, even with the full support of their guardian. I believe it would not have been successful if not for the current crisis, and the rather favorable impression you have made recently. I have spoken of the suggestions you made yesterday – which are admittedly naive, but have the potential to be expanded on since they move in directions we had not considered before – and your request to take your family seat and be included in the discussions regarding our response to the Muggle violence. I have also made them aware that you have extensively studied the Muggle world, but stressed that you are still a noble child of a witch and a wizard. I may not have been entirely truthful in suggesting that you explicitly asked for emancipation, but I suspect that I did not misrepresent your wishes in doing so regardless."

Harry nodded. "Correct."

"Even with many of the Wizengamot realizing that your expertise could be valuable," the old wizard resumed, "the vote might not have passed if it were not for your recent trial. It has been argued that you have proved your maturity in that instance, as you had both ability and inclination to destroy the nation's prison, yet chose not to do so. For one who is to be included in the Wizengamot immediately on being recognized as an adult, it is fundamental that you have shown yourself not to be rash, as Miss Granger was in destroying the Dementors surrounding Azkaban, but understanding of a precarious political situation."

"Er... That was the worst decision of my life. Or would have been if Hermione hadn't done the job in my place."

"I would strongly suggest that you refrain from mentioning this view," the old wizard said with a smile.

"All right..." Harry said. "So why the extra thirty minutes?

The old wizard took a deep breath. "There is a little more I must prepare you for. You see, over the last few days I have not merely been trying to get you involved in the decision making process; I have been seeking to have you included as an influential member from the start. You may find that many of the more open-minded people – from all sides of the political spectrum, not merely mine – are prepared to view you not as a child but rather as a prodigy, a new player on the chess board who is almost certain to come into power before long. They will remember that you have invented two unprecedented new spells in your first year, managed to strike up a friendship with both the Malfoy and Longbottom heirs as well as a Muggleborn, and that when you last spoke before the Wizengamot, you demonstrated a greater competence than many of its members, resolving conflicts and broaching subjects which others did not dare to raise. They will also acknowledge your admirable foresight in teaching three fellow students your variation of the Patronus Charm, which helped to keep last week's tragedy in hand, and all are aware of your natural assumption of command in Monday night's battle, which may well have saved hundreds of lives. Add to that the things many of those same Lords and Ladies have learned from their children and grandchildren of your performance in school, and the dominance you seem to hold in your year... In short, I imagine that you will have a following."

Harry blinked, taking this in. "If you can run that sort of PR campaign on such a short notice, how come you're not ruling the world yet?"

The old man smiled. "I merely said you will have a following, not that everyone will follow you – not by far. And the reason these tales could be circulated into the enemy camp is that I did not advocate for you directly, nor does it seem to be help me much to gather support for you. You are an independent actor, aligned neither with myself nor my opponents, and many in the political scene are open to embracing a change of its climate and welcome fresh blood – provided, of course, the blood in question is moderately pure and clearly powerful. What is more, the foundation was already laid. You have no preexisting enemies with a motive to bring up less favorable episodes. I feared Lord Malfoy's resistance, but he has so far been remarkably silent on the issue. But do not be overconfident. Not everyone perceives you in the same light; most of the Wizengamot, I imagine, will not easily overlook your youth."

Harry nodded slowly. "That's... useful, I guess. Thank you." Since when did he get so cooperative?

"What is more," the old man continued. "Amelia Bones and a rare few others understand what I have been trying to accomplish. Should a suitable situation arise, do not be surprised if Amelia pushes for you to be given authority."

Harry paused. What?

And then he suddenly understood what the old man was doing.

"You're not helping me because you believe I will do a good job, are you?" He asked hollowly.

The old wizard met his eyes. "I do have faith in you, Harry. You have a good heart, the idealism I have long been forced to lose, and wisdom well beyond your years. But I confess that it is not the sole reason I am pushing for you to come into power earlier than you otherwise would."

"You're giving him what he wants," Harry concluded. "You're trying to get me put in charge, regardless of what I may do, so Riddle will stop interfering. You're losing."

"I know you must think me weak." The old man tore his eyes away, staring at the wall instead. "For ten long years, I have fought Voldemort. Ten years of death, loss, agony. Fighting a losing battle, and yet knowing that more people would suffer if I did not fight. Then a miracle happened and I got my reprieve, always knowing that it could not last forever. And then you came, and you told me that he had been holding back all along. That he could have won easily, had he only chosen to."

Grief crossed the old face. "People are dying once more, in greater numbers than before, and it will only get worse. For all my efforts, I have no hope of stopping this war; I can only futilely try to mitigate its damage. I cannot bear it anymore, Harry! If we have no hope of winning regardless, will it not be better to lose quickly, rather than sacrificing numerous lives to only stall the inevitable?"

"I see," breathed Harry. And he did see. He had given the former Headmaster an out, the idea that perhaps he could just give up and stop fighting, and the world would be no worse for it. And it might even be true.

"I expect that, if you should manage to come into power," the old wizard continued, "you will not attempt to subjugate Muggles. Nor do I expect that –" he trailed off. "Come in!"

The door opened and Mad-Eye Moody strode into the room. He turned his face to look at Professor Dumbledore, who nodded and started casting a number of wordless spells. Finally, he turned back to Harry.

"Before we carry on, there is one test we must try, Harry. Alastor?"

"Imperio."

It was the most wonderful feeling. Harry felt a floating sensation as every thought in his mind was wiped away, leaving nothing but a vague, untraceable happiness.

(Yet somewhere inside him, something struggled for attention.)

UNTIE YOUR SHOELACES, a voice in his head said. It wasn't any of the usual voices, but it carried such a tone of command, that his brain almost unquestionably sent the command to his hands to obey.

No! said a small voice inside him. Harry's hand halted. Where does that voice come from? It is not me!

UNTIE YOUR SHOELACES the voice of God repeated in his head.

I normally wouldn't just follow random voices in my head, the small voice repeated, almost inaudible but persistent. I would question where they came from. What has changed between then and now?

Oh, I don't know, maybe the part where the ex-Auror guy pointed his wand at us and said Imperio? Harry recognized the new voice as his Slytherin side speaking.

Oh. Right.

With a rush of disorientation, thought returned to Harry's consciousness. He gasped as the dreamlike state lifted. That had been weird, listening to his own thought processes as an outsider.

"What –"

"He's done it, Albus."

"I can see that. Thank you Alastor. And Harry, I am sorry, but before we proceed with the plan to steer you towards a position of influence, I had to know what would happen if you were placed under the Imperius Curse."

"You just – !"

The man looked grim. "I do apologize for violating your free will, but if we succeed, and you come into a position of influence, we cannot have you controlled by Voldemort or some other powerful wizard. Fortunately, the Imperius Curse does not become much stronger as the caster's power grows. If you can resist Alastor, especially without mental preparation, you can resist anyone. I hope you understand the need, and why I did not ask for your consent."

Harry breathed deeply, once, twice. He did understand. And given that Moody had done nothing worse than trying to make him untie his shoelaces, he really didn't have a proper reason to feel overly offended about it.

"Isn't that illegal?"

"Yes, it is, which is why we are doing this now, as opposed to when you go before the Wizengamot. I hardly think you are likely to report us."

Given how much blackmail material you have on me, Headmaster, that's kind of a given.

"How does Amelia Bones feel about your doing this? She's in on your plans, isn't she?"

"Partially," the man nodded. "Her main incentive to follow my suggestion of leading you into influence is to lay a trap for Voldemort, actually. She believes that if we can bring him out into the open, her Aurors may have a chance to overpower him."

"Good luck with that," Harry muttered. In the corner, Mad-Eye snorted. "Don't underestimate Amelia."

"To answer your question," Dumbledore spoke, "she does not officially know what I am doing, and is wise enough not to ask. The Imperius Curse is illegal, even for testing and teaching purposes, and even with consent. There are good reasons for that, although yes, I rather believe that an exception is warranted in this case. However, I feel that I should mention that your success was entirely probable; anyone who knows you and understands the spell would have expected you to be able to resist. It takes a certain force of personality and rejection of authority, which you possess in abundance. In truth, my fear was not so much that you would be unable to resist, but rather that it would pass control to... certain parts of you."

Ah. If his dark side had been a separate entity, it did make some sort of sense that when his consciousness got discoupled from his thoughts, his dark side might take over. But it wasn't, and it hadn't. Regardless...

"How do you know that that's not what happened?"

"Because the spell was lifted from you, as Alastor sensed. Besides, you do not now seem to be the persona you were in January, when the Dementor reduced you to the coldest, darkest part of yourself." He did not mention Harry's dark side explicitly, Harry noticed. Moody had probably not been told about that particular detail. Which was a flaw, as Moody might well be able to figure out the horcrux thing, but Harry wasn't going to bring it up.

""I see," he said instead. "And, forgive my asking, but are you sure it was lifted from me? I mean, I think I'm fine again, but I don't have that much experience with the Imperius Curse, and maybe that's just what he wants me to think. I'm surprised you trusted him to Imperius me, honestly." Moody just grinned. That was one good thing about the paranoid ex-Auror: he would never be offended by such an accusation.

The Former Headmaster smiled, with a glance at his friend. "I am certain the spell was lifted from you, Harry, because you can see that in the eyes the moment it happens. And I had to rely on him, since I cannot cast the spell myself. It was the safest option. Alastor cannot be controlled with the Imperius Curse, and I tested him beforehand for all disguises known to man. He insisted that I do, in fact."

"At least you're thinking properly," Moody growled. "That makes this whole mess a tiny bit less of a disaster. And it's time. Take him away, Albus. I'll see myself out."

Harry stood before the greatest people of the country, thinking what a stupid little man Cornelius Fudge, the Minister of Magic, seemed to be.

"Mr. Potter," the Minister of Magic was saying in formal tones. "A select group of representatives of the Wizengamot have reached the decision to honor your request for emancipation and recognize you as an adult. This means you will assume formal leadership of your house: you will be known as Lord Potter, have full access to your family vault, and may assume your family's seat in the Wizengamot. You will also be held fully responsible for your actions, and judged as an adult for any crimes you should commit. Do you accept?"

"I do," Harry answered in an equally formal tone. As long as that crime judging part is not retro-active.

"Welcome then, Lord Potter," boomed the Chief Warlock. "Feel free to take a seat. We shall have suitable robes made for you within three days."

Harry carefully climbed up the half-circles, noting how much space was free. Many of the Wizengamot must already have left the country, and it might not be easy to get back on a regular basis. He carefully selected a place right in the middle of the room, away both from Dumbledore's and Malfoy's camp. Everyone will know that that is a sign.

"Now that this pointless interlude is settled," a man on the Malfoy side spoke, "perhaps we can finally get back to debating the current crisis."

"Of course, Mr. Nember," the Chief Warlock nodded. "But please do recall that we agreed to debate Lord Potter's emancipation due to its relevance to the... other situation. Lord Potter might bring a key voice to the debate."

The man snorted, but abated.

"May I ask," Harry said. "Exactly what the current status is? I was not briefed before being brought here."

"We have confirmation from Sarissa Johnson that not the Muggle government, but rather high-ranked figures in their military were responsible for Monday's events," Madam Bones answered. "Military-grade equipment has been handed out to civilians all over the country, and there have been various attacks. We have contacted the Prime Minister, but he called for security and we deemed it more diplomatic to leave. It also does not seem likely that the man has any hold over his people. The Wizengamot have been debating a response, but so far no resolution has been reached."

"That is to say," a man Harry did not know by name spoke up, "For some unfathomable reason we are still debating whether to pander to those child-murderers, or show them what it means to put yourself against wizards."

"You are unreasonable, Lord Usto!" Dumbledore spoke loudly. "You would punish the many for the actions of the few. In relative terms, a mere handful of Muggles have assaulted wizards. Most Muggles just want to live their lives in peace. Most, I daresay, would not even approve of the actions of those you view as their representatives."

"So our real ire should be aimed at those Muggles you conveniently sent off abroad, is what you're saying," Lord Usto bit. "The ones with their hands on the blade, those are the ones you gave back to their own kind, where undoubtedly they are now feasting and celebrating their victory. If anything, they should have been cut open in front of their families as an example! Since they are beyond our reach now, I say we pick their family and neighbors for punishment."

"There is no purpose in revenge!" The Chief Warlock exclaimed. "Our kind have already taken thrice as many Muggle lives as they have taken ours, in the last two days alone!"

"Well, that's nothing, is it?" Another man – Lord Jugson, if Harry remembered correctly – piped up. "A wizard is easily worth a hundred Muggles!"

"This is pointless," another man on the Malfoy side spoke up. "We are not in a position to exact revenge. Beasts though they may be, they hold power that I would not have imagined possible."

"They won't be able hurt us if we kill the lot of them first, Mr. McWillen."

"There are sixty million Muggles in Britain alone," Madam Bones spoke impatiently. "Even if the idea of killing them all would not be morally repugnant, we do not have the resources to achieve it."

"But as I said before," the toad-woman sitting next to Minister Fudge said in a falsely sweet tone, "we can simply subvert their government first, and then set an example."

"We've gone over this several times," Madam Longbottom spoke dismissively. "The Muggle government doesn't have much control over their people at the moment, and will have even less control if the people see wizards controlling them."

"So we replace them," a woman on Dumbledore's side spoke up. "Set up a new government, and enforce law and order. We do not need to hurt them, as long as they stay in their place."

"You are being wantonly naive, Madam," the man called McWillen spoke up. "They will resist such a rule if it is not achieved with their consent, and their resistance will be bloody. If anything, the last days should have demonstrated that they are willing and able to cause a lot of trouble for us."

Toad-woman gave a fake giggle. "Surely you're not suggesting Muggles can really hurt a competent witch or wizard when they're prepared for it? I mean, a dog can bite an unsuspecting wizard, but surely you wouldn't claim that they could do anything to an adult – let alone a whole country! – who knows what they can do?"

Harry decided that this was a good point to step in. He stood up. "You don't know what they can do."

"We have seen a fair few of their attacks, Mister... I mean, Lord Potter," one of the men responded. "At close range, they can use confringo-like effects and summon smoke, but they have very little versatility. I will admit that their large-scale weapons are fearsome, but as long as we remain in their own cities, near their own citizens, they cannot use them."

"Professor Flitwick said a similar thing, Monday night," Harry said kindly, "This was right before the Muggles surprised us with a volley of tear gas. So far they have figured out only a few things they could use against us, and those they use over and over, but it will not be long before they realize all the other possibilities they possess that could hurt us. I would also like to note that nobody in this room seems to be wearing bubbleheads, so we are clearly not so perfectly prepared even for the things we already know they can do."

"The Wizengamot is very well protected!" Toad-woman snapped. "Muggles couldn't get down here, the very idea!"

"Exactly how sure of that are you?" Harry threw back. "They clearly know where the Ministry is, and the Wizengamot is connected to it. Even if the wards keep out Muggles, would Merlin have thought to block robots? They only need to get a hose down here to take us out."

Some people looked uncomfortable, but Amelia Bones shook her head. "Even if they were able to penetrate the Ministry, they would not manage to do it without detection. My people will give warning immediately when something threatening appears."

"What's a robot?" Someone else asked. "Do they have more dangerous magics?"

"Technology," Dumbledore corrected.

"Yes they do," Harry answered. "And if they do not, they soon will." He looked around, making sure he had everyone's attention. "My Lords and Ladies," (that seemed to be the right way to address the group) "I hope I do not offend anyone if I point out that there is a flaw in your perception. You see Muggles, and think of them as witches or wizards without the magic. In this view, they are reduced to helpless creatures, as handicapped as a witch or wizard would be if they lost their magic. But they have never known magic, and this is not the way they see themselves. Muggles grow up in a completely different way from us. Where we mostly study existing spells, Muggle technology was almost entirely developed in the last century. Muggles learn to invent, and adapt. There are hundreds of Muggle inventions that could be creatively used against us, and it only takes one person to think of them."

"I find that hard to believe," Minister Fudge protested.

"It is a fact," Harry said simply. "If any of you have children who have watched or participated in the first-year 'armies', ask them just how much different such things like a car battery or ball bearings can make."

"Against first-year magic, maybe," Lord Usto said dismissively. "But that's hardly impressive."

Bellatrix Black was broken out of Azkaban with the help of Muggle technology. Harry thought it, but it wouldn't be safe to bring it up. Instead, he shrugged. "I could only use what a first-year could transfigure. Muggles, however, are not restrained by having to transfigure everything themselves, which means that they are allowed to use liquids and gases, and can use far more advanced equipment and potentially lethal weapons. Do not underestimate them. It will be the last thing you do."

"This is much like I have been saying all along," a man near the middle spoke. "If we go to war, we can only lose. Even if – if! – we should manage to defeat the Muggles, they will not give up. It is nigh impossible to hold an underground resistance in check, and even if we can, how many resources will we not have to expend on keeping them in line?"

"War is bad for business," a woman agreed. "If we can put these hostilities behind us, with the Statute of Secrecy ended, we will be able to engage in a mutually beneficial trade. I would rather monetize the opportunities this creates than spend money and effort fighting a foe we can control through market forces."

"What do they have to offer us?" Another man sneered dismissively. "Food, perhaps, and some precious minerals. But if we enslave them, we can simply set them to working the land and the mines! You're over-thinking how hard it is to keep a bunch of Muggles in check. We'll just employ a small number of Legilimenses to randomly test them for ill intent towards wizards, and execute the rebellious ones!"

"You will be forever killing if you do so," Dumbledore spoke sternly. "For surely the act of executing innocents who have merely committed crimes in their thoughts will itself cause more rebelliousness."

"At first, perhaps," the first speaker shrugged. "But I cannot see this cycle lasting long. There are plenty of people who would be cowed by such methods, and we don't really have a use for more than a small fraction of the Muggles currently alive in Britain."

Arguments flared up again, as the morality and practicality of enslaving and possibly killing millions of people was debated with vehemence. Harry kept silent. It wouldn't be good politics to immediately try to dominate the conversation, and the arguments didn't seem to be going anywhere, so he could afford to sit this part out. Instead, he quietly considered the best formulation of his next point while waiting for an opportune moment to bring it up.

"Before we continue debating what to do after we win our hypothetical war," a man whom the others referred to as "Mr. Deas" spoke firmly, "we should ask Lord Potter what exactly he meant not to underestimate them." He turned to Harry. "What other weapons can they employ against us?"

"All kinds of things," Harry answered promptly. "A flashbang – that's a kind of explosive that can blind and deafen you at the same time – might well break even a competent wizard's concentration. Ball bearings will complicate movement, and a wizard could be lured into a pit trap – most wizards don't carry around a broomstick to get themselves out. We can avoid breathing gases with a Bubblehead Charm, but that charm only covers the head, and there are noxious gases which hurt the skin. Explosives also don't need to be thrown, they can be buried as mines, or you trap a building and then blow it up once you get a few wizards inside. Also, electricity will put stress on a shield – I actually tested that in the first army battle we had this year – and once the Muggles figure that one out, they will definitely weaponize it. And that's not even going into things like lasers or electromagnetic radiation. Some of those things may not be practical with the equipment the average Muggle keeps around the house, nor even available to the military right now, but I guarantee you that the technology will get developed very quickly once Muggles figure out that it can be used. In fact, there's probably some secret labs already working on them, both here and in other countries."

Rattling off all the possibilities felt remarkably like his first Defense class this year. In fact... "Oh, and before I forget about the defensive side, we already know that metal armor will stop low-level spells. I strongly suspect that better materials can be developed that will hold out against almost everything, and you don't want to start throwing too many Unforgivable Curses around. Also, it's not just direct combat you should be picturing here – they might well employ things like poisons or, if the situation gets desperate enough, perhaps even suicide commands. There's more than a thousand Muggles for every witch or wizard, after all."

There was a shocked silence as he finished, and several people looked distinctly green.

"Surely," a woman eventually said, "now that we know about these things, we can guard against them?"

Harry grimaced. "These were just the first ideas that came to my mind, Madam. I suspect it is not even half of what a competent military commander could come up with. Also, although I claim a fair amount of expertise because I have studied the possibilities of the Muggle world extensively, I am only eleven. I never had access to military science laboratories and my knowledge of physics is rudimentary. I cannot even guess at what scientists may invent in, say, a year time, especially if they have access to a witch or wizard to test with."

"But how would they get –"

"Mudbloods," a man near Lord Malfoy spat. "And blood traitors. They might well sell us out."

"We can keep an eye on them, surely?" Another asked, voice wavering.

"Unlikely," Amelia Bones said with a frown. "It takes only one person willing to cast their faith with the Muggles, either due to bribes, conflicting loyalties or simply mistreatment by the magical world – I do not personally know any Muggleborn who I believe would willingly engineer the destruction of our kind, but I know of many who would have every earthly reason to do so. And do not forget that it wouldn't need to be a British person. Muggles do possess near-instant globe-wide communication methods."

A deep, painful silence followed these words. Harry decided that this was a good moment to lead into his point, before the others started trying to rationalize their preconceived ideas again.

"Look," he spoke clearly, standing up. "I think we've been trying to answer the wrong question here." (It definitely seemed like a good idea to use we instead of you, so he wouldn't be seen as setting himself against the more senior Wizengamot members.) "We can debate all day whether it is moral to attempt to conquer the Muggle world, but we will never agree on that point. Let us instead ask whether it is expedient. To that, I think we can all agree, the answer is an unequivocal no. Even in the unlikely event that we could win a war in Britain, it would be at the price of massive bloodshed on both sides – would that be worth it? And then the other countries would respond. They have nuclear weapons too!"

He looked around the room, catching eyes. "But we do not have to go to war. We can negotiate, create a peace treaty that satisfies both sides. Ultimately, all we want is to be left alone, and I daresay they will be content with the same thing. The average Muggle does not want war, they cannot even truly contemplate the idea. Don't forget that there hasn't been a Muggle war on British soil in centuries."

"You would have us negotiate with child murderers?" A woman spoke up.

"I do not see that we have much of a choice," Madam Longbottom spoke angrily. "Harry Potter is right. We have to think about the good of the country, even if that requires distasteful decisions like allowing murderers to get away. Are you willing to have us all destroyed just so you can have revenge?"

"Negotiation is challenging, though," Mr. Deas pointed out. "Seeing as they will not talk to us."

Lord Jugson snorted. "Nor would it matter if they did, since we have already established that the Muggle government are no longer in control of their people, nor have any checks on their soldiers."

"I think there is a way around that," Harry said. He wasn't entirely sure whether it would work, but there was a decent chance, and they should at least try. "Use publicity. Give the Muggle government free reign to set the location and conditions for the negotiations, allow them to transmit everything to national television... If we can then arrange a deal that the majority of the people can live with, and proceed to follow through with our side of the agreements, it will take the heart out of the resistance. There probably will still be some people who do not believe it, but the longer we are seen as holding to our side of the deal, the more those people will be considered mere conspiracy theorists. This does require that we do not give them any provocation whatsoever. That is to say, we must pass laws against any and all lethal, painful of permanently debilitating magic used on Muggles, even in self-defense, when other options are available."

Lucius Malfoy shook his head. "How do you propose to enforce such a law? You will never persuade most of our kind to not retaliate against Muggle violence, let alone not defending themselves!"

"I did not mean to suggest that people should simply allow themselves to be hurt, Lord Malfoy," Harry nodded. "But we can set standard procedures. A signal, perhaps, that will call a group of Aurors to the aid of any magical person who triggers it? Or self-defense with stunners, where the offending parties are imprisoned afterwards. Muggle prisons are not like Azkaban, fortunately, but they are still far from pleasant to be in, and it will be in the Muggle government's interest to not offend us overly much by letting the people we arrest get away without at least bringing them to court for attempted murder. In turn, we should also arrest any witches or wizards engaging in violent behavior towards Muggles, and openly try them."

"I can't see that happening, lad," a man near Harry spoke. "You can make laws whatever you like, but you won't stop the people who want to hurt Muggles. They'll just wear a mask, and the DMLE cannot be everywhere at once."

"I'm afraid Mr. Fortescue is right," Madam Bones nodded. reluctantly. "With emotions running as high as they have been lately, it will be quite difficult to prevent further attacks on Muggles, or even to detect them in time to make an arrest that will appear convincing. Certainly my people will do all that they can, but even so, we will have to prepare the Muggles from the start for the eventuality that there will be attacks – or overly violent defenses – that we cannot stop in time."

"Not to mention," another woman added, "the crazy nutter who started all this is still at large. Considering he single-handedly brought down the Statute of Secrecy, I'd be amazed if he were to refrain from further provocations."

"Why should we care what he does?" The Toad-woman asked. "I'd say we'd be doing quite enough already, allowing them to keep governing themselves and even passing laws against self-defense! They can hardly expect us to solve every little problem for them, can they?"

"We should care," Madam Bones said impatiently, "because the Muggles will never accept a peace treaty which includes a clause that wizards will not randomly kill Muggles if we are not actually seen to enforce that clause. We do not approve of the man, but they will nevertheless perceive him as representing us. Our negotiations would not achieve anything if our partners believe us to be insincere." She turned to Harry and added formally: "Since you seem to have considered this, do you have a solution in mind, Lord Potter?"

"I have some ideas," Harry said calmly. "But I would need to know exactly what tools we have. First of all, is it possible to detect magic done on or near Muggles?"

"Only if we specifically put a warning ward on every Muggle in the country," Madam Bones said regretfully. "Even doing so, nearness to Muggles may not be problematic by itself – many wizards live near Muggles, but not in direct sight, and in order to detect whether the Muggle would notice the magic, the Muggle would need more advanced shielding that needs regular reinforcement."

"That, or just a way to report magic they notice, conditional on magic actually being performed nearby," Harry pointed out. "But I can see this being open to abuse, and many Muggles will not want to be subject to magical protections, so let's put that idea aside for the moment. Second idea: at the start of the year, Professor McGonagall told me there are ways to detect underage magic. Can you tell me how you do that?"

"We put a trace on the areas where Muggleborns live," Madam Bones answered with a slight tone of surprise. "We can detect any magic occurring there. Magical parents are expected to keep an eye on their own children."

"Does the trace tell you who did the magic?"

"No, just the nature and location."

Harry closed his eyes briefly and counted to ten rapidly. There were so many flaws in this arrangement that it was hard to imagine, but then, these were the same kinds of people who organized professional Quidditch leagues.

"Does 'nature' mean the spell that was used?" He asked.

"The effect, actually," Madam Bones replied. "Normal spells tap into a select range of magical effects, which can also be triggered by certain magical creatures like House Elves, or using accidental magic. It is usually quite possible to determine the spell from the effects, especially for powerful spells which carry a unique effect."

Harry nodded. "All right. But I guess the fact that you put the trace on the place where Muggleborns live means that there isn't any way to put a trace on the children themselves, then?" This might make things a little bit harder, although he thought he could work around it.

"Oh, of course we can! But then we'd have to remove it after every holiday and reapply it when the children go home, or we'd constantly get the alarms."

"I see. Couldn't you just make it not give an alarm if the student is in a place where it's explicitly permitted, like Hogwarts or the Hogwarts Express?"

She appeared to consider this. "I suppose we could. But why should we? The current system works well enough, and also captures use of magical items, which a personal trace would not do."

Harry nodded. "Very well. So, there are personal traces and area traces, which can both give information about what magic is being done. How hard would it be to get around such a trace?"

"For a child almost impossible, unless they had a powerful wizard to help them."

"Suppose you were a powerful wizard, inside a traced area. Would you be able to take down the trace without it first giving an alarm?"

She frowned. "Not if it's properly applied, and the core points of the field are well inside the area. The wizard would need to use magic to do it."

"Professor Dumbledore," Harry turned to the former Headmaster. "Could you get around such a trace?"

"Yes," he said simply.

"Do you think you could get around that? Make a trace so sophisticated that even Salazar Slytherin, say, couldn't circumvent it?"

The old wizard considered the question for a few moments. "Yes," he said eventually.

"And what," the man referred to as Mr. Crouch said, "would you want to do with a trace like that?" His tone was aggressive, with a very slight undertone of what might be fear.

"It is quite simple, sir," Harry answered. "It seems that what we want to do is twofold: detect and prevent illegal uses of magic, and find individuals who operate outside the law. By combining both kinds of traces, we can do so. I would propose setting up area traces around the country, detecting any and all uses of magic, and additionally putting a trace on all witches, wizards and spell-casting magical creatures in it. Putting this information together, we will be able to differentiate between magic done by a law-abiding citizen, or by someone who has escaped our detection, and we can give an alarm for lethal spells used in areas labeled as 'Muggle', regardless of who's doing it. Or for any magic done by unregistered entities."

Mr. Crouch blanched. "That is a gross violation of privacy!"

"You speak of privacy, in a country where Legilimency is not against the law? Seriously? Using these traces, we could detect uses of Legilimency and avoid the risk of our government getting compromised by the Imperius Curse. What is more, they will enable us to determine aggressive magic in primarily Muggle areas, and allow us to instantly interfere."

Mr. Crouch spluttered. Professor Dumbledore, too, frowned.

"I am not sure that is wise, Harry – Lord Potter, I mean. If we set up such a system, will we ever be able to get rid of it? What if some dark lord, or even just a less capable government, comes into power? By knowing everything each of its members does at all times, such a rulership could never be rebelled against. Even abiding by the law, I would not be very comfortable living in a country where the government knew everything I did, while I could not know for certain whether I could always trust the government."

One of the men in Malfoy's camp smirked at him. "Didn't you speak in favor of emancipating the boy just an hour ago? Don't like it very much now that he's actually making his own contributions rather than yours, do you?"

"I am merely pointing out a danger – a grave danger! – in the course of action he proposes. Lord Potter, I fear this is not wise at all, not in the long term!"

Harry smirked. Point for Professor Dumbledore disassociating me from himself. "You bring up a valid point, I suppose. The main goal is to have the system in place for the few weeks it will take to calm down emotions and restore a piece of order, but I can see that the system, once it exists, might well remain in place permanently because it is really convenient to the government and law enforcement agencies in particular." He looked at Amelia Bones, who nodded.

"I agree to the need for care," Harry continued. "Not just for fear of a dark lord compromising the system in the future. Everyone is guilty of minor offenses; complete knowledge of everyone's actions would allow the people in charge of the system to selectively enforce laws, thereby essentially giving them the power to punish everyone they do not like for whatever reason. In particular, this would likely affect journalists and leaders of political opposition groups in the future. So yes, we must avoid that. Fortunately, we have magic at our disposal. Perhaps we can build some security straight into the system?"

"What did you have in mind?" Madam Bones asked, in a business-like tone.

"Well, is it possible to give an alarm only for specific kinds of spells – or spell effects, as you said – under specific circumstances, and make the spells and circumstances vary depending on the area?"

"Should be," Madam Bones nodded with a frown.

"Perfect. Then, for a start, it is not wise to have a vast information asymmetry between the government and the governed. Make it so that if the trace gives an alarm, the person – or creature – who set off that alarm is instantly notified of this. Can we do that?" Madam Bones nodded. Harry went on: "Don't store things: if you are not immediately told that the trace gave an alarm, then it cannot be queried afterwards what spell was done or who did it. And also make it so that the things which give an alarm are easy for anyone to check, and that any change in these things can be queried for at least a month afterwards. That way, the government will still be able to snoop without the consent of the people, but not without their knowledge – and any government turned evil could already do the former by forcing people to take a personal trace."

"And what kinds of things would give an alarm?" Mr. Crouch bit.

"We should be able to set that, and any setting should be available for public query. Say, for a given area, we can either specify a number of spells or kinds of magics which are `forbidden', or simply say everything is forbidden except for a certain group of spells. If a `forbidden' spell is cast, it gives an alarm naming the spell effect, the entity who did it and, if at all possible, who or what it was targeted at. We should also be able to add extra alarms for unregistered entities and allow specific people – like Aurors – to do forbidden spells in certain areas without giving alarm."

"So we could forbid any magic from being cast in Muggle towns," Madam Bones concluded. "And if that law is broken, we would be able to send Aurors there to deal with the disturbance without drowning in alarms." Yes, Harry thought, she does look eager. Not surprising, of course, for the head of Magical Law Enforcement to appreciate new tools to do her work more effectively.

"And stop the Unforgivable Curses from being used anywhere!" Madam Longbottom announced viciously. "About time for that too! I fully support this idea. I would be in favor even without any Muggle crisis!"

"Well I, for one, am not!" Mr. Crouch shouted angrily. "Are you all out of your senses? Will you submit to having your private concerns laid open to the world? Will you force our people to not cast any spell without a first-year child knowing about it? Forget it. I shall not accept this proposal."

He has something to hide, Harry thought, and he clearly wasn't the only one. People were casting suspicious looks at him. It was Amelia Bones who spoke up.

"I don't see why you're so upset, Barty – indeed, I would have expected you to welcome an idea like this with open arms! The proposal seems very reasonable, and would not violate anyone's rights – in fact, I would consider it on the conservative side. If we have such a system set up, with some extensions – storing information, as young Lord Potter calls it – we might be able to use it in trials for Occlumenses."

"But it would be difficult to set it up securely if we allow storing," Harry objected. "I'm sure it can be done, but it would require a lot more time to think about than we have now." And ideally we would want to have a computer scientist security expert poking at it for a month or so. "But if you consider the idea sound, and the Ministry and Wizengamot agree, then I think there is no reason why you could not set up an improved trace afterwards. And as for those who do not agree –", he turned to the seething Mr. Crouch, "– I would not wish to force anyone to accept such a trace against their will. No one should be stopped from leaving the country if they do not want to accept the personal trace, or for whatever other reason. In fact, I think the trace should not give alarm for any magic performed outside of our territory."

"What if they get it removed while they're abroad?" one of the women asked logically.

"Let them," Harry suggested. "The main reason for a personal trace is to not give alarm for innocent magic cast by civilians. Remember that the main part of the project is area traces, so we can detect any undesirable magic whatsoever – if we combine that information with the identity of the caster it would make certain things not undesirable. For example, if the average John Smith casts a cutting hex in his garden, you don't want to hear an alarm about that. If Bellatrix Black casts a cutting hex, you do want to know about it. Since I suspect Bellatrix will not be available for tracing, we would have to set a high alarm for spells by unregistered entities. I know that's probably rather inconvenient for tourists, but newborn Muggleborn witches and wizards, at least, already get a trace on their houses, right?"

"No, actually," Madam Bones replied. "Only when they start Hogwarts. But that is inconsequential. International visitors are already required to use registered portkeys or Apparition spots, or otherwise at least announce their arrival to us. The only large thing that will need changing is that we will have to keep an eye on House Elf births."

"But can this really be done?" A woman asked. "It sounds incredibly sophisticated."

"Well, Chief Warlock?" Lord Nott challenged. "I daresay you would be the one most qualified to perform such magics."

"Not on my own, certainly," the grayed wizard shook his head. "But I think I could devise spells like Lord Potter describes, especially if the Ministry would lend me the aid of some skilled Charms Masters and Arithmancers. Some experts in the Ancient Runes would also not be amiss."

"That should not be an issue," Cornelius Fudge nodded. The man looked positively excited, which was probably not a good sign.

"I would like to suggest that all spells are checked by independent parties," Lord Malfoy spoke up. "To be very clear that they do exactly what is described, and that we can all agree to those effects."

"Of course, Lord Malfoy," Dumbledore nodded. "I had no desire to cheat the assembly."

"So are we decided on starting negotiations, then?" Madam Longbottom queried.

"I still don't like it one bit," Lord Usto spat. "But I can see I'm going to be overruled, aren't I?"

"Little though I like the idea of pandering to Muggles," Lucius Malfoy spoke slowly, "I will support this proposal. It seems that we have little choice, if we are to survive. Our country is not yet ready to fight a war."

Yet, Harry registered. But the implication seemed to resonate with many people. There were nods around the benches.

"All right then!" Minister Fudge exclaimed. "So what shall we say is the timescale on this? Can we stop this disaster and then get the Muggles under control before Friday?"

"I think if I can assemble a good team and work through the night, the spells should be ready by morning," Professor Dumbledore supplied. "Any experts Lord Malfoy wishes to appoint for approving the spells can then have a go over them. Amelia, do you think your Aurors can apply the trace on everyone in the country in the matter of a day?"

"I believe so," Madam Bones nodded. "If I can set all my Aurors to it."

"That's assuming quite a lot," another woman pointed out. "Unless you mind not responding to violence aimed at innocent witches and wizards."

"Waiting another day might also be too long," Harry said, frowning. "Today was pretty intense – it won't take long before the Muggle military decides to take a big step again, and we don't know what they're planning, aside from the obvious indication that they're clearing the areas around our important buildings. It's probably a good idea to have the full tracing system developed and approved by independent parties before we start applying it, but how about first placing the area traces, and leaving the individual ones until later? The way the system should be designed, that'll just act like everyone is an unknown entity who should be treated with mistrust, but that only means that we have to ask everyone to refrain from casting spells for a short time. We could exempt St. Mungo's from the trace, allow Apparating and basic Healing Charms everywhere, and start adding the individual trace on reliable Aurors to allow them to cast non-lethal spells, although if possible we want to run them through Thieves' Downfall first. How long would it take to set that up?"

Madam Bones closed her eyes, thinking. "Probably a few hours. Three or four, maybe?"

"Which means that we should be ready at noon tomorrow," the Chief Warlock concluded. "Then we can contact the Prime Minister by Patronus and propose negotiations, showing our goodwill by promising them that no further attacks on Muggles by witches and wizards will be tolerated – and enforcing this from then on."

"We must also contact all of our kind before then," Madam Longbottom supplied. "Perhaps overnight owls with instructions not to cast magic?"

"And instructions for a warning signal," Madam Bones added. "With traces all over the country, this is a lot simpler than it otherwise would be. We can simply detect any time someone casts sparks and send Aurors there to help."

"Which will allow us to decisively deal with any Muggle offensive as well!" McWillen exclaimed eagerly. "If we can demonstrate that we can exercise that kind of control, it should make them interested in a quick resolution too!"

There were sounds of agreement. Mr. Crouch still looked sour, but he didn't protest any further.

"Wonderful!" Professor Dumbledore exclaimed. "It seems like we finally have a solution that will bring an end to this madness. Now we merely need to appoint a negotiator. I hope I do not offend, but perhaps it would not be optimal to send our esteemed Minister again, seeing as the Muggles have a grievance with him."

"Hah!" Lord Jugson cried. "You expect to persuade us to send you, don't you?"

The Chief Warlock smiled genially. "I would naturally be prepared to represent the Wizengamot in this matter. Although I suspect that there are some in this assembly who may not be entirely comfortable appointing me, it is fundamental to send a representative who will not unduly offend the Muggles. As you well know, I have a lot of experience interacting with Muggle leaders."

Clever move, Harry thought silently. Malfoy's followers are more likely to accept me if the alternative is you.

"Such negotiations may well be dangerous, however," Deas pointed out. "I would certainly not like to volunteer myself. If we indeed allow the Muggles to set all the conditions of the meeting, the negotiator may not leave the place alive."

"But it would be a great honor," a woman spoke out.

Harry glanced at Amelia Bones. This would be the perfect time for her to –

Lord Malfoy stood up. "I nominate Lord Potter."

Harry blinked. What?

And that was when he realized that the Malfoy Lord had been remarkably silent and non-confrontational all through the meeting; that he had only commented on feasibility and avoided Dumbledore from getting unchecked control over the country's wards, and that Dumbledore had even said that the man had been surprisingly silent in the last two days.

Was Lucius acting under Voldemort's orders? Or did he simply see a way to take power from the hated Dumbledore and pass it to a new entity?

"If the Wizengamot chooses to send me, I am willing to go." Harry said formally.

"Hem hem," Toad-woman intoned. "I'm sorry if I misunderstand, but Lord Malfoy, surely you would not suggest sending a first-year child as our representative? The idea is absurd!"

"I agree!" Lord Usto shouted. "It's bad enough that we listen to this child, but to have him negotiate on behalf of the entire Wizengamot is absolutely ridiculous."

"The young Lord of Potter is obviously an expert on Muggle matters," Lord Malfoy said patiently. "Despite not being a Muggleborn or blood traitor himself. This makes him perfectly suited to handle the negotiations on our behalf. His youth is only to our advantage: as a child, he will more easily be forgiven for any offense he may inadvertently give. Yet if he is seen to be backed by adults, they will have no choice but to take his offers seriously."

"And if they do bring it up," Madam Longbottom said bitterly, "he can just remind them that they did not much seem to care much about age when they murdered our children." The anger dripped off her voice.

"I agree to the nomination," Amelia Bones said decisively. "We have already voted to put his youth aside, and Lord Malfoy has a point that it could work to our advantage in this regard."

"I too support young Lord Potter," Albus Dumbledore said. "He is our greatest hope in this crisis, and I know his heart to be pure."

There was a stunned silence as the two powerful enemies aligned themselves.

"I have one request, though," Harry asked in the silence. This would be difficult to get away with, but he couldn't afford to be denied on this point. "If I represent our kind in these negotiations, will I have the authority to enter into an agreement on behalf of the government of Magical Britain, and will that agreement be respected afterwards? If I make promises or threats, can I be assured that these will be followed up on?"

"If the agreements reached are reasonable, I am sure we can all agree –" McWillen began, but Harry shook his head.

"I have seen how this body functions," he said firmly. "If I come back here with a treaty, it is certain that every minute detail will be argued about and debated beyond measure, and it is unlikely that we shall have consensus on any point – indeed, I cannot imagine any deal that would meet with the approval of all of the Wizengamot, simply because there is little that we all agree on. There will necessarily have to be compromises, and I have to be free to make those. What is more, recall that the negotiations will have to take place under conditions set by the Muggles, under full witness by the entire country. If I am hesitant and cannot make any promises, we will not get anywhere. If I speak decisively, I expect we can come to an agreement for a full package of laws that mediate the interactions between our kinds, but they will not take me – and by extension, us – seriously if I then come back the next day and request to have three points changed. This is why I ask that you give me the full authority to set a binding deal on behalf of the Ministry."

"Now hold there a moment," the Minister of Magic protested. "Surely we should still have a say in the outcome? You cannot expect us to put ourselves by the sidelines!"

Madam Bones frowned. "I do not like this idea much, but Lord Potter does have a point about the infeasibility of negotiations without this assurance."

"Perhaps there is a compromise," Lord Malfoy spoke. "Our representative does not need to go alone. Indeed, he will be taken more seriously when accompanied by adults."

"That seems reasonable, but we cannot be seen arguing in front of the Muggles," Harry said with a frown. "Nor have the negotiations stall if we disagree on a point."

"There is a spell to speak silently," the Chief Warlock supplied. "What if the final responsibility to speak is yours, but you will have experienced advisers who come with you and are able to supply both opinions and information without interfering with the proceedings?"

"That could work," Harry said, thinking quickly. "As long as the advisers do not directly interfere." Which will still be a problem if I can't guarantee that they'll stay quiet... Unbreakable Vows, perhaps?

"May I ask what is it you're planning to tell the Muggles?" Madam Bones asked reasonably.

"It depends on what they have to say. Ultimately, I want us to live side by side with the Muggles in peace. Peace, and guarantees that they will never use their destructive power on us again. I do believe they want the same – they just don't trust us, as we don't trust them. I will make whatever promises are in the Ministry's power – positive and negative – to achieve that goal."

"Shall we vote on the matter?" Cornelius Fudge asked. "All those in favor of giving Lord Potter the Ministry's full authority in the coming negotiations?"

There were hands – most notably Dumbledore, Bones and Malfoy – but several people still looked hesitant.

"Under protest," one of the other men said, raising his hand only slightly. "As there are no alternatives on the table anyone can agree on. But I do not like it."

"Count me out," Crouch grumbled. "With this child in charge, I'm leaving the country."

"Oh very well," one of the women said, raising her hand. "I can't see that we have much to lose. If someone has to negotiate, it might as well be Lord Potter as someone else, and if Albus thinks he has the best of intentions, I will accept that. So long as the Ministry promises protections on the ancestral houses of those who flee the country for a few years if this turns out wrong."

They just don't want to stay behind when the majority elects a strong leader, Slytherin snickered, as more people and more people, including Cornelius Fudge, raised their hands.

They're right to hesitate, Hufflepuff pointed out. They've just given the authority to make any laws regarding Magical Britain which Muggles can agree to, to a child they know next to nothing about.

It was sad, in a way, to see the government of Magical Britain trade away its power and freedom for a vague promise of protection. But he'd been planning to overthrow the government all along, and this was clearly the most peaceful way to achieve it.

"It seems we have a majority," Cornelius Fudge concluded. "Lord Potter, the assembly agrees to give you full power of negotiation and access to the Ministry's resources for the duration of the crisis."

"I would like to know, however," Lord Malfoy spoke up, "who will accompany Lord Potter in his negotiations."

"Those I can trust," Harry answered. "It is absolutely essential that they can agree to refrain from interfering and stick to it. I have to be able to make snap decisions and propose things whose ulterior goal is not immediately clear – hesitating to discuss it silently and get agreement on such points first would be wildly counterproductive, especially if the people who accompany me are from different sides of the political spectrum and unlikely to agree to everything. If one of my advisers suddenly decided that the agreements are not to his or her tastes and objected out loud, it would severely undermine the efforts and likely launch us all into a war."

"There are ways to guarantee trust," a man sitting next to the Minister, who had been one of the first to vote in Harry's favor, brought up.

Harry raised his eyebrows. "I was under the impression that the Unbreakable Vow is not to be taken lightly, as it requires a magical sacrifice."

"It does, but under the circumstances that may well be acceptable. What is more, a House Vow does not require a permanent sacrifice, and you are the Lord of your House."

This sounded like the idea Padma had brought up to him before, but what she had told him didn't seem like something the Nobles would easily agree to doing. "What exactly does that entail?"

"It is a spell developed in the late Middle Ages. Those who swear service to a Noble House are at the command of its Lord or Lady. They can be killed in an instant if the Lord so chooses, either by his direct decision or by violating a prearranged condition. The contract of service remains in place until their death, or until the Lord of the House releases them. If those who accompany you are sworn to you, you will be certain that they do not speak out of turn, as it would have them killed on the spot, and then you can simply release them afterwards. Indeed, as you have only just gained control of your Noble House, it is actually customary to allow willing witches and wizards to swear to you."

So it was the spell Padma had mentioned. Somewhat similar to the Unbreakable Vow, but limited to obedience to a given person, and possible to break if you were willing to take the risk; a spell that placed your fate completely into someone else's hands. He would have expected this kind of thing to have gone out of style centuries ago, but apparently it hadn't.

So magical Britain condones slavery of people as well as House Elves. Big surprise there, is it? "Would anyone do that?"

"I can guarantee it, sir," the man replied with a slight smile.

"Very well. If anyone should wish to swear service to me, then I will be open to that. But let's make it clear that I do not expect anyone to do it. If no one swears, I will not mind being accompanied by people whom I believe to be trustworthy even without vows, or simply with Unbreakable Vows if a willing binder can be found."

There were nods around the hall, and sudden thoughtful looks on many faces.

The meeting was disbanded shortly afterwards. Harry watched the Lords and Ladies filter out, savoring the bittersweet feeling.

He was king.

At eleven, he held the power of a country, and he might be able to set in motion some of his most ambitious plans for the world. He would never just be a child prodigy who flashed and faded anymore – whatever happened, he would go down in history, whether as hero or villain to be determined later.

And he had done exactly what the man who had – directly or indirectly – murdered three of his parents had wanted him to do.

-o-o-o-o-o-

Author's Note: if you are thinking that no government, sane or insane, would ever allow negotiators to make agreements on its behalf without checks, I would originally have agreed with you... and then I heard about "fast-track" for trade agreements actually getting passed. Hum.

Chapter 109: Negotiations, Pt 1

Friday, May 1st 1992, 10:58am.

"Oh man," Draco said, and then added mentally. You are going to look like such an idiot, Potter.

I'm sure Harry will do just fine, Hermione thought primly. "But we probably shouldn't distract him too much while he's trying to hold a conversation."

I can deal with distraction, Harry grumbled. Just don't expect me to actually respond to what you're saying in my head.

The Ministry had arranged communication pins for all members of the negotiation committee. The pins were magical items which allowed mental communication by "thinking loudly". In a sense, it worked much like normal talking: only people who were close enough could hear thoughts you were sending out, and you could moderate your own loudness. The great advantage was, of course, that outsiders couldn't overhear or interfere in the conversation, unless they had a similar pin set to the same frequency, or used some rather sophisticated interception spells.

The three of them had been experimenting with the pins for almost two hours. At first the adults had participated, but they were more familiar with the technique and had left to other duties. The children had carried on, learning how to moderate loudness, recognize mental from verbal speech and ignoring – or even half-listening to – mental conversations in the background while concentrating on a spoken conversation with someone else.

"I've got to go," Hermione said reluctantly. "Lord Malfoy wants to 'clean me up', which for some reason is supposed to take three hours. Do you have any idea what he has in mind, Draco?"

"Probably something to make you look a bit less like a beaver," Draco shrugged. No offense meant.

She humphed. Harry shot Draco a poisonous look. "He just wants to make sure you look your best when representing our world – you know people tend to judge by looks. Draco and I are also getting a 'cleanup' later on. He has absolutely promised me not to do anything painful to you, nor anything that would be hard to reverse, and don't forget that I have the power to rip the magic out of him and turn him into a Muggle for the rest of his life if he turns out to be insincere. Besides, if you're still uncomfortable with him, I'm sure one of the Aurors won't mind watching over you. They must be getting pretty bored guarding my office all the time."

She grimaced, then took Xare's claw and disappeared. Harry suddenly realized that Draco had stiffened. Oops.

I'm sorry to talk so lightly about that, he sent. I was only saying it because I could, and Lucius knows that, so he will not take the risk. That's the whole point of the House Vow, that you never actually need to use the power it gives. You know I wouldn't hurt your father unless I absolutely had to.

Draco nodded. The idea takes some getting used to

. You do realize that taking his magic would be just as bad as killing him, right?

I can imagine he would feel that way, yes, Harry answered. But you shouldn't be so worried. It's only for a little while – I have officially given my word to cancel all three servitude contracts after the negotiations are over. What is more, I suspect that someone will propose me taking an Unbreakable Vow to release the corresponding bonds when I end the contracts. All in the interest of the continued independence of the Wizengamot, of course.

And I'm sure that the money to pay for the binder will in no way be traceable back to your father, Harry thought quietly to himself as Draco's eyes widened in sudden understanding. He may not do that if I come out on top, but he certainly will if there is any doubt of my dominance after the negotiations. Although now that I've pointed out to your son that I understand what you're doing, Lucius, you may not wish to take that risk. Not that he had any intention of preserving the bond once it was illegal to do so. But Lucius didn't need to know that.

He removed the pin from his hair. "We might as well stop, too. The magic on these things doesn't last very long, and the negotiations may take several days. For what I understand, they're rather expensive to replace."

Draco quietly followed suit. There were some moments of silence between them, and then the boy spoke up again.

"Harry, are you sure you know what you're doing?"

No. "I'm doing the best I can. I don't know how it's going to work out, but it's got to be better than not trying." He looked at Draco's worried face for a moment. "Are you comfortable with this? I know your father wanted you to come along, but I didn't think to ask for your opinion."

"He did ask me first," Draco said guardedly. Harry waited, and eventually Draco continued: "I'm just worried. What if this all goes wrong?"

"I'm sure the blame will fall entirely on me, and nobody would even think of blaming you and your father," Harry shrugged.

"That's not what I'm –" Draco balled his fists in frustration. "This is all happening so fast! I knew theoretically what Muggles were capable of, but I never expected a war, not so soon! I do want to come along, I might even be able to help, but it's really hard to be excited about anything when two days ago I woke up with broken ribs, lying between two dead third-years. If we screw this up – if you screw this up – are we all going to die?"

Ah. "I don't know. Probably not all, but it won't be pretty." Harry sighed. "You're right, this is big. But going for peace talks is the most sensible thing we can do right now, and I think both parties would really prefer peace over continuing the fighting. The Muggles want to be left alone just as much as we do – the only difficulty is to contain those of both our peoples who aren't content with that, and to create guarantees for the future. We'll just do the best we can."

"And what if we fail?"

"Get out of the country," Harry shrugged.

"And wait for the foreign Muggles to come for us?" Draco grumbled bitterly.

"If they do, there will be other opportunities to stop it," Harry reassured him. "It's a big world, Draco. This is our best chance to nip the whole thing in the bud before it gets any worse, but if we fail, it won't be the end of all hope." Besides, Quirrell would never let it come to a destruction of the entire wizarding world. I think. Although I'm not as sure about the safety of Muggles.

"I guess," Draco said dejectedly. Then he seemed to force himself to push off his dark mood. "Well, let's see what my father has in mind for our 'cleanup', shall we?"

Friday, May 1st 1992, 13:56.

The six of them were gathered in full ornate.

Lucius Malfoy had insisted that they should maintain appearances. By looking imposing, the enemy would naturally assign them superiority in their minds. And so he had dressed them up with the best Madam Maulkin and some of his connections could do.

Harry was robed in white silk, with golden bands running down from the top of his robes to the bottom and a heavy blue velvet cloak with intricate silver draped around his shoulders. In his hand, he held a silver staff, artificially lightened. The staff wasn't actually functional, like the old druid staves had been, but it looked far more impressive than a wand ever could. Lord Malfoy's assistants had tried to tame his hair, but it had returned to its natural state the instant he looked in a mirror, so they had declared that part a hopeless case. After long consideration, Lord Malfoy had decided to leave the scar on his forehead alone, since it helped him look more mysterious.

The others could not look quite that fine, of course, but were still made to look impressive, with green dress robes and silver belts underneath a light yellow cloak. Hermione had been forced to sit down and have liberal amounts of Sleekeazy's Hair Potion applied to her hair – which in her case did work – and Lord Malfoy had even insisted on shrinking her teeth. The effect was stunning, but Harry thought it wasn't really Hermione anymore. She herself didn't look very happy with the arrangement either, although her discomfort might also be related to nerves for what they were about to do. Even Draco, who had been trained for this sort of thing all his life, couldn't completely hide his worries.

Each of them had their wand in a pocket of their robes, with enchantments to jump into their owner's hands at a mental command. The adults had applied the most powerful shielding charms they could to the children, and Albus Dumbledore had cast a powerful ward on the group as a whole, which would hopefully be able to keep them protected from most forces as long as they stayed close enough together. All wore their communication pins hidden in their hair and a small silver knob on their forehead which was instilled with Scrying Charms, to allow the Auror Office to see everything they saw. Beneath their robes, both Harry and Albus Dumbledore wore their Time-Turners, both having saved all their uses. Every member of the team had an emergency portkey to transport six people to the Ministry. And both Albus Dumbledore and Hermione Granger had their phoenix on their shoulder. Muggles would not know the meaning of the fire-birds, but they might still be impressed by their beauty. Or, for that matter, by the cries of the phoenixes, should they suggest something inappropriate.

(Harry himself would, of course, be entirely reasonable. Or otherwise give Dumbledore the previously agreed upon signal to silently put both birds under a restraining charm when necessary.)

"Everyone ready?" Harry asked.

Each adult grabbed the child in front of him by the shoulder. Thicknesse took hold of Dumbledore's left arm; Malfoy took Thicknesse's.

"Go," Harry said.

They burned up and reappeared at the entrance of Windsor Castle, quickly letting go of each other. They stood on a red carpet leading in, with soldiers on either side guarding their entrance.

Lucius snorted contemptuously. I wonder whether they expect to need these guards? His mental voice spoke. It would be trivial to put them all under Imperius.

Don't you dare, Harry hissed back.

I wasn't suggesting we do, Lord Potter, Lucius sent, his face wearing a sleek smile. Merely that we could.

Heads held high, not looking around at the curious Muggles who had come to watch, they walked in.

"Welcome."

The old, richly clad woman bowed her head in greeting. Hermione had drawn in her breath when entered the room, and confirmed Harry's immediate suspicion by sending that's the Queen!

"How do you do?" Harry said politely, and made as proper a bow as he knew how to.

Are you sure? Thicknesse asked urgently, as the others followed in a deep bow, not showing any sign of their mental communication. That sounds like an awful risk they're taking.

Not really, Harry thought back. The Queen is pretty dispensable. Her function is mostly ceremonial, and she has a grown son and even two grandchildren.

"Are you Lord Harry Potter?" The Queen asked. If she was surprised, she hid it well, but the eight suited men and women in the room did not have her demeanor. Some were outright staring, others wore sneers.

"I am, Your Majesty."

There was a brief pause, in which Dumbledore quietly mentioned that there were fifteen hidden cameras as well as the three visible ones, and that the Queen and all representatives had tiny wireless communication devices in their ears.

"Please forgive my companions' surprise. I must confess that we had expected someone older to be sent as the speaker for the magical world. Are you a prince, of some kind?"

"I'm afraid I can only speak for the witches and wizards in this country, Your Majesty," Harry replied. "Not the entire world. And I am not a prince, although I am the Lord of a Noble House – I suppose you might say a duke."

Closer to a baron, actually, Malfoy warned him.

"I mean a baron," Harry corrected himself. "As for my age –" he shrugged. "Our culture is very different from yours. I am considered an adult in our world, not through age, but through... achievement, I suppose you might say." Let them consider the meaning of that one.

Introduce us, Malfoy's voice hissed in his mind. At least one of his party knew etiquette.

"If I may introduce," he said as though it were his own idea, "my friends, Hermione Granger and Draco Malfoy." He nodded his head in their directions as he named them. "And three representatives of our governing agencies: Lord Malfoy, Mr. Thicknesse and Mr. Dumbledore."

The Queen nodded solemnly, and started introducing the men and women around her. They were ambassadors of some kind; probably not too important, but reliable people to represent the government.

I'm worried about the implications of their sending the Queen, Harry took the time to say (Hermione would remember all the names, of course, so he didn't need to pay attention). There was no reason to send anyone, they could have just implemented a video conference. But the Queen is a well-loved public figure. If she gets hurt, or even if we are just inappropriately rude to her, it will upset the people immensely. And that will help the government to justify draconian measures to their constituents.

We must not be rude, then, Dumbledore suggested.

No. Thicknesse sounded worried. This is a bad sign. They must have an informant who is intimately familiar with our ancient laws. Merlin himself placed the King of England as the ruler over both wizardry and Muggles. Those laws have never been repealed. I would have to look up whether it says 'king' or 'monarch', and how binding those laws are, but when she commands, we may have to obey.

They would not need an informant, Dumbledore suggested. The knowledge may simply have been passed on in the Queen's family.

This is a pointless discussion, Malfoy bit. If those laws still exist, they are technicalities which have been overlooked for centuries. We can ignore them.

She can grant and revoke nobility, Thicknesse contradicted him. As you well know, given that your own family was ennobled by her ancestor. Think about that, and how many of our ancient rituals and customs are tied to family titles. What is more, we cannot be sure that some of our structures will not open to her. If she formally disbands the Wizengamot – if she knows how to do that – will the Hall still open to us? Tread very carefully, Lord Potter.

Harry had no time to answer, as the Queen had finished introducing the delegates, explained the function of the cameras which were live-broadcasting the meeting, and signified to everyone that they might sit. They took place on the lush chairs placed on their side of the room.

"You asked us for this meeting," the Queen spoke. "Can I assume that you have an opening prepared?"

"I do, in fact," Harry nodded. This part he had discussed with the others at length. "To begin with, I would like to express my heartfelt apologies for the offense given by our Minister, Cornelius Fudge, when he spoke to you last week."

The others had unanimously agreed that it would be imprudent to refer to the Minister of Magic as a bumbling idiot, accurate though the description would certainly be. Having watched the recording in a Pensieve, however, Harry thought that there was something deeper to the Minister's behavior towards the Muggle parliament than sheer stupidity. Fudge believed, as a matter of course, that wizards were superior to Muggles, and that they themselves ought to agree with that idea. The Muggles, of course, did not think like that, and responded accordingly. There, the friction was born.

"To start, do you mind if I refer to non-magical people as Muggles?" He asked. "It is the word we usually employ. It is not meant to be offensive, but I could imagine you would perceive it as such."

"If that is your usual phrase," the Queen said calmly, "then you may."

"Thank you, Your Majesty. As I mentioned before, our culture is very different from yours. In Europe, the Muggle world – that is, the normal world you are used to – and the magical world diverged in the sixteenth century, when the International Statute of Secrecy was passed. Given the significant changes in the Muggle world alone since then, I hope you can appreciate the vast gap which has sprung up between the two peoples. What is more, there are not many of us; in the UK, we number in the thousands rather than the millions. Partly as a result, our society is based around tradition, families and nobility, although accomplishment is also valued, both in the form of magical ability and prowess in other areas, such as trade or politics."

He took a deep breath. "In a society so fundamentally focused around family heritage, bloodlines and power, it is unfortunate but probably not surprising that many of our kind look down on those who do not possess magic, and even on those who are magically weaker. Our near-complete isolation from the Muggle world only exacerbates that issue. This somewhat contemptuous view is... pervasive, although certainly not universal."

"So what you mean to say," a woman asked, "is that the views of your leader do not represent those of the majority?"

That would hardly be accurate, Malfoy hissed in Harry's mind.

"If that is the case," another pointed out, "it would seem unexpected for the majority to elect a leader with those views."

Harry looked at the woman who had spoken. "Madam, we have very little contact with Muggles. As such, this is usually not a major political issue. I believe most of our kind don't really think about Muggles at all. For all that we live in the same country, witches and wizards tend to remain in their own bubble. In truth, for most of my friends I could not say for sure how they feel on the subject; whether they think of Muggles as equals, inferiors, people who have a handicap or even a strange species living completely different lives. It doesn't really come up."

Some of the Muggle representatives looked disturbed at that communication. They seem offended. Best follow up on that, Malfoy suggested.

"I think this is mainly ignorance, however," Harry quickly added. "Now that the Statute of Secrecy can no longer be continued, our people – Muggle and Magical – will be able to get to know each other, and overcome prejudices. For a start, little though I suspect any of us would like to see a continuation of the last days, I believe many of our people have been shaken to the realization that Muggles have power too, even without magic."

Some of the Muggles smirked at that, others shifted uncomfortably. The Queen nodded solemnly.

"In regards to that, I believe an explanation from our side is warranted as well," she spoke. "The assaults on your people – and most importantly your school – were not approved by any governmental body. We have traced down the order to Lieutenant General Richard Darrens, although he was supported by several lesser officers in our military. The Lieutenant General seems to have committed suicide after realizing the consequences of his actions, but the others have been arrested. Please rest assured that the act of firing a nuclear weapon on an unknown target will not go unpunished."

Do not speak of Mr. Johnson, Dumbledore warned. We must intercede, but will surely find a way to do so in private.

I wasn't going to, Harry replied. But the culprit's suicide is a hint we should not neglect. It is the ultimate way to stop us from testing whether he acted under the Imperius Curse.

"Thank you," Harry said. Then, to the querying looks, "I am using a spell to communicate with my colleagues in silence, to avoid either arguing in front of you or accidentally supplying incorrect information. In this case, we were briefly debating what your information implies for the intelligence our own people have gathered. I am sure that you are similarly connected with people not in this room."

The Queen smiled. "Indeed we are. Thank you for your explanation."

One of the men cleared his throat. "On this topic, on behalf of the United Nations, I wanted to ask... do you know what happened to the first missile? Our instruments have only shown the impacts of the second and third."

The one you diverted? Harry queried Dumbledore.

A small island in the North Sea, Dumbledore supplied. Abandoned and safe from Muggles or even sea animals. I have done what I could to contain the radiation damage afterwards, in particular by renewing the wards to keep any living being from entering or leaving the surrounding area.

"We diverted the missile to an abandoned island in the North Sea," Harry repeated smoothly. "We hope that our precautions will keep the contamination in hand, but we shall of course supply you with the necessary information to confirm the safety of the waters for yourself."

The man nodded. "We would appreciate that."

There was a brief silence, broken by the Queen. "Perhaps you could explain what has happened in these past weeks?"

Harry nodded. "Naturally. I suppose there are several parts to tell. You remember, of course, the man our Minister told you of – the 'terrorist' as your people said, who has led several attacks on the Muggle world, including one particularly devastating one."

Some people nodded, but he also saw frowns. "Surely you aren't going to claim that all of the violence directed at our citizens was by some convenient madman?"

"No," Harry said sadly. "That would be a lie. In the last week, several of our people have taken part in the violence. This was not government-sanctioned – indeed, we have made several arrests – but was initiated by the people themselves, either responding to the loss of the Statute of Secrecy or acting in retaliation." He spread his hands helplessly. "As I have said, several of our people consider themselves superior to Muggles, but most never think about it, and would certainly not engage in such acts. There are a few, however, some pathetic few, who like to feel superior by showing their dominance over people who cannot fight back so effectively. That is why you have seen wizards attacking Muggles in the streets, biting doorknobs, poisonous mists and other such nastiness – those same people, had they no magic, would be torturing animals or abducting children. It's the same kind of mindset. Our government and law enforcement agency absolutely do not condone this sort of behavior, and there have been arrests, but unfortunately in the general unrest too many such people managed to slip under the radar – which is what they counted on, of course."

He paused for some moments, waiting for his words to sink in, then continued. "The others were acting in misguided retaliation. When Muggles attack witches or wizards, there will be those of our kind who decide to strike back – and they do not distinguish one group of Muggles from the rest. Especially after the attack on our school, and the subsequent attack on the refugee children. Our community is small – with eighty children dead, a large share of our people have lost someone they loved. So yes, unfortunately many have been guided by fear and irrational hatred towards the group rather than the few individuals who actually caused all this harm. It is wrong, but in the end, it is human nature, isn't it?"

They can't exactly fault your reasoning there, Hermione observed as some of the assembled people nodded slightly. Not without having to explain what Muggle citizens have been doing.

"I see," the Queen spoke. "But that is not how this started."

"Indeed," Harry conceded. "This was started by an individual who, it seems, was seeking to overthrow the Statute of Secrecy and create bad blood between magical and non-magical people at the same time. He is the man our Minister referred to as Quirinius Quirrell, although I am quite sure that is not the man's real name, but rather an assumed identity under which he has taught at Hogwarts School for a short period. After being exposed, he has twice attacked Muggles in a very blatant, very hard to hide way, both of which our Ministry ended up covering up in a rather immoral way, because the preservation of the International Statute of Secrecy weighed higher to them than the lives affected. Having met the man, I can only assume that he was counting on this line of action to create hostility."

"You call your own government immoral?" One of the men asked surprised, even as Lucius hissed in his mind about rash comments.

"I called their actions in this instance immoral, as there is little point in denying that they were. Whether or not these actions were preferable to the alternative – violating a century-old international treaty of world-changing impact – is a question for debate. It might be worth observing that in fact a war started within days of secrecy being lost, so some of these fears were not unfounded, although I must confess this might well have been avoided if we'd handled the situation better."

You're overdoing it! Lucius snapped. You're practically down on your knees apologizing for how terrible we are. If you continue acting weak like this, they will try to walk all over us!

The Muggles were clearly thinking on the same lines. Some were looking surprised, others wore smirks, clearly classifying him as a stupid little kid. One woman was sending shrewd looks at the older wizards behind him.

"Well, Lord Potter," the Queen began. "Your honesty is certainly... refreshing. But I notice you didn't mention the events of Monday last week. Is it usual for one person in your world to be able to do such widespread damage in so little time?"

"It really isn't," Harry said decisively. "But these were... special circumstances. Explaining this requires a little background, however. May I?"

"Of course," nodded the Queen.

"Thank you, your Majesty. In the history of magic, we have a long tradition of 'knowledge which is not to be spoken'. Some magic is extremely dangerous, and if you tell people who do not possess the – the skills, or maturity, to handle the knowledge properly, it could lead to very dangerous consequences." He saw some of the ambassadors frowning, so he added: "Suppose for example that a scientist discovered a formula to make an atomic bomb with common household equipment. You wouldn't want him to publish it in the newspapers. In fact, you probably wouldn't want him to publish it at all." There were some nods, some frowns, and some hesitant looks.

"I realize that in the Muggle world it might be hard to keep such knowledge quiet forever. But in the wizarding world, there are many things like that. And therefore we have a long tradition of secrecy."

One of the men snorted. "What you're saying is that magic is so dangerous it should be forbidden!"

"Well, sir," Harry said politely, turning to him. "Would you rather drive it underground, or teach people how to use magic properly and not to explode the country or spill secrets that would achieve that?"

"I suppose I see the point," the Queen nodded. Whether or not she agreed was a separate matter, but she had been trained from birth to be a diplomat, and obviously wasn't going to be judgmental. "Although I wonder how this is relevant?"

"A particular piece of knowledge," Harry explained. "There is – was – a certain extremely dangerous kind of magical creature. We call them 'Dementors'. Pius?" The Senior Secretary to the Minister carefully reached inside his robes and a vision appeared before them. The Muggles gasped.

"Muggles cannot see them," Harry continued. "Yet they can feel them. They suck away life and happiness, and if unconstrained, can reduce their victims to a comatose state which, our oldest sources say, is worse than death. In the best case, this could simply mean that they are brain-dead while their bodies continue to function, as empty hulls. In the worst case, they have lost control over their bodies but continue to live, in constant agony."

That is not the worst case, Dumbledore reminded him.

Shut up, Harry suggested. I'm not going to confuse matters by bringing up souls.

"There is a certain spell to defend against Dementors," he continued. "It conjures up a magical guardian, which will keep the Dementors at a distance and stop them from attacking or affecting people near the guardian. For over fifteen hundred years, witches and wizards have kept Dementors controlled, keeping them away from Muggles, because there was no way to kill them. There was one flaw in this spell, however. It only works if you do not understand the nature of Dementors."

"That they represent death?" A man asked. "That was what the voice said."

"Yes," Harry nodded. "Many witches and wizards might have known, but they never spoke of it, for the knowledge would harm other people. Last week, however, it seems this man deliberately broke the rule to not share harmful information. No longer controlled, the Dementors attacked. You have seen the results."

"How did you get them to stop?" The man who had spoken on behalf of the UN asked interestedly.

"Well, earlier this year, I have discovered not only the secret, but a way to destroy Dementors. Most people cannot do it, and naturally I had to be very restrained in telling people about it, as the spell to destroy them required understanding of the nature of Dementors first, a secret which I knew had to be guarded. However, a few of my friends managed to learn the spell. Our Director of Magical Law Enforcement has then sent us around the world to help mitigate the damage. Since no further Dementors have been reported in over a week, I suspect we got them all. As such, this event cannot be repeated."

He was met with disbelieving looks. One man actually snorted. "Convenient. Not only is there a single point of blame for all our troubles, we are also to accept that you, personally, are the hero who saved the entire world?"

"Well, sir," Harry politely pointed out, "there is a reason my people chose an eleven-year-old to represent them."

"I think he's telling the truth, Clyde," a woman spoke up. "I thought I recognized him, earlier. He was in the videos, one of those children with the silvery light. And so was she." The woman pointed at Hermione.

"That's not the only thing we have on video," the man bounced back. "What about all the murders by wizards in those hours?"

"Those people we could not save from the Dementors might have been in unspeakable agony," Harry reminded him. "So a number of volunteers have quietly put them to rest. They intended it as a mercy." He ignored Dumbledore's quick mental warning not to say more; he wasn't planning to mention his own opinion on the point, not unless they asked. It would be good to discuss this with medical professionals, but saying that his people may have been responsible for tens of thousands of unnecessary murders due to ignorance, presumption and a misguided hope to be able to save some secrecy was probably not the best thing to bring up early in the negotiations.

"I'm not talking about that! What about the attacks on London Bridge or the Birmingham Underground? There was nothing wrong with the people there!"

"Oh, those attacks. Sorry. Yes, you're right. Almost all the Dementors in the UK and Ireland were in a single place, which Hermione Granger handled very early on." No need to mention quite how early on. "As such, given the crisis all over the world, pretty much anyone who could make themselves useful was engaged helping out abroad. No one at the right positions realized what was happening here until it was too late. This was again... Quirrell, the single dark wizard intend on sowing chaos."

"There were different people in different places," the man objected. "And women as well as men."

"There is a potion, Polyjuice Potion, which allows the drinker to take on someone else's appearance. I suspect he used it multiple times."

He could see the disbelief in their eyes. In fact, he had to admit that it seemed like a bit of a stretch.

"To what purpose?" A different man asked. "Why would he do all that? Is he insane?"

"Oh, not all," Harry breathed. "He is extremely sane."

He fixed the speaker with his eyes. "All the clues point in the same direction: he intended to start a war. It is not so strange, when you think about it. With a united magical front, we can easily win; with the cooperation of foreign magical governments, I daresay wizards could conquer the entire world. We end up with a peaceful magical utopia ruled by wizards, where Muggles take a subservient place, as many of our kind believe to be the natural order."

There was a brief silence, broken by the Queen's polite cough. "And is that your purpose too, Lord Potter?"

"Oh, no." Harry stood up for full effect, which was only slightly ruined by the fact that he was still shorter than most of the sitting people. "Not at all."

"You see," he spoke carefully (he had practiced this in his mind over and over). "The Ministry of Magical Britain have placed themselves fully behind me. The Wizengamot – our ruling body – have agreed to approve any treaty we create in these negotiations." He lifted the staff, ignoring the flinches in his audience, and took it in both hands. "We can reasonably say that I speak for all magic users in this country."

"From that position –" he threw the staff forwards, where it fell in front of the Queen's feet with a clatter, "I surrender."